<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customize small language models on AWS with automotive terminology</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through the phases of customizing SLMs on AWS, with a specific focus on automotive terminology for diagnostics as a Q&amp;amp;A task. We begin with the data analysis phase and progress through the end-to-end process, covering fine-tuning, deployment, and evaluation. We compare a customized SLM with a general purpose LLM, using various metrics to assess vocabulary richness and overall accuracy.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-small-language-models-on-aws-with-automotive-terminology/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate emails for task management using Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to create an automated email response solution using Amazon Bedrock and its features, including Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-emails-for-task-management-using-amazon-bedrock-agents-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-and-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate analysis and discovery of cancer biomarkers with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 18:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Bedrock agents can streamline workflows and provide AI automation to boost productivity. In this post, we show you how agentic workflows with Amazon Bedrock Agents can help accelerate this journey for research scientists with a natural language interface. We define an example analysis pipeline, specifically for lung cancer survival with clinical, genomics, and imaging modalities of biomarkers. We showcase a variety of tools including database retrieval with Text2SQL, statistical models and visual charts with scientific libraries, biomedical literature search with public APIs and internal evidence, and medical image processing with Amazon SageMaker jobs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate building guardrails for Amazon Bedrock using test-driven development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Guardrails helps implement safeguards for generative AI applications based on specific use cases and responsible AI policies. Amazon Bedrock Guardrails assists in controlling the interaction between users and foundation models (FMs) by detecting and filtering out undesirable and potentially harmful content, while maintaining safety and privacy. In this post, we explore a solution that automates building guardrails using a test-driven development approach.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-building-guardrails-for-amazon-bedrock-using-test-driven-development/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build cost-effective RAG applications with Binary Embeddings in Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2, Amazon OpenSearch Serverless, and Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are happy to announce the availability of Binary Embeddings for Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2 in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and Amazon OpenSearch Serverless. This post summarizes the benefits of this new binary vector support and gives you information on how you can get started.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-cost-effective-rag-applications-with-binary-embeddings-in-amazon-titan-text-embeddings-v2-amazon-opensearch-serverless-and-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate cloud security vulnerability assessment and alerting using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates a proactive approach for security vulnerability assessment of your accounts and workloads, using Amazon GuardDuty, Amazon Bedrock, and other AWS serverless technologies. This approach aims to identify potential vulnerabilities proactively and provide your users with timely alerts and recommendations, avoiding reactive escalations and other damages.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-cloud-security-vulnerability-assessment-and-alerting-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DXC transforms data exploration for their oil and gas customers with LLM-powered tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how DXC and AWS collaborated to build an AI assistant using large language models (LLMs), enabling users to access and analyze different data types from a variety of data sources. The AI assistant is powered by an intelligent agent that routes user questions to specialized tools that are optimized for different data types such as text, tables, and domain-specific formats. It uses the LLM’s ability to understand natural language, write code, and reason about conversational context.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How MSD uses Amazon Bedrock to translate natural language into SQL for complex healthcare databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSD, a leading pharmaceutical company, collaborates with AWS to implement a powerful text-to-SQL generative AI solution using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic&#39;s Claude 3.5 Sonnet model. This approach streamlines data extraction from complex healthcare databases like DE-SynPUF, enabling analysts to generate SQL queries from natural language questions. The solution addresses challenges such as coded columns, non-intuitive names, and ambiguous queries, significantly reducing query time and democratizing data access.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate AWS Resilience Hub findings in natural language using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post discusses a solution that combines AWS Resilience Hub and Amazon Bedrock to generate architectural findings in natural language. By using the capabilities of Resilience Hub and Amazon Bedrock, you can share findings with C-suite executives, engineers, managers, and other personas within your corporation to provide better visibility over maintaining a resilient architecture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-aws-resilience-hub-findings-in-natural-language-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate and evaluate images in Amazon Bedrock with Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 v2 and Anthropic Claude 3.5 Sonnet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to interact with the Amazon Titan Image Generator G1 v2 model on Amazon Bedrock to generate an image. Then, we show you how to use Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to describe it, evaluate it with a score from 1–10, explain the reason behind the given score, and suggest improvements to the image.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-and-evaluate-images-in-amazon-bedrock-with-amazon-titan-image-generator-g1-v2-and-anthropic-claude-3-5-sonnet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How InsuranceDekho transformed insurance agent interactions using Amazon Bedrock and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how InsuranceDekho harnessed the power of generative AI using Amazon Bedrock and Anthropic’s Claude to provide responses to customer queries on policy coverages, exclusions, and more. This let our customer care agents and POSPs confidently help our customers understand the policies without reaching out to insurance subject matter experts (SMEs) or memorizing complex plans while providing sales and after-sales services. The use of this solution has improved sales, cross-selling, and overall customer service experience.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for addressing the core dimensions of responsible AI for Amazon Bedrock applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the core dimensions of responsible AI and explore considerations and strategies on how to address these dimensions for Amazon Bedrock applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/considerations-for-addressing-the-core-dimensions-of-responsible-ai-for-amazon-bedrock-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From RAG to fabric: Lessons learned from building real-world RAGs at GenAIIC – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post focuses on doing RAG on heterogeneous data formats. We first introduce routers, and how they can help managing diverse data sources. We then give tips on how to handle tabular data and will conclude with multimodal RAG, focusing specifically on solutions that handle both text and image data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/from-rag-to-fabric-lessons-learned-from-building-real-world-rags-at-genaiic-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohere Embed multimodal embeddings model is now available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Cohere Embed multimodal embeddings model is now generally available on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. This model is the newest Cohere Embed 3 model, which is now multimodal and capable of generating embeddings from both text and images, enabling enterprises to unlock real value from their vast amounts of data that exist in image form. In this post, we discuss the benefits and capabilities of this new model with some examples.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GoDaddy built Lighthouse, an interaction analytics solution to generate insights on support interactions using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how GoDaddy’s Care &amp;amp; Services team, in close collaboration with the AWS GenAI Labs team, built Lighthouse—a generative AI solution powered by Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that makes foundation models (FMs) from leading AI startups and Amazon available through an API, so you can choose from a wide range of FMs to find the model that is best suited for your use case.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune multimodal models for vision and text use cases on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showcase how to fine-tune a text and vision model, such as Meta Llama 3.2, to better perform at visual question answering tasks. The Meta Llama 3.2 Vision Instruct models demonstrated impressive performance on the challenging DocVQA benchmark for visual question answering. By using the power of Amazon SageMaker JumpStart, we demonstrate the process of adapting these generative AI models to excel at understanding and responding to natural language questions about images.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Financial Group uses QnABot on AWS and Amazon Q Business to enhance workforce productivity with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_11_2024/15_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Principal used QnABot paired with Amazon Q Business and Amazon Bedrock to create Principal AI Generative Experience: a user-friendly, secure internal chatbot for faster access to information. Using generative AI, Principal’s employees can now focus on deeper human judgment based decisioning, instead of spending time scouring for answers from data sources manually.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/principal-financial-group-uses-qnabot-on-aws-and-amazon-q-business-to-enhance-workforce-productivity-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governing ML lifecycle at scale: Best practices to set up cost and usage visibility of ML workloads in multi-account environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cloud costs can significantly impact your business operations. Gaining real-time visibility into infrastructure expenses, usage patterns, and cost drivers is essential. To allocate costs to cloud resources, a tagging strategy is essential. This post outlines steps you can take to implement a comprehensive tagging governance strategy across accounts, using AWS tools and services that provide visibility and control. By setting up automated policy enforcement and checks, you can achieve cost optimization across your machine learning (ML) environment.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate invoice processing with Streamlit and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through a step-by-step guide to automating invoice processing using Streamlit and Amazon Bedrock, addressing the challenge of handling invoices from multiple vendors with different formats. We show how to set up the environment, process invoices stored in Amazon S3, and deploy a user-friendly Streamlit application to review and interact with the processed data.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-invoice-processing-with-streamlit-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralize model governance with SageMaker Model Registry Resource Access Manager sharing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently announced the general availability of cross-account sharing of Amazon SageMaker Model Registry using AWS Resource Access Manager (AWS RAM), making it easier to securely share and discover machine learning (ML) models across your AWS accounts. In this post, we will show you how to use this new cross-account model sharing feature to build your own centralized model governance capability, which is often needed for centralized model approval, deployment, auditing, and monitoring workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize trip planning with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Location Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to build a generative AI-powered trip-planning service that revolutionizes the way travelers discover and explore destinations. By using advanced AI technology and Amazon Location Service, the trip planner lets users translate inspiration into personalized travel itineraries. This innovative service goes beyond traditional trip planning methods, offering real-time interaction through a chat-based interface and maintaining scalability, reliability, and data security through AWS native services.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify automotive damage processing with Amazon Bedrock and vector databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores a solution that uses the power of AWS generative AI capabilities like Amazon Bedrock and OpenSearch vector search to perform damage appraisals for insurers, repair shops, and fleet managers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-automotive-damage-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-and-vector-databases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding prompt engineering: Unlock the creative potential of Stability AI models on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Stability AI’s newest launch of Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5L) on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart enhances image generation, human anatomy rendering, and typography by producing more diverse outputs and adhering closely to user prompts, making it a significant upgrade over its predecessor. In this post, we explore advanced prompt engineering techniques that can enhance the performance of these models and facilitate the creation of compelling imagery through text-to-image transformations.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2024/14_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the availability of Stability AI’s latest and most advanced text-to-image model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large, in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart. In this post, we provide an implementation guide for subscribing to Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large in SageMaker JumpStart, deploying the model in Amazon SageMaker Studio, and generating images using text-to-image prompts.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-stable-diffusion-3-5-large-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve governance of models with Amazon SageMaker unified Model Cards and Model Registry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can now register machine learning (ML) models in Amazon SageMaker Model Registry with Amazon SageMaker Model Cards, making it straightforward to manage governance information for specific model versions directly in SageMaker Model Registry in just a few clicks. In this post, we discuss a new feature that supports the integration of model cards with the model registry. We discuss the solution architecture and best practices for managing model cards with a registered model version, and walk through how to set up, operationalize, and govern your models using the integration in the model registry.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcribe, translate, and summarize live streams in your browser with AWS AI and generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the approach behind building an AWS AI-powered Chrome extension that aims to revolutionize the live streaming experience by providing real-time transcription, translation, and summarization capabilities directly within your browser.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transcribe-translate-and-summarize-live-streams-in-your-browser-with-aws-ai-and-generative-ai-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate your financial statement analysis with Amazon Bedrock and generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to deploy a generative AI application that can accelerate your financial statement analysis on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-your-financial-statement-analysis-with-amazon-bedrock-and-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual content processing using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post outlines a custom multilingual document extraction and content assessment framework using a combination of Anthropic’s Claude 3 on Amazon Bedrock and Amazon A2I to incorporate human-in-the-loop capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/multilingual-content-processing-using-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-a2i/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a reverse image search engine with Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings in Amazon Bedrock and AWS managed services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2024/13_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you will learn how to extract key objects from image queries using Amazon Rekognition and build a reverse image search engine using Amazon Titan Multimodal Embeddings from Amazon Bedrock in combination with Amazon OpenSearch Serverless Service.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-reverse-image-search-engine-with-amazon-titan-multimodal-embeddings-in-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-managed-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI for agriculture: How Agmatix is improving agriculture with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes how Agmatix, a pioneering Agtech company powering R&amp;amp;D for input companies and digital agronomic solutions, uses Amazon Bedrock and AWS fully featured services to enhance the research process and development of higher-yielding seeds and sustainable molecules for global agriculture.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-for-agriculture-how-agmatix-is-improving-agriculture-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate financial industry-specific insights using generative AI and in-context fine-tuning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we demonstrate prompt engineering techniques to generate accurate and relevant analysis of tabular data using industry-specific language. This is done by providing large language models (LLMs) in-context sample data with features and labels in the prompt. The results are similar to fine-tuning LLMs without the complexities of fine-tuning models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-financial-industry-specific-insights-using-generative-ai-and-in-context-fine-tuning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliver personalized marketing with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2024/12_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Bedrock Developer Experience, and Amazon Personalize that allow marketers to save time and deliver efficient personalized advertising using a generative AI enhanced solution. Our solution is a marketing agent that shows how Amazon Personalize can effectively segment target customers based on relevant characteristics and behaviors. Additionally, by using Amazon Bedrock Agents and foundation models (FMs), our tool generates personalized creative content specifically tailored to each purpose.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
