<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 19:18:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ray jobs on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod: scalable and resilient distributed AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 19:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ray is an open source framework that makes it straightforward to create, deploy, and optimize distributed Python jobs. In this post, we demonstrate the steps involved in running Ray jobs on SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ray-jobs-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-scalable-and-resilient-distributed-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Large Language Models on Amazon Bedrock for multi-step task execution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 19:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_04_2025/02_04_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the application of LLMs in executing complex analytical queries through an API, with specific focus on Amazon Bedrock. To demonstrate this process, we present a use case where the system identifies the patient with the least number of vaccines by retrieving, grouping, and sorting data, and ultimately presenting the final result.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-large-language-models-on-amazon-bedrock-for-multi-step-task-execution/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AWS MCP Servers for code assistants (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 20:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the open source release of AWS MCP Servers for code assistants — a suite of specialized Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers that bring Amazon Web Services (AWS) best practices directly to your development workflow. This post is the first in a series covering AWS MCP Servers. In this post, we walk through how these specialized MCP servers can dramatically reduce your development time while incorporating security controls, cost optimizations, and AWS Well-Architected best practices into your code.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harness the power of MCP servers with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 19:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, MCP is providing agents standard access to an expanding list of accessible tools that you can use to accomplish a variety of tasks. In this post, we show you how to build an Amazon Bedrock agent that uses MCP to access data sources to quickly build generative AI applications.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harness-the-power-of-mcp-servers-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate compliant content with Amazon Bedrock and ConstitutionalChain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 16:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore practical strategies for using Constitutional AI to produce compliant content efficiently and effectively using Amazon Bedrock and LangGraph to build ConstitutionalChain for rapid content creation in highly regulated industries like finance and healthcare
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generate-compliant-content-with-amazon-bedrock-and-constitutionalchain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimize generative AI hallucinations with Amazon Bedrock Automated Reasoning checks</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 15:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To improve factual accuracy of large language model (LLM) responses, AWS announced Amazon Bedrock Automated Reasoning checks (in gated preview) at AWS re:Invent 2024. In this post, we discuss how to help prevent generative AI hallucinations using Amazon Bedrock Automated Reasoning checks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/minimize-generative-ai-hallucinations-with-amazon-bedrock-automated-reasoning-checks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS App Studio introduces a prebuilt solutions catalog and cross-instance Import and Export</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 14:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_04_2025/01_04_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a recent AWS What’s New Post, App Studio announced two new features to accelerate application building: Prebuilt solutions catalog and cross-instance Import and Export. In this post, we walk through how to use the prebuilt solutions catalog to get started quickly and use the Import and Export feature
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-app-studio-introduces-a-prebuilt-solutions-catalog-and-cross-instance-import-and-export/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build agentic systems with CrewAI and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 15:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_03_2025/31_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how CrewAI’s open source agentic framework, combined with Amazon Bedrock, enables the creation of sophisticated multi-agent systems that can transform how businesses operate. Through practical examples and implementation details, we demonstrate how to build, deploy, and orchestrate AI agents that can tackle complex tasks with minimal human oversight.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-agentic-systems-with-crewai-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock Guardrails image content filters provide industry-leading safeguards, helping customer block up to 88% of harmful multimodal content: Generally available today</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 20:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_03_2025/28_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock Guardrails announces the general availability of image content filters, enabling you to moderate both image and text content in your generative AI applications. In this post, we discuss how to get started with image content filters in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-bedrock-guardrails-image-content-filters-provide-industry-leading-safeguards-helping-customer-block-up-to-88-of-harmful-multimodal-content-generally-available-today/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating custom dependencies in Amazon SageMaker Canvas workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 19:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When implementing machine learning workflows in Amazon SageMaker Canvas, organizations might need to consider external dependencies required for their specific use cases. Although SageMaker Canvas provides powerful no-code and low-code capabilities for rapid experimentation, some projects might require specialized dependencies and libraries that aren’t included by default in SageMaker Canvas. This post provides an example of how to incorporate code that relies on external dependencies into your SageMaker Canvas workflows.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate training data and cost-effectively train categorical models with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 18:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how you can use Amazon Bedrock to generate high-quality categorical ground truth data, which is crucial for training machine learning (ML) models in a cost-sensitive environment. Generative AI solutions can play an invaluable role during the model development phase by simplifying training and test data creation for multiclass classification supervised learning use cases. We dive deep into this process on how to use XML tags to structure the prompt and guide Amazon Bedrock in generating a balanced label dataset with high accuracy.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference in multi-account environments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 15:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_03_2025/27_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to modify your Regional access controls to specifically allow Amazon Bedrock cross-Region inference while maintaining broader Regional restrictions for other AWS services. We provide practical examples for both SCP modifications and AWS Control Tower implementations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-amazon-bedrock-cross-region-inference-in-multi-account-environments/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker JumpStart adds fine-tuning support for models in a private model hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are announcing an enhanced private hub feature with several new capabilities that give organizations greater control over their ML assets. These enhancements include the ability to fine-tune SageMaker JumpStart models directly within the private hub, support for adding and managing custom-trained models, deep linking capabilities for associated notebooks, and improved model version management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-adds-fine-tuning-support-for-models-in-a-private-model-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered game design: Accelerating early development with Stability AI models on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 14:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_03_2025/26_03_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI has emerged as a game changer, offering unprecedented opportunities for game designers to push boundaries and create immersive virtual worlds. At the forefront of this revolution is Stability AI’s cutting-edge text-to-image AI model, Stable Diffusion 3.5 Large (SD3.5 Large), which is transforming the way we approach game environment creation. In this post, we explore how you can use SD3.5 Large to address practical gaming needs such as early concept art and character design.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
