<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Imperva optimizes SQL generation from natural language using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Ori Nakar from Imperva. Imperva Cloud WAF protects hundreds of thousands of websites against cyber threats and blocks billions of security events every day. Counters and insights based on security events are calculated daily and used by users from multiple departments. Millions of counters are added daily, together […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/imperva-optimizes-sql-generation-from-natural-language-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create natural conversations with Amazon Lex QnAIntent and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer service organizations today face an immense opportunity. As customer expectations grow, brands have a chance to creatively apply new innovations to transform the customer experience. Although meeting rising customer demands poses challenges, the latest breakthroughs in conversational artificial intelligence (AI) empowers companies to meet these expectations. Customers today expect timely responses to their questions […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-natural-conversations-with-amazon-lex-qnaintent-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate the reliability of Retrieval Augmented Generation applications using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to evaluate the performance, trustworthiness, and potential biases of your RAG pipelines and applications on Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Mistral AI, Stability AI, and Amazon through a single API, along with a broad set of capabilities to build generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Amazon services using AWS PrivateLink in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 16:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2024/20_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a solution for configuring SageMaker notebook instances to connect to Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services with the use of AWS PrivateLink and Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) security groups.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/connect-to-amazon-services-using-aws-privatelink-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize your Amazon Translate architecture using strategic caching layers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explain how setting up a cache for frequently accessed translations can benefit organizations that need scalable, multi-language translation across large volumes of content. You’ll learn how to build a simple caching mechanism for Amazon Translate to accelerate turnaround times.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-your-amazon-translate-architecture-using-strategic-caching-layers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Slack gateway for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2024/19_06_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced digital world, streamlining workflows and boosting productivity are paramount. That’s why we’re thrilled to share an exciting integration that will take your team’s collaboration to new heights. Get ready to unlock the power of generative artificial intelligence (AI) and bring it directly into your Slack workspace. Imagine the possibilities: Quick and efficient […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-a-slack-gateway-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving air quality with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution that uses a generative artificial intelligence (AI) to standardize air quality data from low-cost sensors in Africa, specifically addressing the air quality data integration problem of low-cost sensors. The solution harnesses the capabilities of generative AI, specifically Large Language Models (LLMs), to address the challenges posed by diverse sensor data and automatically generate Python functions based on various data formats. The fundamental objective is to build a manufacturer-agnostic database, leveraging generative AI’s ability to standardize sensor outputs, synchronize data, and facilitate precise corrections.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use zero-shot large language models on Amazon Bedrock for custom named entity recognition</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Name entity recognition (NER) is the process of extracting information of interest, called entities, from structured or unstructured text. Manually identifying all mentions of specific types of information in documents is extremely time-consuming and labor-intensive. Some examples include extracting players and positions in an NFL game summary, products mentioned in an AWS keynote transcript, or […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-zero-shot-large-language-models-on-amazon-bedrock-for-custom-named-entity-recognition/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguard a generative AI travel agent with prompt engineering and Guardrails for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a comprehensive solution for addressing the challenges of securing a virtual travel agent powered by generative AI. We provide an end-to-end example and its accompanying code to demonstrate how to implement prompt engineering techniques, content moderation, and various guardrails to make sure the assistant operates within predefined boundaries by relying on Guardrails for Amazon Bedrock. Additionally, we delve into monitoring strategies to track the activation of these safeguards, enabling proactive identification and mitigation of potential issues.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline financial workflows with generative AI for email automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 17:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2024/18_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explains a generative artificial intelligence (AI) technique to extract insights from business emails and attachments. It examines how AI can optimize financial workflow processes by automatically summarizing documents, extracting data, and categorizing information from email attachments. This enables companies to serve more clients, direct employees to higher-value tasks, speed up processes, lower expenses, enhance data accuracy, and increase efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-financial-workflows-with-generative-ai-for-email-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Twilio used Amazon SageMaker MLOps pipelines with PrestoDB to enable frequent model retraining and optimized batch transform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 17:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Shamik Ray, Srivyshnav K S, Jagmohan Dhiman and Soumya Kundu from Twilio. Today’s leading companies trust Twilio’s Customer Engagement Platform (CEP) to build direct, personalized relationships with their customers everywhere in the world. Twilio enables companies to use communications and data to add intelligence and security to every step of […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-twilio-used-amazon-sagemaker-mlops-pipelines-with-prestodb-to-enable-frequent-model-retraining-and-optimized-batch-transform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate deep learning training and simplify orchestration with AWS Trainium and AWS Batch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 16:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_06_2024/17_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In large language model (LLM) training, effective orchestration and compute resource management poses a significant challenge. Automation of resource provisioning, scaling, and workflow management is vital for optimizing resource usage and streamlining complex workflows, thereby achieving efficient deep learning training processes. Simplified orchestration enables researchers and practitioners to focus more on model experimentation, hyperparameter tuning, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-deep-learning-training-and-simplify-orchestration-with-aws-trainium-and-aws-batch/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
