<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:40:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a domain‐aware data preprocessing pipeline: A multi‐agent collaboration approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a multi-agent collaboration pipeline for processing unstructured insurance data using Amazon Bedrock, featuring specialized agents for classification, conversion, and metadata extraction. We demonstrate how this domain-aware approach transforms diverse data formats like claims documents, videos, and audio files into metadata-rich outputs that enable fraud detection, customer 360-degree views, and advanced analytics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-domain%E2%80%90aware-data-preprocessing-pipeline-a-multi%E2%80%90agent-collaboration-approach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating complex document processing: How Onity Group built an intelligent solution using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_05_2025/20_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Onity Group, a financial services company specializing in mortgage servicing and origination, transformed their document processing capabilities using Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services. The solution helped Onity achieve a 50% reduction in document extraction costs while improving overall accuracy by 20% compared to their previous OCR and AI/ML solution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automating-complex-document-processing-how-onity-group-built-an-intelligent-solution-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HERE Technologies boosts developer productivity with new generative AI-powered coding assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 17:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_05_2025/19_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            HERE collaborated with the GenAIIC. Our joint mission was to create an intelligent AI coding assistant that could provide explanations and executable code solutions in response to users’ natural language queries. The requirement was to build a scalable system that could translate natural language questions into HTML code with embedded JavaScript, ready for immediate rendering as an interactive map that users can see on screen.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/here-technologies-boosts-developer-productivity-with-new-generative-ai-powered-coding-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a custom plugin on Amazon Q Business and authenticate with Amazon Cognito to interact with backend systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a custom plugin with Amazon Q Business for backend integration. This plugin can integrate existing systems, including third-party systems, with little to no development in just weeks and automate critical workflows. Additionally, we show how to safeguard the solution using Amazon Cognito and AWS IAM Identity Center, maintaining the safety and integrity of sensitive data and workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/set-up-a-custom-plugin-on-amazon-q-business-and-authenticate-with-amazon-cognito-to-interact-with-backend-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect hallucinations for RAG-based systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks you through how to create a basic hallucination detection system for RAG-based applications. We also weigh the pros and cons of different methods in terms of accuracy, precision, recall, and cost.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/detect-hallucinations-for-rag-based-systems/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS machine learning supports Scuderia Ferrari HP pit stop analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pit crews are trained to operate at optimum efficiency, although measuring their performance has been challenging, until now. In this post, we share how Amazon Web Services (AWS) is helping Scuderia Ferrari HP develop more accurate pit stop analysis techniques using machine learning (ML).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-machine-learning-supports-scuderia-ferrari-hp-pit-stop-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate edge AI development with SiMa.ai Edgematic with a seamless AWS integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_05_2025/16_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to retrain and quantize a model using SageMaker AI and the SiMa.ai Palette software suite. The goal is to accurately detect individuals in environments where visibility and protective equipment detection are essential for compliance and safety.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-edge-ai-development-with-sima-ai-edgematic-with-a-seamless-aws-integration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apoidea Group enhances visual information extraction from banking documents with multimodal models using LLaMA-Factory on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building on this foundation of specialized information extraction solutions and using the capabilities of SageMaker HyperPod, we collaborate with APOIDEA Group to explore the use of large vision language models (LVLMs) to further improve table structure recognition performance on banking and financial documents. In this post, we present our work and step-by-step code on fine-tuning the Qwen2-VL-7B-Instruct model using LLaMA-Factory on SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-apoidea-group-enhances-visual-information-extraction-from-banking-documents-with-multimodal-models-using-llama-factory-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Qualtrics built Socrates: An AI platform powered by Amazon SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Qualtrics built an AI platform powered by Amazon SageMaker and Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-qualtrics-built-socrates-an-ai-platform-powered-by-amazon-sagemaker-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vxceed secures transport operations with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_05_2025/15_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS partnered with Vxceed to support their AI strategy, resulting in the development of LimoConnect Q, an innovative ground transportation management solution. Using AWS services including Amazon Bedrock and Lambda, Vxceed successfully built a secure, AI-powered solution that streamlines trip booking and document processing.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/vxceed-secures-transport-operations-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost-effective AI image generation with PixArt-Σ inference on AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is the first in a series where we will run multiple diffusion transformers on Trainium and Inferentia-powered instances. In this post, we show how you can deploy PixArt-Sigma to Trainium and Inferentia-powered instances.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cost-effective-ai-image-generation-with-pixart-%CF%83-inference-on-aws-trainium-and-aws-inferentia/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize DeepSeek-R1 671b model using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod recipes – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we use the recipes to fine-tune the original DeepSeek-R1 671b parameter model. We demonstrate this through the step-by-step implementation of these recipes using both SageMaker training jobs and SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/customize-deepseek-r1-671b-model-using-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-recipes-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a financial research assistant using Amazon Q Business and Amazon QuickSight for generative AI–powered insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 15:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2025/14_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Amazon Q Business can help augment your generative AI needs in all the abovementioned use cases and more by answering questions, providing summaries, generating content, and securely completing tasks based on data and information in your enterprise systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-financial-research-assistant-using-amazon-q-business-and-amazon-quicksight-for-generative-ai-powered-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Amazon Bedrock Agents: A guide to safeguarding against indirect prompt injections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI tools have transformed how we work, create, and process information. At Amazon Web Services (AWS), security is our top priority. Therefore, Amazon Bedrock provides comprehensive security controls and best practices to help protect your applications and data. In this post, we explore the security measures and practical strategies provided by Amazon Bedrock Agents to safeguard your AI interactions against indirect prompt injections, making sure that your applications remain both secure and reliable.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build scalable containerized RAG based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon EKS with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) with Amazon Bedrock to build scalable and containerized RAG solutions for your generative AI applications on AWS while bringing your unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-scalable-containerized-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-eks-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hexagon built an AI assistant using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recognizing the transformative benefits of generative AI for enterprises, we at Hexagon’s Asset Lifecycle Intelligence division sought to enhance how users interact with our Enterprise Asset Management (EAM) products. Understanding these advantages, we partnered with AWS to embark on a journey to develop HxGN Alix, an AI-powered digital worker using AWS generative AI services. This blog post explores the strategy, development, and implementation of HxGN Alix, demonstrating how a tailored AI solution can drive efficiency and enhance user satisfaction.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
