<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:29:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RAG architecture with Voyage AI embedding models on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Anthropic Claude 3 models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the state-of-the-art embedding models by Voyage AI and show a RAG implementation with Voyage AI’s text embedding model on Amazon SageMaker Jumpstart, Anthropic’s Claude 3 model on Amazon Bedrock, and Amazon OpenSearch Service. Voyage AI’s embedding models are the preferred embedding models for Anthropic. In addition to general-purpose embedding models, Voyage AI offers domain-specific embedding models that are tuned to a particular domain.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporate offline and online human – machine workflows into your generative AI applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recent advances in artificial intelligence have led to the emergence of generative AI that can produce human-like novel content such as images, text, and audio. These models are pre-trained on massive datasets and, to sometimes fine-tuned with smaller sets of more task specific data. An important aspect of developing effective generative AI application is Reinforcement […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/incorporate-offline-and-online-human-machine-workflows-into-your-generative-ai-applications-on-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build generative AI applications with Amazon Titan Text Premier, Amazon Bedrock, and AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 17:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_05_2024/14_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Titan Text Premier, the latest addition to the Amazon Titan family of large language models (LLMs), is now generally available in Amazon Bedrock. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading artificial intelligence (AI) companies like AI21 Labs, Anthropic, Cohere, Meta, Stability AI, and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-titan-text-premier-amazon-bedrock-and-aws-cdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of generative AI techniques for clinical report summarization</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2024/13_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a comparison of results obtained by two such techniques: zero-shot and few-shot prompting. We also explore the utility of the RAG prompt engineering technique as it applies to the task of summarization. Evaluating LLMs is an undervalued part of the machine learning (ML) pipeline.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/evaluation-of-generative-ai-techniques-for-clinical-report-summarization/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS DeepRacer enables builders of all skill levels to upskill and get started with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 18:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s technological landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) are becoming increasingly accessible, enabling builders of all skill levels to harness their power. As more companies adopt AI solutions, there’s a growing need to upskill both technical and non-technical teams in responsibly expanding AI usage. Getting hands-on experience is crucial for understanding and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-deepracer-enables-builders-of-all-skill-levels-to-upskill-and-get-started-with-machine-learning/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform customer engagement with no-code LLM fine-tuning using Amazon SageMaker Canvas and SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 16:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_05_2024/10_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) creates tailored customer experiences that align with a brand’s unique voice. Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon SageMaker JumpStart democratize this process, offering no-code solutions and pre-trained models that enable businesses to fine-tune LLMs without deep technical expertise, helping organizations move faster with fewer technical resources. SageMaker Canvas provides an intuitive […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transform-customer-engagement-with-no-code-llm-fine-tuning-using-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How LotteON built dynamic A/B testing for their personalized recommendation system</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with HyeKyung Yang, Jieun Lim, and SeungBum Shim from LotteON. LotteON is transforming itself into an online shopping platform that provides customers with an unprecedented shopping experience based on its in-store and online shopping expertise. Rather than simply selling the product, they create and let customers experience the product through their […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-lotteon-built-dynamic-a-b-testing-for-their-personalized-recommendation-system/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing the power of generative AI: Verisk’s journey to an Instant Insight Engine for enhanced customer support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Tom Famularo, Abhay Shah and Nicolette Kontor from Verisk. Verisk (Nasdaq: VRSK) is a leading data analytics and technology partner for the global insurance industry. Through advanced analytics, software, research, and industry expertise across over 20 countries, Verisk helps build resilience for individuals, communities, and businesses. The company is committed […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unleashing-the-power-of-generative-ai-verisks-journey-to-an-instant-insight-engine-for-enhanced-customer-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing an AI/ML center of excellence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 15:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2024/09_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The rapid advancements in artificial intelligence and machine learning (AI/ML) have made these technologies a transformative force across industries. According to a McKinsey study, across the financial services industry (FSI), generative AI is projected to deliver over $400 billion (5%) of industry revenue in productivity benefits. As maintained by Gartner, more than 80% of enterprises […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/establishing-an-ai-ml-center-of-excellence/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Hugging Face text classification model in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 20:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker JumpStart provides a suite of built-in algorithms, pre-trained models, and pre-built solution templates to help data scientists and machine learning (ML) practitioners get started on training and deploying ML models quickly. You can use these algorithms and models for both supervised and unsupervised learning. They can process various types of input data, including […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-hugging-face-text-classification-model-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dialog Axiata used Amazon SageMaker to scale ML models in production with AI Factory and reduced customer churn within 3 months</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The telecommunications industry is more competitive than ever before. With customers able to easily switch between providers, reducing customer churn is a crucial priority for telecom companies who want to stay ahead. To address this challenge, Dialog Axiata has pioneered a cutting-edge solution called the Home Broadband (HBB) Churn Prediction Model. This post explores the […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-dialog-axiata-used-amazon-sagemaker-to-scale-ml-models-in-production-with-ai-factory-and-reduced-customer-churn-within-3-months/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon SageMaker now integrates with Amazon DataZone to streamline machine learning governance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 17:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_05_2024/08_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker is a fully managed machine learning (ML) service that provides a range of tools and features for building, training, and deploying ML models. Amazon DataZone is a data management service that makes it faster and easier for customers to catalog, discover, share, and govern data stored across AWS, on-premises, and third-party sources. Today, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-sagemaker-now-integrates-with-amazon-datazone-to-streamline-machine-learning-governance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost employee productivity with automated meeting summaries using Amazon Transcribe, Amazon SageMaker, and LLMs from Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution to automatically generate a meeting summary from a recorded virtual meeting (for example, using Amazon Chime) with several participants. The recording is transcribed to text using Amazon Transcribe and then processed using Amazon SageMaker Hugging Face containers to generate the meeting summary. The Hugging Face containers host a large language model (LLM) from the Hugging Face Hub.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-employee-productivity-with-automated-meeting-summaries-using-amazon-transcribe-amazon-sagemaker-and-llms-from-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Veritone uses Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Rekognition, Amazon Transcribe, and information retrieval to update their video search pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Tim Camara, Senior Product Manager at Veritone. Veritone is an artificial intelligence (AI) company based in Irvine, California. Founded in 2014, Veritone empowers people with AI-powered software and solutions for various applications, including media processing, analytics, advertising, and more. It offers solutions for media transcription, facial recognition, content summarization, object […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-veritone-uses-amazon-bedrock-amazon-rekognition-amazon-transcribe-and-information-retrieval-to-update-their-video-search-pipeline/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information extraction with LLMs using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) have unlocked new possibilities for extracting information from unstructured text data. Although much of the current excitement is around LLMs for generative AI tasks, many of the key use cases that you might want to solve have not fundamentally changed. Tasks such as routing support tickets, recognizing customers intents from a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/information-extraction-with-llms-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
