<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:07:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transforming network operations with AI: How Swisscom built a network assistant using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Swisscom developed their Network Assistant. We discuss the initial challenges and how they implemented a solution that delivers measurable benefits. We examine the technical architecture, discuss key learnings, and look at future enhancements that can further transform network operations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/transforming-network-operations-with-ai-how-swisscom-built-a-network-assistant-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End model training and deployment with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we guide you through the stages of customizing large language models (LLMs) with SageMaker Unified Studio and SageMaker AI, covering the end-to-end process starting from data discovery to fine-tuning FMs with SageMaker AI distributed training, tracking metrics using MLflow, and then deploying models using SageMaker AI inference for real-time inference. We also discuss best practices to choose the right instance size and share some debugging best practices while working with JupyterLab notebooks in SageMaker Unified Studio.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize RAG in production environments using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to use Amazon OpenSearch Service as a vector store to build an efficient RAG application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimize-rag-in-production-environments-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart-and-amazon-opensearch-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing AI agent governance with Boomi and AWS: A unified approach to observability and compliance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Boomi partnered with AWS to help enterprises accelerate and scale AI adoption with confidence using Agent Control Tower.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/advancing-ai-agent-governance-with-boomi-and-aws-a-unified-approach-to-observability-and-compliance/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio to build complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how you can use SageMaker Unified Studio to create complex AI workflows using Amazon Bedrock Flows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-to-build-complex-ai-workflows-using-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating AI innovation: Scale MCP servers for enterprise workloads with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present a centralized Model Context Protocol (MCP) server implementation using Amazon Bedrock that provides shared access to tools and resources for enterprise AI workloads. The solution enables organizations to accelerate AI innovation by standardizing access to resources and tools through MCP, while maintaining security and governance through a centralized approach.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-ai-innovation-scale-mcp-servers-for-enterprise-workloads-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the right approach for generative AI-powered structured data retrieval</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore five different patterns for implementing LLM-powered structured data query capabilities in AWS, including direct conversational interfaces, BI tool enhancements, and custom text-to-SQL solutions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/choosing-the-right-approach-for-generative-ai-powered-structured-data-retrieval/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing drug data analysis using Amazon Bedrock multimodal RAG capabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock&#39;s multimodal RAG capabilities revolutionize drug data analysis by efficiently processing complex medical documentation containing text, images, graphs, and tables.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionizing-drug-data-analysis-using-amazon-bedrock-multimodal-rag-capabilities/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and deploy AI inference workflows with new enhancements to the Amazon SageMaker Python SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 21:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide an overview of the user experience, detailing how to set up and deploy these workflows with multiple models using the SageMaker Python SDK. We walk through examples of building complex inference workflows, deploying them to SageMaker endpoints, and invoking them for real-time inference.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-deploy-ai-inference-workflows-with-new-enhancements-to-the-amazon-sagemaker-python-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context extraction from image files in Amazon Q Business using LLMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we look at a step-by-step implementation for using the custom document enrichment (CDE) feature within an Amazon Q Business application to process standalone image files. We walk you through an AWS Lambda function configured within CDE to process various image file types, and showcase an example scenario of how this integration enhances Amazon Q Business&#39;s ability to provide comprehensive insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/context-extraction-from-image-files-in-amazon-q-business-using-llms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AWS architecture diagrams using Amazon Q CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q Developer CLI with the AWS Diagram MCP and the AWS Documentation MCP servers to create sophisticated architecture diagrams that follow AWS best practices. We discuss techniques for basic diagrams and real-world diagrams, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-aws-architecture-diagrams-using-amazon-q-cli-and-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS costs estimation using Amazon Q CLI and AWS Cost Analysis MCP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how to use Amazon Q CLI with the AWS Cost Analysis MCP server to perform sophisticated cost analysis that follows AWS best practices. We discuss basic setup and advanced techniques, with detailed examples and step-by-step instructions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/aws-costs-estimation-using-amazon-q-cli-and-aws-cost-analysis-mcp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
