<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:25:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Amazon Q Business with AWS HealthScribe to gain insights from patient consultations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how you can use AWS HealthScribe with Amazon Q Business to create a chatbot to quickly gain insights into patient clinician conversations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-amazon-q-business-with-aws-healthscribe-to-gain-insights-from-patient-consultations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Amazon SageMaker Studio with a custom file system in Amazon EFS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore three scenarios demonstrating the versatility of integrating Amazon EFS with SageMaker Studio. These scenarios highlight how Amazon EFS can provide a scalable, secure, and collaborative data storage solution for data science teams.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-amazon-sagemaker-studio-with-a-custom-file-system-in-amazon-efs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summarize call transcriptions securely with Amazon Transcribe and Amazon Bedrock Guardrails</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2024/17_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Amazon Transcribe to get near real-time transcriptions of calls sent to Amazon Bedrock for summarization and sensitive data redaction. We’ll walk through an architecture that uses AWS Step Functions to orchestrate the process, providing seamless integration and efficient processing
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/summarize-call-transcriptions-securely-with-amazon-transcribe-and-amazon-bedrock-guardrails/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How DPG Media uses Amazon Bedrock and Amazon Transcribe to enhance video metadata with AI-powered pipelines</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how DPG Media is introducing AI-powered processes using Amazon Bedrock into its video publication pipelines. This solution is helping accelerate audio metadata extraction, create a more engaging user experience, and save time.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-dpg-media-uses-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-transcribe-to-enhance-video-metadata-with-ai-powered-pipelines/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SailPoint uses Anthropic’s Claude on Amazon Bedrock to automatically generate TypeScript code for SaaS connectors</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we highlight how the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center collaborated with SailPoint Technologies to build a generative AI-based coding assistant that uses Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet on Amazon Bedrock to help accelerate the development of software as a service (SaaS) connectors.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-sailpoint-uses-anthropics-claude-on-amazon-bedrock-to-automatically-generate-typescript-code-for-saas-connectors/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map Earth’s vegetation in under 20 minutes with Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate the power of SageMaker geospatial capabilities by mapping the world’s vegetation in under 20 minutes. This example not only highlights the efficiency of SageMaker, but also its impact how geospatial ML can be used to monitor the environment for sustainability and conservation purposes.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/map-earths-vegetation-in-under-20-minutes-with-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking insights and enhancing customer service: Intact’s transformative AI journey with AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2024/16_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Intact&#39;s Call Quality solution used Amazon Transcribe and other AWS services to improve critical KPIs with AI-powered contact center call auditing and analytics.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-insights-and-enhancing-customer-service-intacts-transformative-ai-journey-with-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate migration portfolio assessment using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 22:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we will harness the power of generative AI and Amazon Bedrock to help organizations simplify, accelerate, and scale migration assessments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-migration-portfolio-assessment-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve public speaking skills using a generative AI-based virtual assistant with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present an Amazon Bedrock powered virtual assistant that can transcribe presentation audio and examine it for language use, grammatical errors, filler words, and repetition of words and sentences to provide recommendations as well as suggest a curated version of the speech to elevate the presentation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-public-speaking-skills-using-a-generative-ai-based-virtual-assistant-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bria 2.3, Bria 2.2 HD, and Bria 2.3 Fast are now available in Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 20:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss Bria’s family of models, explain the Amazon SageMaker platform, and walk through how to discover, deploy, and run inference on a Bria 2.3 model using SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/bria-2-3-bria-2-2-hd-and-bria-2-3-fast-are-now-available-in-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing SageMaker Core: A new object-oriented Python SDK for Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how the SageMaker Core SDK simplifies the developer experience while providing API for seamlessly executing various steps in a general ML lifecycle. We also discuss the main benefits of using this SDK along with sharing relevant resources to learn more about this SDK.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-sagemaker-core-a-new-object-oriented-python-sdk-for-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a data labeling project with Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth Plus</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 16:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2024/15_10_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon SageMaker Ground Truth is a powerful data labeling service offered by AWS that provides a comprehensive and scalable platform for labeling various types of data, including text, images, videos, and 3D point clouds, using a diverse workforce of human annotators. In addition to traditional custom-tailored deep learning models, SageMaker Ground Truth also supports generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-data-labeling-project-with-amazon-sagemaker-ground-truth-plus/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a multimodal chatbot tailored to your unique dataset with Amazon Bedrock FMs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to create a multimodal chat assistant on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using Amazon Bedrock models, where users can submit images and questions, and text responses will be sourced from a closed set of proprietary documents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/create-a-multimodal-chatbot-tailored-to-your-unique-dataset-with-amazon-bedrock-fms/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design secure generative AI application workflows with Amazon Verified Permissions and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2024/14_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to design fine-grained access controls using Verified Permissions for a generative AI application that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to answer questions about insurance claims that exist in a claims review system using textual prompts as inputs and outputs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/design-secure-generative-ai-application-workflows-with-amazon-verified-permissions-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity by using AI in cloud operational health management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to create an AI-powered, event-driven operations assistant that automatically responds to operational events. The assistant can filter out irrelevant events (based on your organization’s policies), recommend actions, create and manage issue tickets in integrated IT service management (ITSM) tools to track actions, and query knowledge bases for insights related to operational events.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-productivity-by-using-ai-in-cloud-operational-health-management/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Indeed builds and deploys fine-tuned LLMs on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we describe how using the capabilities of Amazon SageMaker has accelerated Indeed’s AI research, development velocity, flexibility, and overall value in our pursuit of using Indeed’s unique and vast data to leverage advanced LLMs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-indeed-builds-and-deploys-fine-tuned-llms-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve LLM application robustness with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Bedrock Guardrails can improve the robustness of the agent framework. We are able to stop our chatbot from responding to non-relevant queries and protect personal information from our customers, ultimately improving the robustness of our agentic implementation with Amazon Bedrock Agents.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-llm-application-robustness-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dive deep into vector data stores using Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 19:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive deep into the vector database options available as part of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases and the applicable use cases, and look at working code examples.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dive-deep-into-vector-data-stores-using-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable or disable ACL crawling safely in Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_10_2024/11_10_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business recently added support for administrators to modify the default access control list (ACL) crawling feature for data source connectors. Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, AI powered assistant with enterprise-grade security and privacy features. It includes over 40 data source connectors that crawl and index documents. By default, Amazon Q Business […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enable-or-disable-acl-crawling-safely-in-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
