<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 22:04:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrate dynamic web content in your generative AI application using a web search API and Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 22:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use Amazon Bedrock Agents with a web search API to integrate dynamic web content in your generative AI application.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-dynamic-web-content-in-your-generative-ai-application-using-a-web-search-api-and-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a generative AI assistant to enhance employee experience using Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we explore how you can use Amazon Q Business to build generative AI assistants that enhance employee experience and boost productivity. Amazon Q Business seamlessly integrates with internal data sources, knowledge bases, and productivity tools to equip your workforce with instant access to information, automated tasks, and personalized support.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-generative-ai-assistant-to-enhance-employee-experience-using-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing document-level sync reports: Enhanced data sync visibility in Amazon Kendra</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 19:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_09_2024/20_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how the new document-level report in Amazon Kendra provides enhanced visibility and observability into the document processing lifecycle during data source sync jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-document-level-sync-reports-enhanced-data-sync-visibility-in-amazon-kendra/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune Meta Llama 3.1 models using torchtune on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 22:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, AWS collaborates with Meta’s PyTorch team to showcase how you can use Meta’s torchtune library to fine-tune Meta Llama-like architectures while using a fully-managed environment provided by Amazon SageMaker Training.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-meta-llama-3-1-models-using-torchtune-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases with Microsoft SharePoint as a data source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 17:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2024/19_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to configure Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases with SharePoint Online as a data source. By connecting SharePoint Online as a data source, employees can interact with the organization’s knowledge and data stored in SharePoint using natural language, making it straightforward to find relevant information, extract key points, and derive valuable insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-with-microsoft-sharepoint-as-a-data-source/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize logo design creation with Amazon Bedrock: Embracing generative art, dynamic logos, and AI collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 19:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how AWS can help accelerate a brand’s creative efforts with access to a powerful image-to-image model from Stable Diffusion available on Amazon Bedrock to interactively create and edit art and logo images.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionize-logo-design-creation-with-amazon-bedrock-embracing-generative-art-dynamic-logos-and-ai-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvent personalization with generative AI on Amazon Bedrock using task decomposition for agentic workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present an automated solution to provide a consistent and responsible personalization experience for your customers by using smaller LLMs for website personalization tailored to businesses and industries. This decomposes the complex task into subtasks handled by task / domain adopted LLMs, adhering to company guidelines and human expertise.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/reinvent-personalization-with-generative-ai-on-amazon-bedrock-using-task-decomposition-for-agentic-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate pre-training of Mistral’s Mathstral model with highly resilient clusters on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present to you an in-depth guide to starting a continual pre-training job using PyTorch Fully Sharded Data Parallel (FSDP) for Mistral AI’s Mathstral model with SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-pre-training-of-mistrals-mathstral-model-with-highly-resilient-clusters-on-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an efficient MLOps platform with OSS tools on Amazon ECS with AWS Fargate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2024/18_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how Zeta Global, a data-driven marketing technology company, has built an efficient MLOps platform to streamline the end-to-end ML workflow, from data ingestion to model deployment, while optimizing resource utilization and cost efficiency.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-an-efficient-mlops-platform-with-oss-tools-on-amazon-ecs-with-aws-fargate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build RAG-based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 17:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP with Amazon Bedrock to provide a RAG experience for your generative AI applications on AWS by bringing company-specific, unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-fsx-for-netapp-ontap-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for AWS DeepComposer ending soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS DeepComposer was first introduced during AWS re:Invent 2019 as a fun way for developers to compose music by using generative AI. AWS DeepComposer was the world’s first machine learning (ML)-enabled keyboard for developers to get hands-on—literally—with a musical keyboard and the latest ML techniques to compose their own music. After careful consideration, we have […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/support-for-aws-deepcomposer-ending-soon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve access and explore alternatives for Amazon Lookout for Equipment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how you can maintain access to Lookout for Equipment after it is closed to new customers and some alternatives to Lookout for Equipment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/preserve-access-and-explore-alternatives-for-amazon-lookout-for-equipment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR-Cas9 guide RNA efficiency prediction with efficiently tuned models in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat (CRISPR) technology holds the promise to revolutionize gene editing technologies, which is transformative to the way we understand and treat diseases. This technique is based in a natural mechanism found in bacteria that allows a protein coupled to a single guide RNA (gRNA) strand to locate and make […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/crispr-cas9-guide-rna-efficiency-prediction-with-efficiently-tuned-models-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG performance using Cohere Rerank</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 19:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Cohere Rerank to improve search efficiency and accuracy in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-performance-using-cohere-rerank/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
