<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:56:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Bedrock powers next-generation account planning at AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how we built Account Plan Pulse, a generative AI tool designed to streamline and enhance the account planning process, using Amazon Bedrock. Pulse reduces review time and provides actionable account plan summaries for ease of collaboration and consumption, helping AWS sales teams better serve our customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-bedrock-powers-next-generation-account-planning-at-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pioneering AI workflows at scale: A deep dive into Asana AI Studio and Amazon Q index collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 21:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the integration of Asana AI Studio with Amazon Q index, bringing generative AI directly into your daily workflows. In this post, we explore how Asana AI Studio and Amazon Q index transform enterprise efficiency through intelligent workflow automation and enhanced data accessibility.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pioneering-ai-workflows-at-scale-a-deep-dive-into-asana-ai-studio-and-amazon-q-index-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI for the payments industry – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the unique challenges facing the payments industry in scaling AI adoption, the regulatory considerations that shape implementation decisions, and practical approaches to applying responsible AI principles. In Part 2, we provide practical implementation strategies to operationalize responsible AI within your payment systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-for-the-payments-industry-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI for the payments industry – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of our series, we explored the foundational concepts of responsible AI in the payments industry. In this post, we discuss the practical implementation of responsible AI frameworks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-for-the-payments-industry-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process multi-page documents with human review using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to process multi-page documents with a human review loop using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon SageMaker AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/process-multi-page-documents-with-human-review-using-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business with Amazon S3 clickable URLs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 01:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business that responds to user requests based on your enterprise documents stored in an S3 bucket, and how the users can use the reference URLs in the AI assistant responses to view or download the referred documents, and verify the AI responses to practice responsible AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-q-business-with-amazon-s3-clickable-urls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover insights from Microsoft Exchange with the Microsoft Exchange connector for Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Business is a fully managed, generative AI-powered assistant that helps enterprises unlock the value of their data and knowledge. With Amazon Q Business, you can quickly find answers to questions, generate summaries and content, and complete tasks by using the information and expertise stored across your company’s various data sources and enterprise systems. […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/discover-insights-from-microsoft-exchange-with-the-microsoft-exchange-connector-for-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost tracking multi-tenant model inference on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 01:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to track and analyze multi-tenant model inference costs on Amazon Bedrock using the Converse API&#39;s requestMetadata parameter. The solution includes an ETL pipeline using AWS Glue and Amazon QuickSight dashboards to visualize usage patterns, token consumption, and cost allocation across different tenants and departments.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/cost-tracking-multi-tenant-model-inference-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI judging AI: Scaling unstructured text analysis with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we highlight how you can deploy multiple generative AI models in Amazon Bedrock to instruct an LLM model to create thematic summaries of text responses. We then show how to use multiple LLM models as a jury to review these LLM-generated summaries and assign a rating to judge the content alignment between the summary title and summary description.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/ai-judging-ai-scaling-unstructured-text-analysis-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI-driven course content generation system using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore each component in detail, along with the technical implementation of the two core modules: course outline generation and course content generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-an-ai-driven-course-content-generation-system-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Handmade.com modernizes product image and description handling with Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Handmade.com, a leading hand-crafts marketplace, modernized their product description handling by implementing an AI-driven pipeline using Amazon Bedrock and Amazon OpenSearch Service. The solution combines Anthropic&#39;s Claude 3.7 Sonnet LLM for generating descriptions, Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2 for vector embedding, and semantic search capabilities to automate and enhance product descriptions across their catalog of over 60,000 items.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-handmade-com-modernizes-product-image-and-description-handling-with-amazon-bedrock-and-amazon-opensearch-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the newly announced Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser Tool. We explore why organizations need cloud-based browser automation and the limitations it addresses for FMs that require real-time data access. We talk about key use cases and the core capabilities of the AgentCore Browser Tool. We walk through how to get started with the tool.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser-tool/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Code Interpreter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Code Interpreter, a fully managed service that enables AI agents to securely execute code in isolated sandbox environments. We discuss how the AgentCore Code Interpreter helps solve challenges around security, scalability, and infrastructure management when deploying AI agents that need computational capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-the-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-code-interpreter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing and evaluating AI agentic workflows with Strands Agents SDK and Arize AX</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we present how the Arize AX service can trace and evaluate AI agent tasks initiated through Strands Agents, helping validate the correctness and trustworthiness of agentic workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/observing-and-evaluating-ai-agentic-workflows-with-strands-agents-sdk-and-arize-ax/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AIOps with Amazon Q Developer CLI and MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to implement a low-code no-code AIOps solution that helps organizations monitor, identify, and troubleshoot operational events while maintaining their security posture. We show how these technologies work together to automate repetitive tasks, streamline incident response, and enhance operational efficiency across your organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-aiops-with-amazon-q-developer-cli-and-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerize legacy Spring Boot application using Amazon Q Developer CLI and MCP server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, you’ll learn how you can use Amazon Q Developer command line interface (CLI) with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers integration to modernize a legacy Java Spring Boot application running on premises and then migrate it to Amazon Web Services (AWS) by deploying it on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/containerize-legacy-spring-boot-application-using-amazon-q-developer-cli-and-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing AWS Batch Support for Amazon SageMaker Training jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 17:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS Batch now seamlessly integrates with Amazon SageMaker Training jobs. In this post, we discuss the benefits of managing and prioritizing ML training jobs to use hardware efficiently for your business. We also walk you through how to get started using this new capability and share suggested best practices, including the use of SageMaker training plans.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/introducing-aws-batch-support-for-amazon-sagemaker-training-jobs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured outputs with Amazon Nova: A guide for builders</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We launched constrained decoding to provide reliability when using tools for structured outputs. Now, tools can be used with Amazon Nova foundation models (FMs) to extract data based on complex schemas, reducing tool use errors by over 95%. In this post, we explore how you can use Amazon Nova FMs for structured output use cases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/structured-outputs-with-amazon-nova-a-guide-for-builders/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI agents unifying structured and unstructured data: Transforming support analytics and beyond with Amazon Q Plugins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to enhance Amazon Q with custom plugins to combine semantic search capabilities with precise analytics for AWS Support data. This solution enables more accurate answers to analytical questions by integrating structured data querying with RAG architecture, allowing teams to transform raw support cases and health events into actionable insights. Discover how this enhanced architecture delivers exact numerical analysis while maintaining natural language interactions for improved operational decision-making.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Strands Agents SDK: A technical deep dive into agent architectures and observability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we first introduce the Strands Agents SDK and its core features. Then we explore how it integrates with AWS environments for secure, scalable deployments, and how it provides rich observability for production use. Finally, we discuss practical use cases, and present a step-by-step example to illustrate Strands in action.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-strands-agents-sdk-a-technical-deep-dive-into-agent-architectures-and-observability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build dynamic web research agents with the Strands Agents SDK and Tavily</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce how to combine Strands Agents with Tavily’s purpose-built web intelligence API, to create powerful research agents that excel at complex information gathering tasks while maintaining the security and compliance standards required for enterprise deployment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-dynamic-web-research-agents-with-the-strands-agents-sdk-and-tavily/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
