<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:45:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boost employee productivity with automated meeting summaries using Amazon Transcribe, Amazon SageMaker, and LLMs from Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents a solution to automatically generate a meeting summary from a recorded virtual meeting (for example, using Amazon Chime) with several participants. The recording is transcribed to text using Amazon Transcribe and then processed using Amazon SageMaker Hugging Face containers to generate the meeting summary. The Hugging Face containers host a large language model (LLM) from the Hugging Face Hub.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-employee-productivity-with-automated-meeting-summaries-using-amazon-transcribe-amazon-sagemaker-and-llms-from-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Veritone uses Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Rekognition, Amazon Transcribe, and information retrieval to update their video search pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 19:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is co-written with Tim Camara, Senior Product Manager at Veritone. Veritone is an artificial intelligence (AI) company based in Irvine, California. Founded in 2014, Veritone empowers people with AI-powered software and solutions for various applications, including media processing, analytics, advertising, and more. It offers solutions for media transcription, facial recognition, content summarization, object […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-veritone-uses-amazon-bedrock-amazon-rekognition-amazon-transcribe-and-information-retrieval-to-update-their-video-search-pipeline/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information extraction with LLMs using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 17:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2024/07_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) have unlocked new possibilities for extracting information from unstructured text data. Although much of the current excitement is around LLMs for generative AI tasks, many of the key use cases that you might want to solve have not fundamentally changed. Tasks such as routing support tickets, recognizing customers intents from a […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/information-extraction-with-llms-using-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionize Customer Satisfaction with tailored reward models for your business on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 16:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As more powerful large language models (LLMs) are used to perform a variety of tasks with greater accuracy, the number of applications and services that are being built with generative artificial intelligence (AI) is also growing. With great power comes responsibility, and organizations want to make sure that these LLMs produce responses that align with […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/revolutionize-customer-satisfaction-with-tailored-reward-models-for-your-business-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Personalize launches new recipes supporting larger item catalogs with lower latency</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability of two advanced recipes in Amazon Personalize, User-Personalization-v2 and Personalized-Ranking-v2 (v2 recipes), which are built on the cutting-edge Transformers architecture to support larger item catalogs with lower latency. In this post, we summarize the new enhancements, and guide you through the process of training a model and providing recommendations for your users.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/amazon-personalize-launches-new-recipes-supporting-larger-item-catalogs-with-lower-latency/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with Amazon Titan Text Embeddings V2: A new state-of-the-art embeddings model on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2024/02_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings are integral to various natural language processing (NLP) applications, and their quality is crucial for optimal performance. They are commonly used in knowledge bases to represent textual data as dense vectors, enabling efficient similarity search and retrieval. In Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), embeddings are used to retrieve relevant passages from a corpus to provide […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-started-with-amazon-titan-text-embeddings-v2-a-new-state-of-the-art-embeddings-model-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple guide to training Llama 2 with AWS Trainium on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Large language models (LLMs) are making a significant impact in the realm of artificial intelligence (AI). Their impressive generative abilities have led to widespread adoption across various sectors and use cases, including content generation, sentiment analysis, chatbot development, and virtual assistant technology. Llama2 by Meta is an example of an LLM offered by AWS. Llama […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simple-guide-to-training-llama-2-with-aws-trainium-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune and deploy language models with Amazon SageMaker Canvas and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine harnessing the power of advanced language models to understand and respond to your customers’ inquiries. Amazon Bedrock, a fully managed service providing access to such models, makes this possible. Fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) on domain-specific data supercharges tasks like answering product questions or generating relevant content. In this post, we show how Amazon […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-and-deploy-language-models-with-amazon-sagemaker-canvas-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving inclusion and accessibility through automated document translation with an open source app using Amazon Translate</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations often offer support in multiple languages, saying “contact us for translations.” However, customers who don’t speak the predominant language often don’t know that translations are available or how to request them. This can lead to poor customer experience and lost business. A better approach is proactively providing information in multiple languages so customers can […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improving-inclusion-and-accessibility-through-automated-document-translation-with-an-open-source-app-using-amazon-translate/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate chatbot for document and data retrieval using Agents and Knowledge Bases for Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2024/01_05_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Numerous customers face challenges in managing diverse data sources and seek a chatbot solution capable of orchestrating these sources to offer comprehensive answers. This post presents a solution for developing a chatbot capable of answering queries from both documentation and databases, with straightforward deployment. Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-chatbot-for-document-and-data-retrieval-using-agents-and-knowledge-bases-for-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
