<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:06:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Support for AWS DeepComposer ending soon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AWS DeepComposer was first introduced during AWS re:Invent 2019 as a fun way for developers to compose music by using generative AI. AWS DeepComposer was the world’s first machine learning (ML)-enabled keyboard for developers to get hands-on—literally—with a musical keyboard and the latest ML techniques to compose their own music. After careful consideration, we have […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/support-for-aws-deepcomposer-ending-soon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserve access and explore alternatives for Amazon Lookout for Equipment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_09_2024/17_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we discuss how you can maintain access to Lookout for Equipment after it is closed to new customers and some alternatives to Lookout for Equipment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/preserve-access-and-explore-alternatives-for-amazon-lookout-for-equipment/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR-Cas9 guide RNA efficiency prediction with efficiently tuned models in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat (CRISPR) technology holds the promise to revolutionize gene editing technologies, which is transformative to the way we understand and treat diseases. This technique is based in a natural mechanism found in bacteria that allows a protein coupled to a single guide RNA (gRNA) strand to locate and make […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/crispr-cas9-guide-rna-efficiency-prediction-with-efficiently-tuned-models-in-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve RAG performance using Cohere Rerank</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 19:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_09_2024/16_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to use Cohere Rerank to improve search efficiency and accuracy in Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/improve-rag-performance-using-cohere-rerank/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock AWS Cost and Usage insights with generative AI powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore a solution that uses generative artificial intelligence (AI) to generate a SQL query from a user’s question in natural language. This solution can simplify the process of querying CUR data stored in an Amazon Athena database using SQL query generation, running the query on Athena, and representing it on a web portal for ease of understanding.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-aws-cost-and-usage-insights-with-generative-ai-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline workflow orchestration of a system of enterprise APIs using chaining with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how chaining domain-specific agents using Amazon Bedrock Agents can transform a system of complex API interactions into streamlined, adaptive workflows, empowering your business to operate with agility and precision.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-workflow-orchestration-of-a-system-of-enterprise-apis-using-chaining-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build ultra-low latency multimodal generative AI applications using sticky session routing in Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 18:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_09_2024/13_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explained how the new sticky routing feature in Amazon SageMaker allows you to achieve ultra-low latency and enhance your end-user experience when serving multi-modal models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ultra-low-latency-multimodal-generative-ai-applications-using-sticky-session-routing-in-amazon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a RAG-based QnA application using Llama3 models from SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 22:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we provide a step-by-step guide for creating an enterprise ready RAG application such as a question answering bot. We use the Llama3-8B FM for text generation and the BGE Large EN v1.5 text embedding model for generating embeddings from Amazon SageMaker JumpStart.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-rag-based-qna-application-using-llama3-models-from-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best prompting practices for using Meta Llama 3 with Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 22:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we dive into the best practices and techniques for prompting Meta Llama 3 using Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to generate high-quality, relevant outputs. We discuss how to use system prompts and few-shot examples, and how to optimize inference parameters, so you can get the most out of Meta Llama 3.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/best-prompting-practices-for-using-meta-llama-3-with-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How healthcare payers and plans can empower members with generative AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 19:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how generative artificial intelligence (AI) can help health insurance plan members get the information they need. The solution presented in this post not only enhances the member experience by providing a more intuitive and user-friendly interface, but also has the potential to reduce call volumes and operational costs for healthcare payers and plans.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-healthcare-payers-and-plans-can-empower-members-with-generative-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling production-grade generative AI: New capabilities lower costs, streamline production, and boost security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 18:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As generative AI moves from proofs of concept (POCs) to production, we’re seeing a massive shift in how businesses and consumers interact with data, information—and each other. In what we consider “Act 1” of the generative AI story, we saw previously unimaginable amounts of data and compute create models that showcase the power of generative […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-production-grade-generative-ai-new-capabilities-lower-costs-streamline-production-and-boost-security/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Thomson Reuters’ language model research with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_09_2024/12_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore the journey that Thomson Reuters took to enable cutting-edge research in training domain-adapted large language models (LLMs) using Amazon SageMaker HyperPod, an Amazon Web Services (AWS) feature focused on providing purpose-built infrastructure for distributed training at scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/scaling-thomson-reuters-language-model-research-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of purpose-built accelerators for financial services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we aim to provide business leaders with a non-technical overview of purpose-built accelerators (PBAs) and their role within the financial services industry (FSI).
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/a-review-of-purpose-built-accelerators-for-financial-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly detection in streaming time series data with online learning using Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a robust real-time anomaly detection solution for streaming time series data using Amazon Managed Service for Apache Flink and other AWS managed services.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/anomaly-detection-in-streaming-time-series-data-with-online-learning-using-amazon-managed-service-for-apache-flink/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI-powered technology operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 19:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we describe how AWS generative AI solutions (including Amazon Bedrock, Amazon Q Developer, and Amazon Q Business) can further enhance TechOps productivity, reduce time to resolve issues, enhance customer experience, standardize operating procedures, and augment knowledge bases.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/generative-ai-powered-technology-operations/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing MLOps for Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 18:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review the guidance for optimizing MLOps for Sustainability on AWS, providing service-specific practices to understand and reduce the environmental impact of these workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/optimizing-mlops-for-sustainability/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling complex generative AI applications with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 14:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we take a closer look at Amazon Bedrock Agents. They empower you to build intelligent and context-aware generative AI applications, streamlining complex workflows and delivering natural, conversational user experiences.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enabling-complex-generative-ai-applications-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics England uses Amazon SageMaker to predict cancer subtypes and patient survival from multi-modal data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_09_2024/11_09_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we detail our collaboration in creating two proof of concept (PoC) exercises around multi-modal machine learning for survival analysis and cancer sub-typing, using genomic (gene expression, mutation and copy number variant data) and imaging (histopathology slides) data. We provide insights on interpretability, robustness, and best practices of architecting complex ML workflows on AWS with Amazon SageMaker. These multi-modal pipelines are being used on the Genomics England cancer cohort to enhance our understanding of cancer biomarkers and biology.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
