<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:43:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate Amazon QuickSight data stories creation with agentic AI using Amazon Nova Act</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how Amazon Nova Act automates QuickSight data story creation, saving time so you can focus on making critical, data-driven business decisions.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-amazon-quicksight-data-stories-creation-with-agentic-ai-using-amazon-nova-act/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement automated monitoring for Amazon Bedrock batch inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrated how a financial services company can use an FM to process large volumes of customer records and get specific data-driven product recommendations. We also showed how to implement an automated monitoring solution for Amazon Bedrock batch inference jobs. By using EventBridge, Lambda, and DynamoDB, you can gain real-time visibility into batch processing operations, so you can efficiently generate personalized product recommendations based on customer credit data.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI: How PowerSchool safeguards millions of students with AI-powered content filtering using Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how PowerSchool built and deployed a custom content filtering solution using Amazon SageMaker AI that achieved better accuracy while maintaining low false positive rates. We walk through our technical approach to fine tuning Llama 3.1 8B, our deployment architecture, and the performance results from internal validations.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-how-powerschool-safeguards-millions-of-students-with-ai-powered-content-filtering-using-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock global AI inference scalability using new global cross-Region inference on Amazon Bedrock  with Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 4.5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 21:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Organizations are increasingly integrating generative AI capabilities into their applications to enhance customer experiences, streamline operations, and drive innovation. As generative AI workloads continue to grow in scale and importance, organizations face new challenges in maintaining consistent performance, reliability, and availability of their AI-powered applications. Customers are looking to scale their AI inference workloads across […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlock-global-ai-inference-scalability-using-new-global-cross-region-inference-on-amazon-bedrock-with-anthropics-claude-sonnet-4-5/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure ingress connectivity to Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway using interface VPC endpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to access AgentCore Gateway through a VPC interface endpoint from an Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instance in a VPC. We also show how to configure your VPC endpoint policy to provide secure access to the AgentCore Gateway while maintaining the principle of least privilege access.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/secure-ingress-connectivity-to-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway-using-interface-vpc-endpoints/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance agentic workflows with enterprise search using Kore.ai and Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how organizations can enhance their employee productivity by integrating Kore.ai’s AI for Work platform with Amazon Q Business. We show how to configure AI for Work as a data accessor for Amazon Q index for independent software vendors (ISVs), so employees can search enterprise knowledge and execute end-to-end agentic workflows involving search, reasoning, actions, and content generation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhance-agentic-workflows-with-enterprise-search-using-kore-ai-and-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate development with the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore MCP server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 21:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server. With built-in support for runtime, gateway integration, identity management, and agent memory, the AgentCore MCP Server is purpose-built to speed up creation of components compatible with Bedrock AgentCore. You can use the AgentCore MCP server for rapid prototyping, production AI solutions, […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-development-with-the-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-mcpserver/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hapag-Lloyd improved schedule reliability with ML-powered vessel schedule predictions using Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Hapag-Lloyd developed and implemented a machine learning (ML)-powered assistant predicting vessel arrival and departure times that revolutionizes their schedule planning. By using Amazon SageMaker AI and implementing robust MLOps practices, Hapag-Lloyd has enhanced its schedule reliability—a key performance indicator in the industry and quality promise to their customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-hapag-lloyd-improved-schedule-reliability-with-ml-powered-vessel-schedule-predictions-using-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rox accelerates sales productivity with AI agents powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that Rox is generally available, with Rox infrastructure built on AWS and delivered across web, Slack, macOS, and iOS. In this post, we share how Rox accelerates sales productivity with AI agents powered by Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rox-accelerates-sales-productivity-with-ai-agents-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize fraud prevention: GraphStorm v0.5 for real-time inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 20:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to implement real-time fraud prevention using GraphStorm v0.5&#39;s new capabilities for deploying graph neural network (GNN) models through Amazon SageMaker. We show how to transition from model training to production-ready inference endpoints with minimal operational overhead, enabling sub-second fraud detection on transaction graphs with billions of nodes and edges.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/modernize-fraud-prevention-graphstorm-v0-5-for-real-time-inference/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
