<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:52:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining software development with the Amazon Q Developer Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Q Developer uses generative artificial intelligence (AI) to deliver state-of-the-art accuracy for all developers, taking first place on the leaderboard for SWE-bench, a dataset that tests a system’s ability to automatically resolve GitHub issues. This post describes how to get started with the software development agent, gives an overview of how the agent works, and discusses its performance on public benchmarks. We also delve into the process of getting started with the Amazon Q Developer Agent and give an overview of the underlying mechanisms that make it a state-of-the-art feature development agent.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started quickly with AWS Trainium and AWS Inferentia using AWS Neuron DLAMI and AWS Neuron DLC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with the AWS Neuron 2.18 release, you can now launch Neuron DLAMIs (AWS Deep Learning AMIs) and Neuron DLCs (AWS Deep Learning Containers) with the latest released Neuron packages on the same day as the Neuron SDK release. When a Neuron SDK is released, you’ll now be notified of the support for Neuron DLAMIs […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/get-started-quickly-with-aws-trainium-and-aws-inferentia-using-aws-neuron-dlami-and-aws-neuron-dlc/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprinklr improves performance by 20% and reduces cost by 25% for machine learning inference on AWS Graviton3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is a guest post co-written with Ratnesh Jamidar and Vinayak Trivedi from Sprinklr. Sprinklr’s mission is to unify silos, technology, and teams across large, complex companies. To achieve this, we provide four product suites, Sprinklr Service, Sprinklr Insights, Sprinklr Marketing, and Sprinklr Social, as well as several self-serve offerings. Each of these products are […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/sprinklr-improves-performance-by-20-and-reduces-cost-by-25-for-machine-learning-inference-on-aws-graviton3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Wiz is empowering organizations to remediate security risks faster with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2024/11_06_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Wiz is a cloud security platform that enables organizations to secure everything they build and run in the cloud by rapidly identifying and removing critical risks. Over 40% of the Fortune 100 trust Wiz’s purpose-built cloud security platform to gain full-stack visibility, accurate risk prioritization, and enhanced business agility. Organizations can connect Wiz in minutes […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-wiz-is-empowering-organizations-to-remediate-security-risks-faster-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code generation using Code Llama 70B and Mixtral 8x7B on Amazon SageMaker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 14:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2024/10_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the ever-evolving landscape of machine learning and artificial intelligence (AI), large language models (LLMs) have emerged as powerful tools for a wide range of natural language processing (NLP) tasks, including code generation. Among these cutting-edge models, Code Llama 70B stands out as a true heavyweight, boasting an impressive 70 billion parameters. Developed by Meta […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/code-generation-using-code-llama-70b-and-mixtral-8x7b-on-amazon-sagemaker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build RAG applications using Jina Embeddings v2 on Amazon SageMaker JumpStart</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2024/06_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce that the Jina Embeddings v2 model, developed by Jina AI, is available for customers through Amazon SageMaker JumpStart to deploy with one click for running model inference. This state-of-the-art model supports an impressive 8,192-tokens context length. You can deploy this model with SageMaker JumpStart, a machine learning (ML) hub […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-rag-applications-using-jina-embeddings-v2-on-amazon-sagemaker-jumpstart/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect email phishing attempts using Amazon Comprehend</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 19:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Phishing is the process of attempting to acquire sensitive information such as usernames, passwords and credit card details by masquerading as a trustworthy entity using email, telephone or text messages. There are many types of phishing based on the mode of communication and targeted victims. In an Email phishing attempt, an email is sent as […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/detect-email-phishing-attempts-using-amazon-comprehend/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Skyflow creates technical content in days using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_06_2024/05_06_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guest post is co-written with Manny Silva, Head of Documentation at Skyflow, Inc. Startups move quickly, and engineering is often prioritized over documentation. Unfortunately, this prioritization leads to release cycles that don’t match, where features release but documentation lags behind. This leads to increased support calls and unhappy customers. Skyflow is a data privacy […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-skyflow-creates-technical-content-in-days-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline custom model creation and deployment for Amazon Bedrock with Provisioned Throughput using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 17:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As customers seek to incorporate their corpus of knowledge into their generative artificial intelligence (AI) applications, or to build domain-specific models, their data science teams often want to conduct A/B testing and have repeatable experiments. In this post, we discuss a solution that uses infrastructure as code (IaC) to define the process of retrieving and […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/streamline-custom-model-creation-and-deployment-for-amazon-bedrock-with-provisioned-throughput-using-terraform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity with video conferencing transcripts and summaries with the Amazon Chime SDK Meeting Summarizer solution</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 16:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2024/04_06_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Businesses today heavily rely on video conferencing platforms for effective communication, collaboration, and decision-making. However, despite the convenience these platforms offer, there are persistent challenges in seamlessly integrating them into existing workflows. One of the major pain points is the lack of comprehensive tools to automate the process of joining meetings, recording discussions, and extracting […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/boost-productivity-with-video-conferencing-transcripts-and-summaries-with-the-amazon-chime-sdk-meeting-summarizer-solution/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
