<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:18:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simplify ModelOps with Amazon SageMaker AI Projects using Amazon S3-based templates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how you can use Amazon S3-based templates to simplify ModelOps workflows, walk through the key benefits compared to using Service Catalog approaches, and demonstrates how to create a custom ModelOps solution that integrates with GitHub and GitHub Actions—giving your team one-click provisioning of a fully functional ML environment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/simplify-modelops-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-projects-using-amazon-s3-based-templates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scale AI in South Africa using Amazon Bedrock global cross-Region inference with Anthropic Claude 4.5 models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk through how global cross-Region inference routes requests and where your data resides, then show you how to configure the required AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) permissions and invoke Claude 4.5 models using the global inference profile Amazon Resource Name (ARN). We also cover how to request quota increases for your workload. By the end, you&#39;ll have a working implementation of global cross-Region inference in af-south-1.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build reliable Agentic AI solution with Amazon Bedrock: Learn from Pushpay’s journey on GenAI evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2026/27_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2026/27_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we walk you through Pushpay&#39;s journey in building this solution and explore how Pushpay used Amazon Bedrock to create a custom generative AI evaluation framework for continuous quality assurance and establishing rapid iteration feedback loops on AWS.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-reliable-agentic-ai-solution-with-amazon-bedrock-learn-from-pushpays-journey-on-genai-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent contract management solution with Amazon Quick Suite and Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2026/27_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_01_2026/27_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post demonstrates how to build an intelligent contract management solution using Amazon Quick Suite as your primary contract management solution, augmented with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore for advanced multi-agent capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-contract-management-solution-with-amazon-quick-suite-and-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless AI Gateway architecture with AWS AppSync Events</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how to use AppSync Events as the foundation of a capable, serverless, AI gateway architecture. We explore how it integrates with AWS services for comprehensive coverage of the capabilities offered in AI gateway architectures. Finally, we get you started on your journey with sample code you can launch in your account and begin building.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-ai-gateway-architecture-with-aws-appsync-events/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Totogi automated change request processing with Totogi BSS Magic and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post describes how Totogi automates change request processing by partnering with the AWS Generative AI Innovation Center and using the rapid innovation capabilities of Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-totogi-automated-change-request-processing-with-totogi-bss-magic-and-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI agents with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore using AWS CloudFormation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Amazon Bedrock AgentCore services are now being supported by various IaC frameworks such as AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), Terraform and AWS CloudFormation Templates. This integration brings the power of IaC directly to AgentCore so developers can provision, configure, and manage their AI agent infrastructure. In this post, we use CloudFormation templates to build an end-to-end application for a weather activity planner.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-ai-agents-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-using-aws-cloudformation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Amazon.com Catalog Team built self-learning generative AI at scale with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how the Amazon Catalog Team built a self-learning system that continuously improves accuracy while reducing costs at scale using Amazon Bedrock.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-the-amazon-com-catalog-team-built-self-learning-generative-ai-at-scale-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
