<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:33:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Securing Amazon Bedrock Agents: A guide to safeguarding against indirect prompt injections</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI tools have transformed how we work, create, and process information. At Amazon Web Services (AWS), security is our top priority. Therefore, Amazon Bedrock provides comprehensive security controls and best practices to help protect your applications and data. In this post, we explore the security measures and practical strategies provided by Amazon Bedrock Agents to safeguard your AI interactions against indirect prompt injections, making sure that your applications remain both secure and reliable.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build scalable containerized RAG based generative AI applications in AWS using Amazon EKS with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate a solution using Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) with Amazon Bedrock to build scalable and containerized RAG solutions for your generative AI applications on AWS while bringing your unstructured user file data to Amazon Bedrock in a straightforward, fast, and secure way.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-scalable-containerized-rag-based-generative-ai-applications-in-aws-using-amazon-eks-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hexagon built an AI assistant using AWS generative AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 16:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_05_2025/13_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Recognizing the transformative benefits of generative AI for enterprises, we at Hexagon’s Asset Lifecycle Intelligence division sought to enhance how users interact with our Enterprise Asset Management (EAM) products. Understanding these advantages, we partnered with AWS to embark on a journey to develop HxGN Alix, an AI-powered digital worker using AWS generative AI services. This blog post explores the strategy, development, and implementation of HxGN Alix, demonstrating how a tailored AI solution can drive efficiency and enhance user satisfaction.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent community agent to revolutionize IT support with Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_05_2025/12_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how your organization can reduce the end-to-end burden of resolving regular challenges experienced by your IT support teams—from understanding errors and reviewing diagnoses, remediation steps, and relevant documentation, to opening external support tickets using common third-party services such as Jira.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-community-agent-to-revolutionize-it-support-with-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevate marketing intelligence with Amazon Bedrock and LLMs for content creation, sentiment analysis, and campaign performance evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_05_2025/09_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the media and entertainment industry, understanding and predicting the effectiveness of marketing campaigns is crucial for success. Marketing campaigns are the driving force behind successful businesses, playing a pivotal role in attracting new customers, retaining existing ones, and ultimately boosting revenue. However, launching a campaign isn’t enough; to maximize their impact and help achieve […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/elevate-marketing-intelligence-with-amazon-bedrock-and-llms-for-content-creation-sentiment-analysis-and-campaign-performance-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Deutsche Bahn redefines forecasting using Chronos models – Now available on Amazon Bedrock Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whereas traditional forecasting methods typically rely on statistical modeling, Chronos treats time series data as a language to be modeled and uses a pre-trained FM to generate forecasts — similar to how large language models (LLMs) generate texts. Chronos helps you achieve accurate predictions faster, significantly reducing development time compared to traditional methods. In this post, we share how Deutsche Bahn is redefining forecasting using Chronos models, and provide an example use case to demonstrate how you can get started using Chronos.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use custom metrics to evaluate your generative AI application with Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 21:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Now with Amazon Bedrock, you can develop custom evaluation metrics for both model and RAG evaluations. This capability extends the LLM-as-a-judge framework that drives Amazon Bedrock Evaluations. In this post, we demonstrate how to use custom metrics in Amazon Bedrock Evaluations to measure and improve the performance of your generative AI applications according to your specific business requirements and evaluation criteria.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/use-custom-metrics-to-evaluate-your-generative-ai-application-with-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
