<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:16:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build an agentic solution with Amazon Nova, Snowflake, and LangGraph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we cover how you can use tools from Snowflake AI Data Cloud and Amazon Web Services (AWS) to build generative AI solutions that organizations can use to make data-driven decisions, increase operational efficiency, and ultimately gain a competitive edge.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-agentic-solution-with-amazon-nova-snowflake-and-langgraph/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Spectrum fine-tuning to improve FM training efficiency on Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post you will learn how to use Spectrum to optimize resource use and shorten training times without sacrificing quality, as well as how to implement Spectrum fine-tuning with Amazon SageMaker AI training jobs. We will also discuss the tradeoff between QLoRA and Spectrum fine-tuning, showing that while QLoRA is more resource efficient, Spectrum results in higher performance overall.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/using-spectrum-fine-tuning-to-improve-fm-training-efficiency-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing tic-tac-toe to life with AWS AI services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RoboTic-Tac-Toe is an interactive game where two physical robots move around a tic-tac-toe board, with both the gameplay and robots’ movements orchestrated by LLMs. Players can control the robots using natural language commands, directing them to place their markers on the game board. In this post, we explore the architecture and prompt engineering techniques used to reason about a tic-tac-toe game and decide the next best game strategy and movement plan for the current player.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperPod enhances ML infrastructure with security and storage</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post introduces two major enhancements to Amazon SageMaker HyperPod that strengthen security and storage capabilities for large-scale machine learning infrastructure. The new features include customer managed key (CMK) support for encrypting EBS volumes with organization-controlled encryption keys, and Amazon EBS CSI driver integration that enables dynamic storage management for Kubernetes volumes in AI workloads.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/hyperpod-enhances-ml-infrastructure-with-security-and-storage/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating generative AI applications with a platform engineering approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, I will illustrate how applying platform engineering principles to generative AI unlocks faster time-to-value, cost control, and scalable innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-generative-ai-applications-with-a-platform-engineering-approach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your complete guide to Amazon Quick Suite at AWS re:Invent 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This year, re:Invent will be held in Las Vegas, Nevada, from December 1 to December 5, 2025, and this guide will help you navigate our comprehensive session catalog and plan your week. The sessions cater to business and technology leaders, product and engineering teams, and data and analytics teams interested in incorporating agentic AI capabilities across their teams and organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/your-complete-guide-to-amazon-quick-suite-at-aws-reinvent-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate enterprise solutions with agentic AI-powered consulting: Introducing AWS Professional Service Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;m excited to announce AWS Professional Services now offers specialized AI agents including the AWS Professional Services Delivery Agent. This represents a transformation to the consulting experience that embeds intelligent agents throughout the consulting life cycle to deliver better value for customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-enterprise-solutions-with-agentic-ai-powered-consulting-introducing-aws-professional-service-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude: Transforming business with agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_11_2025/17_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore and Claude are enabling enterprises like Cox Automotive and Druva to deploy production-ready agentic AI systems that deliver measurable business value, with results including up to 63% autonomous issue resolution and 58% faster response times. We examine the technical foundation combining Claude&#39;s frontier AI capabilities with AgentCore&#39;s enterprise-grade infrastructure that allows organizations to focus on agent logic rather than building complex operational systems from scratch.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a biomedical research agent with Biomni tools and Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a production-ready biomedical research agent by integrating Biomni&#39;s specialized tools with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Gateway, enabling researchers to access over 30 biomedical databases through a secure, scalable infrastructure. The implementation showcases how to transform research prototypes into enterprise-grade systems with persistent memory, semantic tool discovery, and comprehensive observability for scientific reproducibility .
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-biomedical-research-agent-with-biomni-tools-and-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your web apps hands-free with Amazon Nova Sonic</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Graphical user interfaces have carried the torch for decades, but today’s users increasingly expect to talk to their applications. In this post we show how we added a true voice-first experience to a reference application—the Smart Todo App—turning routine task management into a fluid, hands-free conversation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/make-your-web-apps-hands-free-with-amazon-nova-sonic/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the power of generative AI: Druva’s multi-agent copilot for streamlined data protection</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generative AI is transforming the way businesses interact with their customers and revolutionizing conversational interfaces for complex IT operations. Druva, a leading provider of data security solutions, is at the forefront of this transformation. In collaboration with Amazon Web Services (AWS), Druva is developing a cutting-edge generative AI-powered multi-agent copilot that aims to redefine the customer experience in data security and cyber resilience.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/harnessing-the-power-of-generative-ai-druvas-multi-agent-copilot-for-streamlined-data-protection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
