<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:03:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building health care agents using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this solution, we demonstrate how the user (a parent) can interact with a Strands or LangGraph agent in conversational style and get information about the immunization history and schedule of their child, inquire about the available slots, and book appointments. With some changes, AI agents can be made event-driven so that they can automatically send reminders, book appointments, and so on.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/building-health-care-agents-using-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build multi-agent site reliability engineering assistants with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 15:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_09_2025/26_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build a multi-agent SRE assistant using Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, LangGraph, and the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This system deploys specialized AI agents that collaborate to provide the deep, contextual intelligence that modern SRE teams need for effective incident response and infrastructure management.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-multi-agent-site-reliability-engineering-assistants-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DoWhile loops now supported in Amazon Bedrock Flows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce support for DoWhile loops in Amazon Bedrock Flows. With this powerful new capability, you can create iterative, condition-based workflows directly within your Amazon Bedrock flows, using Prompt nodes, AWS Lambda functions, Amazon Bedrock Agents, Amazon Bedrock Flows inline code, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases, Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3), […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/dowhile-loops-now-supported-in-amazon-bedrock-flows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How PropHero built an intelligent property investment advisor with continuous evaluation using Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how we built a multi-agent conversational AI system using Amazon Bedrock that delivers knowledge-grounded property investment advice. We explore the agent architecture, model selection strategy, and comprehensive continuous evaluation system that facilitates quality conversations while facilitating rapid iteration and improvement.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-prophero-built-an-intelligent-property-investment-advisor-with-continuous-evaluation-using-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate benefits claims processing with Amazon Bedrock Data Automation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the benefits administration industry, claims processing is a vital operational pillar that makes sure employees and beneficiaries receive timely benefits, such as health, dental, or disability payments, while controlling costs and adhering to regulations like HIPAA and ERISA. In this post, we examine the typical benefit claims processing workflow and identify where generative AI-powered automation can deliver the greatest impact.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-benefits-claims-processing-with-amazon-bedrock-data-automation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running deep research AI agents on Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI agents are evolving beyond basic single-task helpers into more powerful systems that can plan, critique, and collaborate with other agents to solve complex problems. Deep Agents—a recently introduced framework built on LangGraph—bring these capabilities to life, enabling multi-agent workflows that mirror real-world team dynamics. The challenge, however, is not just building such agents but […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/running-deep-research-ai-agents-on-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate tokenization with Amazon Bedrock Guardrails for secure data handling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show you how to integrate Amazon Bedrock Guardrails with third-party tokenization services to protect sensitive data while maintaining data reversibility. By combining these technologies, organizations can implement stronger privacy controls while preserving the functionality of their generative AI applications and related systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/integrate-tokenization-with-amazon-bedrock-guardrails-for-secure-data-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid ML experimentation for enterprises with Amazon SageMaker AI and Comet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_09_2025/22_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to use SageMaker and Comet together to spin up fully managed ML environments with reproducibility and experiment tracking capabilities.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/rapid-ml-experimentation-for-enterprises-with-amazon-sagemaker-ai-and-comet/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move your AI agents from proof of concept to production with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Amazon Bedrock AgentCore helps you transition your agentic applications from experimental proof of concept to production-ready systems. We follow the journey of a customer support agent that evolves from a simple local prototype to a comprehensive, enterprise-grade solution capable of handling multiple concurrent users while maintaining security and performance standards.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/move-your-ai-agents-from-proof-of-concept-to-production-with-amazon-bedrock-agentcore/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
