<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 19:32:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PwC and AWS Build Responsible AI with Automated Reasoning on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents how AWS and PwC are developing new reasoning checks that combine deep industry expertise with Automated Reasoning checks in Amazon Bedrock Guardrails to support innovation.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pwc-and-aws-build-responsible-ai-with-automated-reasoning-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon scaled Rufus by building multi-node inference using AWS Trainium chips and vLLM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Amazon shares how they developed a multi-node inference solution for Rufus, their generative AI shopping assistant, using Amazon Trainium chips and vLLM to serve large language models at scale. The solution combines a leader/follower orchestration model, hybrid parallelism strategies, and a multi-node inference unit abstraction layer built on Amazon ECS to deploy models across multiple nodes while maintaining high performance and reliability.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-scaled-rufus-by-building-multi-node-inference-using-aws-trainium-chips-and-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an intelligent financial analysis agent with LangGraph and Strands Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post describes an approach of combining three powerful technologies to illustrate an architecture that you can adapt and build upon for your specific financial analysis needs: LangGraph for workflow orchestration, Strands Agents for structured reasoning, and Model Context Protocol (MCP) for tool integration.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-intelligent-financial-analysis-agent-with-langgraph-and-strands-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory: Building context-aware agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Memory, a fully managed service that enables AI agents to maintain both immediate and long-term knowledge, transforming one-off conversations into continuous, evolving relationships between users and AI agents. The service eliminates complex memory infrastructure management while providing full control over what AI agents remember, offering powerful capabilities for maintaining both short-term working memory and long-term intelligent memory across sessions.
Link to article: https://aws.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a conversational natural language interface for Amazon Athena queries using Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore an innovative solution that uses Amazon Bedrock Agents, powered by Amazon Nova Lite, to create a conversational interface for Athena queries. We use AWS Cost and Usage Reports (AWS CUR) as an example, but this solution can be adapted for other databases you query using Athena. This approach democratizes data access while preserving the powerful analytical capabilities of Athena, so you can interact with your data using natural language.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train and deploy AI models at trillion-parameter scale with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod support for P6e-GB200 UltraServers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we review the technical specifications of P6e-GB200 UltraServers, discuss their performance benefits, and highlight key use cases. We then walk though how to purchase UltraServer capacity through flexible training plans and get started using UltraServers with SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/train-and-deploy-ai-models-at-trillion-parameter-scale-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-support-for-p6e-gb200-ultraservers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Indegene’s AI-powered social intelligence for life sciences turns social media conversations into insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores how Indegene’s Social Intelligence Solution uses advanced AI to help life sciences companies extract valuable insights from digital healthcare conversations. Built on AWS technology, the solution addresses the growing preference of HCPs for digital channels while overcoming the challenges of analyzing complex medical discussions on a scale.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-indegenes-ai-powered-social-intelligence-for-life-sciences-turns-social-media-conversations-into-insights/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking enhanced legal document review with Lexbe and Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, Lexbe, a legal document review software company, demonstrates how they integrated Amazon Bedrock and other AWS services to transform their document review process, enabling legal professionals to instantly query and extract insights from vast volumes of case documents using generative AI. Through collaboration with AWS, Lexbe achieved significant improvements in recall rates, reaching up to 90% by December 2024, and developed capabilities for broad human-style reporting and deep automated inference across multiple languages.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AIOps with SageMaker Unified Studio Projects, Part 2: Technical implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we focus on implementing this architecture with step-by-step guidance and reference code. We provide a detailed technical walkthrough that addresses the needs of two critical personas in the AI development lifecycle: the administrator who establishes governance and infrastructure through automated templates, and the data scientist who uses SageMaker Unified Studio for model development without managing the underlying infrastructure.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-aiops-with-sagemaker-unified-studio-projects-part-2-technical-implementation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate AIOps with Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio projects, Part 1: Solution architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post presents architectural strategies and a scalable framework that helps organizations manage multi-tenant environments, automate consistently, and embed governance controls as they scale their AI initiatives with SageMaker Unified Studio.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-aiops-with-amazon-sagemaker-unified-studio-projects-part-1-solution-architecture/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Amazon Bedrock Pricing for a Chatbot Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we&#39;ll look at Amazon Bedrock pricing through the lens of a practical, real-world example: building a customer service chatbot. We&#39;ll break down the essential cost components, walk through capacity planning for a mid-sized call center implementation, and provide detailed pricing calculations across different foundation models.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/demystifying-amazon-bedrock-pricing-for-a-chatbot-assistant/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune OpenAI GPT-OSS models on Amazon SageMaker AI using Hugging Face libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Released on August 5, 2025, OpenAI’s GPT-OSS models, gpt-oss-20b and gpt-oss-120b, are now available on AWS through Amazon SageMaker AI and Amazon Bedrock. In this post, we walk through the process of fine-tuning a GPT-OSS model in a fully managed training environment using SageMaker AI training jobs.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/fine-tune-openai-gpt-oss-models-on-amazon-sagemaker-ai-using-hugging-face-libraries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DIVA logistics agent, powered by Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we discuss how DTDC and ShellKode used Amazon Bedrock to build DIVA 2.0, a generative AI-powered logistics agent.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-diva-logistics-agent-powered-by-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate enterprise workflows by integrating Salesforce Agentforce with Amazon Bedrock Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 16:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores a practical collaboration, integrating Salesforce Agentforce with Amazon Bedrock Agents and Amazon Redshift, to automate enterprise workflows.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/automate-enterprise-workflows-by-integrating-salesforce-agentforce-with-amazon-bedrock-agents/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Bedrock powers next-generation account planning at AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how we built Account Plan Pulse, a generative AI tool designed to streamline and enhance the account planning process, using Amazon Bedrock. Pulse reduces review time and provides actionable account plan summaries for ease of collaboration and consumption, helping AWS sales teams better serve our customers.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/how-amazon-bedrock-powers-next-generation-account-planning-at-aws/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pioneering AI workflows at scale: A deep dive into Asana AI Studio and Amazon Q index collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 21:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce the integration of Asana AI Studio with Amazon Q index, bringing generative AI directly into your daily workflows. In this post, we explore how Asana AI Studio and Amazon Q index transform enterprise efficiency through intelligent workflow automation and enhanced data accessibility.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/pioneering-ai-workflows-at-scale-a-deep-dive-into-asana-ai-studio-and-amazon-q-index-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI for the payments industry – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the unique challenges facing the payments industry in scaling AI adoption, the regulatory considerations that shape implementation decisions, and practical approaches to applying responsible AI principles. In Part 2, we provide practical implementation strategies to operationalize responsible AI within your payment systems.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-for-the-payments-industry-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsible AI for the payments industry – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Part 1 of our series, we explored the foundational concepts of responsible AI in the payments industry. In this post, we discuss the practical implementation of responsible AI frameworks.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/responsible-ai-for-the-payments-industry-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process multi-page documents with human review using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon SageMaker AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to process multi-page documents with a human review loop using Amazon Bedrock Data Automation and Amazon SageMaker AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/process-multi-page-documents-with-human-review-using-amazon-bedrock-data-automation-and-amazon-sagemaker-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business with Amazon S3 clickable URLs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 01:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to build an AI assistant using Amazon Q Business that responds to user requests based on your enterprise documents stored in an S3 bucket, and how the users can use the reference URLs in the AI assistant responses to view or download the referred documents, and verify the AI responses to practice responsible AI.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-an-ai-assistant-using-amazon-q-business-with-amazon-s3-clickable-urls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
