<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws.amazon.com/Blogs/Machine-Learning on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximize HyperPod Cluster utilization with HyperPod task governance fine-grained quota allocation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability of fine-grained compute and memory quota allocation with HyperPod task governance. With this capability, customers can optimize Amazon SageMaker HyperPod cluster utilization on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), distribute fair usage, and support efficient resource allocation across different teams or projects. For more information, see HyperPod task governance best […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/maximize-hyperpod-cluster-utilization-with-hyperpod-task-governance-fine-grained-quota-allocation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and scale adoption of AI agents for education with Strands Agents, Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and LibreChat</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post demonstrates how to quickly build sophisticated AI agents using Strands Agents, scale them reliably with Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, and make them accessible through LibreChat’s familiar interface to drive immediate user adoption across your institution.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-and-scale-adoption-of-ai-agents-for-education-with-strands-agents-amazon-bedrock-agentcore-and-librechat/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skai uses Amazon Bedrock Agents to significantly improve customer insights by revolutionized data access and analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Skai (formerly Kenshoo) is an AI-driven omnichannel advertising and analytics platform designed for brands and agencies to plan, launch, optimize, and measure paid media across search, social, retail media marketplaces and other “walled-garden” channels from a single interface. In this post, we share how Skai used Amazon Bedrock Agents to improve data access and analysis and improve customer insights.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/skai-uses-amazon-bedrock-agents-to-significantly-improve-customer-insights-by-revolutionized-data-access-and-analysis/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of AI in driving personalized product discovery at Snoonu</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_09_2025/08_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization. In this post, we share how Snoonu, a leading ecommerce platform in the Middle East, transformed their product discovery experience using AI-powered personalization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/the-power-of-ai-in-driving-personalized-product-discovery-at-snoonu/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating HPC and AI research in universities with Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how a research university implemented SageMaker HyperPod to accelerate AI research by using dynamic SLURM partitions, fine-grained GPU resource management, budget-aware compute cost tracking, and multi-login node load balancing—all integrated seamlessly into the SageMaker HyperPod environment.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerating-hpc-and-ai-research-in-universities-with-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Real-Time Race Track with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:58:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_09_2025/05_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post explores the Real-Time Race Track (RTRT), an interactive experience built using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock, that lets fans design, customize, and share their own racing circuits. We highlight how generative AI capabilities come together to deliver strategic racing insights such as pit timing and tire choices, and interactive features like an AI voice assistant and a retro-style racing poster.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/exploring-the-real-time-race-track-with-amazon-nova/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build character consistent storyboards using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we take an animated short film, Picchu, produced by FuzzyPixel from Amazon Web Services (AWS), prepare training data by extracting key character frames, and fine-tune a character-consistent model for the main character Mayu and her mother, so we can quickly generate storyboard concepts for new sequels like the following images.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-character-consistent-storyboards-using-amazon-nova-in-amazon-bedrock-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build character consistent storyboards using Amazon Nova in Amazon Bedrock – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_09_2025/04_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The art of storyboarding stands as the cornerstone of modern content creation, weaving its essential role through filmmaking, animation, advertising, and UX design. Though traditionally, creators have relied on hand-drawn sequential illustrations to map their narratives, today’s AI foundation models (FMs) are transforming this landscape. FMs like Amazon Nova Canvas and Amazon Nova Reel offer […]
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-character-consistent-storyboards-using-amazon-nova-in-amazon-bedrock-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate Amazon Q Business data accessors using a trusted token issuer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we showed how to implement TTI authentication for Amazon Q data accessors. We covered the setup process for both ISVs and enterprises and demonstrated how TTI authentication simplifies the user experience while maintaining security standards.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/authenticate-amazon-q-business-data-accessors-using-a-trusted-token-issuer/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the future of professional services: How Proofpoint uses Amazon Q Business</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Proofpoint has redefined its professional services by integrating Amazon Q Business, a fully managed, generative AI powered assistant that you can configure to answer questions, provide summaries, generate content, and complete tasks based on your enterprise data. In this post, we explore how Amazon Q Business transformed Proofpoint’s professional services, detailing its deployment, functionality, and future roadmap.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/unlocking-the-future-of-professional-services-how-proofpoint-uses-amazon-q-business/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing LLM accuracy with Coveo Passage Retrieval on Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we show how to deploy Coveo’s Passage Retrieval API as an Amazon Bedrock Agents action group to enhance response accuracy, so Coveo users can use their current index to rapidly deploy new generative experiences across their organization.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/enhancing-llm-accuracy-with-coveo-passage-retrieval-on-amazon-bedrock/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train and deploy models on Amazon SageMaker HyperPod using the new HyperPod CLI and SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2025/03_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrate how to use the new Amazon SageMaker HyperPod CLI and SDK to streamline the process of training and deploying large AI models through practical examples of distributed training using Fully Sharded Data Parallel (FSDP) and model deployment for inference. The tools provide simplified workflows through straightforward commands for common tasks, while offering flexible development options through the SDK for more complex requirements, along with comprehensive observability features and production-ready deployment capabilities.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a serverless Amazon Bedrock batch job orchestration workflow using AWS Step Functions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we introduce a flexible and scalable solution that simplifies the batch inference workflow. This solution provides a highly scalable approach to managing your FM batch inference needs, such as generating embeddings for millions of documents or running custom evaluation or completion tasks with large datasets.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/build-a-serverless-amazon-bedrock-batch-job-orchestration-workflow-using-aws-step-functions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural language-based database analytics with Amazon Nova</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we explore how natural language database analytics can revolutionize the way organizations interact with their structured data through the power of large language model (LLM) agents. Natural language interfaces to databases have long been a goal in data management. Agents enhance database analytics by breaking down complex queries into explicit, verifiable reasoning steps and enabling self-correction through validation loops that can catch errors, analyze failures, and refine queries until they accurately match user intent and schema requirements.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases using Terraform for RAG-based generative AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post, we demonstrated how to automate the deployment of Amazon Knowledge Bases for RAG applications using Terraform.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/deploy-amazon-bedrock-knowledge-bases-using-terraform-for-rag-based-generative-ai-applications/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document intelligence evolved: Building and evaluating KIE solutions that scale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this blog post, we demonstrate an end-to-end approach for building and evaluating a KIE solution using Amazon Nova models available through Amazon Bedrock. This end-to-end approach encompasses three critical phases: data readiness (understanding and preparing your documents), solution development (implementing extraction logic with appropriate models), and performance measurement (evaluating accuracy, efficiency, and cost-effectiveness). We illustrate this comprehensive approach using the FATURA dataset—a collection of diverse invoice documents that serves as a representative proxy for real-world enterprise data.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the new cluster creation experience for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_09_2025/02_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the new cluster creation experience, you can create your SageMaker HyperPod clusters, including the required prerequisite AWS resources, in one click, with prescriptive default values automatically applied. In this post, we explore the new cluster creation experience for Amazon SageMaker HyperPod.
Link to article: https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/announcing-the-new-cluster-creation-experience-for-amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
