<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.50: Indispensable for Daily Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.50 represents a major leap forward in how development teams build, secure, and ship software. Across the last several releases, we&#39;ve delivered meaningful improvements that directly address the challenges you face every day: faster debugging workflows, enterprise-grade security controls that don&#39;t get in your way, and seamless AI integration that makes modern development...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-50/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Engine v29: Foundational Updates for the Future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is for Linux users running Docker Engine (Community Edition) directly on their hosts. Docker Desktop users don’t need to take any action — Engine updates are included automatically in future Desktop releases. Docker Engine v29 is a foundational release that sets the stage for the future of the Docker platform. While it may...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-engine-version-29/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Remote MCP Servers with OAuth in Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In just a year, the Model Context Protocol (MCP) has become the standard for connecting AI agents to tools and external systems. The Docker MCP Catalog now hosts hundreds of containerized local MCP servers, enabling developers to quickly experiment and prototype locally. We have now added support for remote MCP servers to the Docker MCP...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/connect-to-remote-mcp-servers-with-oauth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help Define the Future of Development – Take the Docker State of Application Development Survey 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the fourth annual Docker State of Application Development survey! Please help us better understand and serve the application development community with just 20 minutes of your time. We want to know where you’re focused, what you’re working on, and what is most important to you. Your thoughts and feedback will help us build...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/state-of-application-development-survey-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most DevSecOps Advice Is Useless without Context—Here’s What Actually Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generic DevSecOps advice may sound good on paper, but it often fails in practice because it ignores team context, workflow, and environment-specific needs. Overloaded controls, broad policies, and misapplied tools disrupt the flow of development. And once flow breaks, security measures are the first to get bypassed. The way forward isn&#39;t more rules but smarter...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/context-aware-devsecops-what-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic MCPs with Docker: Stop Hardcoding Your Agents’ World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MCP protocol is almost one year old and during that time, developers have built thousands of new MCP servers. Thinking back to MCP demos from six months ago, most developers were using one or two local MCP servers, each contributing just a handful of tools. Six months later and we have access to thousands...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/dynamic-mcps-stop-hardcoding-your-agents-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
