<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The GitHub Prompt Injection Data Heist</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 3 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that validate the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Toolkit provides enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to revolutionize how AI agents interact with developer tools, making GitHub repositories, Slack channels, and databases...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-github-prompt-injection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GPT-5 Launch Broke the AI Internet (And Not in a Good Way)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What That Means for Devs and AI App Companies When GPT-5 dropped, OpenAI killed off a bunch of older APIs without much warning. A whole lot of apps face-planted overnight. If your app hard-codes itself to one provider, one API shape, or one model, this is the nightmare scenario. This is also different from losing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/gpt5-api-deprecation-ai-app-failure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents made easy with Goose and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_08_2025/12_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents can be a complex task. But it also can be a fairly simple combination of answers to the following questions: What is the AI backend that powers my intelligent fuzzy computation? What tools do you need to give to the AI to access external systems or execute predefined software commands? What is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-with-goose-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling ≠ Glue: Why changing AI workflows still feels like duct tape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_08_2025/11_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There’s a weird contradiction in modern AI development. We have better tools than ever. We’re building smarter systems with cleaner abstractions. And yet, every time you try to swap out a component in your stack, things fall apart. Again. This isn’t just an inconvenience. It’s become the norm. You’d think with all the frameworks and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-changing-ai-workflows-still-feels-like-duct-tape/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remocal and Minimum Viable Models: Why Right-Sized Models Beat API Overkill</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_08_2025/09_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A practical approach to escaping the expensive, slow world of API-dependent AI The $20K Monthly Reality Check You built a simple sentiment analyzer for customer reviews. It works great. Except it costs $847/month in API calls and takes 2.3 seconds to classify a single review. Your &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; document classifier burns through $3,200/month. Your chatbot feature?...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/remocal-minimum-viable-models-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Recipe AI Agent with Koog and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m Philippe Charriere, a Principal Solutions Architect at Docker. I like to test new tools and see how they fit into real-world workflows. Recently, I set out to see if JetBrains&#39; Koog framework could run with Docker Model Runner, and what started as a quick test turned into something a lot more interesting than...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-a-recipe-ai-agent-with-koog-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Supply Chain Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 2 of our MCP Horror Stories series, an in-depth look at real-world security incidents exposing the vulnerabilities in AI infrastructure, and how the Docker MCP Toolkit delivers enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to be the &amp;quot;USB-C for AI applications&amp;quot; – a universal standard enabling AI agents like ChatGPT, Claude,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-the-supply-chain-attack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
