<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:32:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Docker Chose OCI Artifacts for AI Model Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI development accelerates, developers need tools that let them move fast without having to reinvent their workflows. Docker Model Runner introduces a new specification for packaging large language models (LLMs) as OCI artifacts — a format developers already know and trust. It brings model sharing into the same workflows used for containers, with support...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-docker-chose-oci-artifacts-for-ai-model-packaging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes: How we designed Docker Model Runner and what’s next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_06_2025/18_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The last few years have made it clear that AI models will continue to be a fundamental component of many applications. The catch is that they’re also a fundamentally different type of component, with complex software and hardware requirements that don’t (yet) fit neatly into the constraints of container-oriented development lifecycles and architectures. To help...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/behind-the-scenes-how-we-designed-docker-model-runner-and-whats-next/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build, Run, and Package AI Models Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_06_2025/12_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As a Senior DevOps Engineer and Docker Captain, I’ve helped build AI systems for everything from retail personalization to medical imaging. One truth stands out: AI capabilities are core to modern infrastructure. This guide will show you how to run and package local AI models with Docker Model Runner — a lightweight, developer-friendly tool...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-run-and-package-ai-models-locally-with-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing AI models to Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first released Docker Model Runner, it came with built-in support for running AI models published and maintained by Docker on Docker Hub. This made it simple to pull a model like llama3.2 or gemma3 and start using it locally with familiar Docker-style commands. Model Runner now supports three new commands: tag, push, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/publish-ai-models-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
