<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:55:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Hub MCP Server: A New Way to Discover, Inspect, and Manage Container Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Hub has become an essential resource for developers worldwide, serving 11 billion monthly image downloads and hosting over 14 million container images. As agentic AI proliferates, we&#39;re seeing a significant shift in how developers work. More and more developers are leveraging MCP (Model Context Protocol) servers to power their AI agents and automated workflows....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-hub-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Dev to Deploy: Compose as the Spine of the Application Lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody wants a spineless application development process. What do I mean by this? The spine is the backbone that supports and provides nerve channels for the human body. Without it, we would be floppy, weaker, and would struggle to understand how our extremities were behaving. A slightly tortured analogy, but consider the application lifecycle of...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-powering-the-full-app-lifecycle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Practices for Building, Testing, and Packaging MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently launched a new, reimagined Docker MCP Catalog with improved discovery and a new submission process. Containerized MCP servers offer a secure way to run and scale agentic applications and minimize risks tied to host access and secret management. Developers can submit servers in two ways: Docker-built servers, which include our full security suite...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-server-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.43: Expanded Model Runner, Reimagined MCP Catalog, MCP Server Submissions, and Smarter Gordon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.43 just rolled out a set of powerful updates that simplify how developers run, manage, and secure AI models and MCP tools. Model Runner now includes better model management, expanded OpenAI API compatibility, and fine-grained controls over runtime behavior. The improved MCP Catalog makes it easier to discover and use MCP servers, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gordon to Containerize Your Apps and Work with Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These days, almost every tech company is looking for ways to integrate AI into their apps and workflows, and Docker is no exception. They&#39;ve been rolling out some impressive AI capabilities across their products. This is my first post as a Docker Captain and in this post, I want to shine a spotlight on a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/containerize-your-apps-with-ask-gordon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: Dev Ex &amp; Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Report: What’s helping devs thrive — and what’s still holding them back? A look at how culture, tooling, and habits are shaping the developer experience today, per Docker’s 2025 State of Application Development Survey. Great culture, better tools — but developers often still feel stuck. From pull requests stuck in review to tasks without clear...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-dev-ex-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
