<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Develop and deploy voice AI apps using Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Voice is the next frontier of conversational AI. It is the most natural modality for people to chat and interact with another intelligent being. However, the voice AI software stack is complex, with many moving parts. Docker has emerged as one of the most useful tools for AI agent deployment. In this article, we&#39;ll explore...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/develop-deploy-voice-ai-apps/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now included with the Universal Blue family</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_12_2025/16_12_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large language models (LLMs) and other generative AI models can be a complex, frustrating process of managing dependencies, drivers, and environments. At Docker, we believe this should be as simple as docker model run. That&#39;s why we built Docker Model Runner, and today, we’re thrilled to announce a new collaboration with Universal Blue. Thanks...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-universal-blue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private MCP Catalogs and the Path to Composable Enterprise AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_12_2025/14_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Most discussions about Model Context Protocol infrastructure ask how to govern thousands of AI tools and monitor which MCP servers are running. This question is table stakes but undershoots the possibilities. A better question is how we can unleash MCP to drive developer creativity from a trusted foundation. The first question produces a phone book...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/private-mcp-catalogs-oci-composable-enterprise-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from AWS re:Invent: Supercharging Kiro with Docker Sandboxes and MCP Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the recent AWS re:Invent, Docker focused on a very real developer problem: how to run AI agents locally without giving them access to your machine, credentials, or filesystem. With AWS introducing Kiro, Docker demonstrated how Docker Sandboxes and MCP Toolkit allow developers to run agents inside isolated containers, keeping host environments and secrets out...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/aws-reinvent-kiro-docker-sandboxes-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is AI the New Insider Threat?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Insider threats have always been difficult to manage because they blur the line between trusted access and risky behavior. With generative AI, these risks aren&#39;t tied to malicious insiders misusing credentials or bypassing controls; they come from well-intentioned employees simply trying to get work done faster. Whether it&#39;s developers refactoring code, analysts summarizing long reports,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-insider-threat-shadow-ai-risk-controls/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add MCP Servers to ChatGPT with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_12_2025/12_12_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ChatGPT is great at answering questions and generating code. But here&#39;s what it can&#39;t do: execute that code, query your actual database, create a GitHub repo with your project, or scrape live data from websites. It&#39;s like having a brilliant advisor who can only talk, never act. Docker MCP Toolkit changes this completely. Here&#39;s what...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/add-mcp-server-to-chatgpt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Great news for Windows developers working with AI models: Docker Model Runner now supports vLLM on Docker Desktop for Windows with WSL2 and NVIDIA GPUs! Until now, vLLM support in Docker Model Runner was limited to Docker Engine on Linux. With this update, Windows developers can take advantage of vLLM&#39;s high-throughput inference capabilities directly through...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vllm-windows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free From AI Vendor Lock-in: Integrating GitHub Models with Docker cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2025/11_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The landscape of AI development is rapidly evolving, and one of the most exciting developments in 2025 from Docker is the release of Docker cagent. cagent is Docker&#39;s open-source multi-agent runtime that orchestrates AI agents through declarative YAML configuration. Rather than managing Python environments, SDK versions, and orchestration logic, developers define agent behavior in a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/configure-cagent-github-models/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Joins the Agentic AI Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2025/09_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, the Linux Foundation launched the Agentic AI Foundation with three founding projects: Anthropic&#39;s Model Context Protocol (MCP), Block&#39;s goose agent framework, and OpenAI&#39;s AGENTS.md standard. The foundation brings together the companies building the infrastructure layer for agents: Anthropic, Block, OpenAI, Amazon, Google, Microsoft, Cloudflare, and Bloomberg, alongside key tooling and platform companies. Docker is...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-joins-the-agentic-ai-foundation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
