<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:15:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Powering Local AI Together: Docker Model Runner on Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we always believe in the power of community and collaboration. It reminds me of what Robert Axelrod said in The Evolution of Cooperation: “The key to doing well lies not in overcoming others, but in eliciting their cooperation.” And what better place for Docker Model Runner to foster this cooperation than at Hugging...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-on-hugging-face/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Testing: Using Docker Model Runner with Microcks for Dynamic Mock APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_07_2025/14_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The non-deterministic nature of LLMs makes them ideal for generating dynamic, rich test data, perfect for validating app behavior and ensuring consistent, high-quality user experiences. Today, we’ll walk you through how to use Docker’s Model Runner with Microcks to generate dynamic mock APIs for testing your applications. Microcks is a powerful CNCF tool that allows...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-powered-mock-apis-for-testing-with-docker-and-microcks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a GenAI App With Java Using Spring AI and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 11:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When thinking about starting a Generative AI (GenAI) project, you might assume that Python is required to get started in this new space. However, if you’re already a Java developer, there’s no need to learn a new language. The Java ecosystem offers robust tools and libraries that make building GenAI applications both accessible and productive....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-genai-app-with-java-spring-ai-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Executive summary The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report offers an ultra high-resolution view of today’s fast-evolving dev landscape. Drawing insights from over 4,500 developers, engineers, and tech leaders — three times more users than last year — the survey explores tools, workflows, pain points, and industry trends. In this our third report, key...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2025-docker-state-of-app-dev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Brings Compose to the Agent Era: Building AI Agents is Now Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents are the future, and if you haven’t already started building agents, you probably will soon. Across industries and use cases, agents can act on our behalf, and offload repetitive work, because they can act on our behalf with judgment and context. But while agentic development is moving fast, today it’s tedious, hard, and not...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-ai-agents-with-docker-compose/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose your way with Provider services!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Docker Compose v2.36.0, we&#39;re excited to introduce a powerful new feature: provider services. This extension point opens up Docker Compose to interact not only with containers but also with any kind of external system, all while keeping the familiar Compose file at the center of the workflow. In this blog post,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-with-provider-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Gateway: Open Source, Secure Infrastructure for Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since releasing the Docker MCP Toolkit, we’ve seen strong community adoption, including steady growth in MCP server usage and over 1 million pulls from the Docker MCP Catalog. With the community, we’re laying the groundwork by standardizing how developers define, run, and share agent-based workloads with Docker Compose. Now, we’re expanding on that foundation with...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-gateway-secure-infrastructure-for-agentic-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
