<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your Copilot with SonarQube via Docker MCP Toolkit and Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_08_2025/29_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the era of AI copilots and code generation tools productivity is skyrocketing, but so is the risk of insecure, untested, or messy code slipping into production. How do you ensure it doesn’t introduce vulnerabilities, bugs, or bad practices? A widely adopted tool to help address these concerns is SonarQube. It provides a rich set...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/blog-sonarqube-copilot-docker-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design: A Shift-Left Approach with Testcontainers, Docker Scout, and Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_08_2025/28_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced world of software development, product teams are expected to move quickly: building features, shipping updates, and reacting to user needs in real-time. But moving fast should never mean compromising on quality or security. Thanks to modern tooling, developers can now maintain high standards while accelerating delivery. In a previous article, we explored...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/a-shift-left-approach-with-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop Accelerates Innovation with Faster Release Cadence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce a major evolution in how we deliver Docker Desktop updates to you. Starting with Docker Desktop release 4.45.0 on 28 August we&#39;re moving to releases every two weeks, with the goal of reaching weekly releases by the end of 2025. Why We&#39;re Making This Change You&#39;ve told us you want faster...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-updates-every-two-weeks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
