<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Compose to Kubernetes to Cloud: Designing and Operating Infrastructure with Kanvas</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_12_2025/08_12_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker has long been the simplest way to run containers. Developers start with a docker-compose.yml file, run docker compose up, and get things running fast. As teams grow and workloads expand into Kubernetes and integrate into cloud services, simplicity fades. Kubernetes has become the operating system of the cloud, but your clusters rarely live in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/compose-to-kubernetes-to-cloud-kanvas/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, JetBrains, and Zed: Building a Common Language for Agents and IDEs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As agents become capable enough to write and refactor code, they should work natively inside the environments developers work in: editors. That’s why JetBrains and Zed are co-developing ACP, the Agent Client Protocol. ACP gives agents and editors a shared language, so any agent can read context, take actions, and respond intelligently without bespoke wiring...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-jetbrains-and-zed-building-a-common-language-for-agents-and-ides/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing vLLM v0.12.0, Ministral 3 and DeepSeek-V3.2 for Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2025/05_12_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we are committed to making the AI development experience as seamless as possible. Today, we are thrilled to announce two major updates that bring state-of-the-art performance and frontier-class models directly to your fingertips: the immediate availability of Mistral AI’s Ministral 3 and DeepSeek-V3.2, alongside the release of vLLM v0.12.0 on Docker Model Runner....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vllm-ministral-deepseek/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing the Docker MCP Catalog: Commit Pinning, Agentic Auditing, and Publisher Trust Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trust is the most important consideration when you connect AI assistants to real tools. While MCP containerization provides strong isolation and limits the blast radius of malfunctioning or compromised servers, we’re continuously strengthening trust and security across the Docker MCP solutions to further reduce exposure to malicious code. As the MCP ecosystem scales from hundreds...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/enhancing-mcp-trust-with-the-docker-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents shouldn’t be hard. According to theCUBE Research, Docker makes it easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For most developers, getting started with AI is still too complicated. Different models, tools, and platforms don’t always play nicely together. But with Docker, that’s changing fast. Docker is emerging as essential infrastructure for standardized, portable, and scalable AI environments. By bringing composability, simplicity, and GPU accessibility to the agentic era, Docker is helping developers...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-shouldnt-be-hard-according-to-thecube-research-docker-makes-it-easy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Embedding Models and Unlock Semantic Search with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings have become the backbone of many modern AI applications. From semantic search to retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and intelligent recommendation systems, embedding models enable systems to understand the meaning behind text, code, or documents, not just the literal words. But generating embeddings comes with trade-offs. Using a hosted API for embedding generation often results in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-embedding-models-for-semantic-search/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
