<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Trends Report 2024: AI’s Growing Role in Software Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_04_2024/16_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The most recent Docker State of Application Development Survey results offer insights into how developers are adopting and utilizing AI, reflecting a shift toward more intelligent, efficient, and adaptable development methodologies.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-trends-report-2024/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Error Handling: How Docker Desktop 4.29 Aims to Simplify Developer Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the Docker Desktop 4.29 release, we&#39;ve embarked on an ambitious journey to elevate the user experience by fundamentally redefining error management. Learn more about this intuitive new prompt that sheds light on the mysterious seas of error messages.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/next-level-error-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.29: Docker Socket Mount Permissions in ECI, Advanced Error Management, Moby 26, and New Beta Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.29 introduces enhancements to secure and streamline the development process and to improve error management and workflow efficiency. With the integration of Enhanced Container Isolation (ECI) with Docker socket mount permissions, the debut of Moby 26 within Docker Desktop, and exciting features such as Docker Compose enhancements via synchronized file shares reaching Beta, we&#39;re equipping developers with the essential resources to tackle the complexities of modern development head-on.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
