<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:48:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tool Calling with Local LLMs: A Practical Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Which local model should I use for tool calling? When building GenAI and agentic applications, one of the most pressing and persistent questions is: “Which local model should I use for tool calling?” We kept hearing again and again, from colleagues within Docker and the developer community, ever since we started working on Docker Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/local-llm-tool-calling-a-practical-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Easy Private AI Assistant with Goose and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Goose is an innovative CLI assistant designed to automate development tasks using AI models. Docker Model Runner simplifies deploying AI models locally with Docker. Combining these technologies creates a powerful local environment with advanced AI assistance, ideal for coding and automation. Looking for a seamless way to run AI-powered development tasks locally without compromising on...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-an-ai-assistant-with-goose-and-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing software development — but not how you think The hype is real, but so are the challenges. Here&#39;s what developers, teams, and tech leaders need to know about AI’s uneven, evolving role in software. Rumors of AI’s pervasiveness in software development have been greatly exaggerated. A look under the hood shows adoption...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
