<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:11:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Run Claude Code Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently showed how to pair OpenCode with Docker Model Runner for a privacy-first, cost-effective AI coding setup. Today, we&#39;re bringing the same approach to Claude Code, Anthropic&#39;s agentic coding tool. This post walks through how to configure Claude Code to use Docker Model Runner, giving you full control over your data, infrastructure, and spend....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-claude-code-locally-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Enterprise Trial – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customizing Docker Hardened Images In Part 1 and Part 2, we established the baseline. You migrated a service to a Docker Hardened Image (DHI), witnessed the vulnerability count drop to zero, and verified the cryptographic signatures and SLSA provenance that make DHI a compliant foundation. But no matter how secure a base image is, it...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-enterprise-trial-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Enterprise Trial – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Verifying Security and Compliance of Docker Hardened Images In Part 1 of this series, we migrated a Node.js service to Docker Hardened Images (DHI) and measured impressive results: 100% vulnerability elimination, 90% package reduction, and 41.5% size decrease. We extracted the SBOM and saw compliance labels for FIPS, STIG, and CIS. The numbers look compelling....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-enterprise-trial-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Automate Arm Migration with Docker MCP Toolkit, VS Code, and GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is a collaboration between Docker and Arm, demonstrating how Docker MCP Toolkit and the Arm MCP Server work together to simplify architecture migrations. Moving workloads from x86 to Arm64 architecture has become increasingly important. Organizations seek to reduce cloud costs and improve performance. AWS Graviton, Azure Cobalt, and Google Cloud Axion have made...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/automate-arm-migration-docker-mcp-copilot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MCP Servers: From Quick Tools to Multi-Agent Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers are a spec for exposing tools, models, or services to language models through a common interface. Think of them as smart adapters: they sit between a tool and the LLM, speaking a predictable protocol that lets the model interact with things like APIs, databases, and agents without needing to know...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-servers-docker-toolkit-cagent-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Dependencies Don’t Care About Your FIPS Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            FIPS compliance is a great idea that makes the entire software supply chain safer. But teams adopting FIPS-enabled container images are running into strange errors that can be challenging to debug. What they are learning is that correctness at the base image layer does not guarantee compatibility across the ecosystem. Change is complicated, and changing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fips-dependencies-and-prebuilt-binaries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
