<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:51:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clawdbot with Docker Model Runner, a Private Personal AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Personal AI assistants are transforming how we manage our daily lives—from handling emails and calendars to automating smart homes. However, as these assistants gain more access to our private data, concerns about privacy, data residency, and long-term costs are at an all-time high. By combining Clawdbot with Docker Model Runner (DMR), you can build a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/clawdbot-docker-model-runner-private-personal-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Claude Code Locally with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_01_2026/26_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We recently showed how to pair OpenCode with Docker Model Runner for a privacy-first, cost-effective AI coding setup. Today, we&#39;re bringing the same approach to Claude Code, Anthropic&#39;s agentic coding tool. This post walks through how to configure Claude Code to use Docker Model Runner, giving you full control over your data, infrastructure, and spend....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-claude-code-locally-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Enterprise Trial – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_01_2026/25_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customizing Docker Hardened Images In Part 1 and Part 2, we established the baseline. You migrated a service to a Docker Hardened Image (DHI), witnessed the vulnerability count drop to zero, and verified the cryptographic signatures and SLSA provenance that make DHI a compliant foundation. But no matter how secure a base image is, it...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-enterprise-trial-part-3/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Enterprise Trial – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_01_2026/24_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Verifying Security and Compliance of Docker Hardened Images In Part 1 of this series, we migrated a Node.js service to Docker Hardened Images (DHI) and measured impressive results: 100% vulnerability elimination, 90% package reduction, and 41.5% size decrease. We extracted the SBOM and saw compliance labels for FIPS, STIG, and CIS. The numbers look compelling....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-enterprise-trial-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
