<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:19:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Docker Premium Support and TAM service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Docker Customer Success and Technical Account Management organizations are excited to introduce the Premium Support and TAM service — a new service designed to extend Docker’s support to always-on 24/7, priority SLAs, expert guidance, and TAM add-on services. We have carefully designed these new services to support our valued customers’ developers and global business...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-the-docker-premium-support-and-tam-service/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run, Test, and Evaluate Models and MCP Locally with Docker &#43; Promptfoo</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_09_2025/25_09_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Promptfoo is an open-source CLI and library for evaluating LLM apps. Docker Model Runner makes it easy to manage, run, and deploy AI models using Docker. The Docker MCP Toolkit is a local gateway that lets you set up, manage, and run containerized MCP servers and connect them to AI agents. Together, these tools let...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/evaluate-models-and-mcp-with-promptfoo-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Drive-By Localhost Breach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_09_2025/23_09_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 4 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that expose the devastating vulnerabilities in AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Gateway provides enterprise-grade protection against sophisticated attack vectors. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) has transformed how developers integrate AI agents with their development environments. Tools like...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mpc-horror-stories-cve-2025-49596-local-host-breach/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Component Updates &amp; Redesigned Update Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 13:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following on from our previous initiative to improve how Docker Desktop delivers updates, we are excited to announce another major improvement to how Docker Desktop keeps your development tools up to date. Starting with Docker Desktop 4.46, we&#39;re introducing automatic component updates and a completely redesigned update experience that puts your productivity first. Why We&#39;re...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-silent-component-updates/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Containers: llama.cpp Now Pulls GGUF Models Directly from Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_09_2025/19_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The world of local AI is moving at an incredible pace, and at the heart of this revolution is llama.cpp—the powerhouse C++ inference engine that brings Large Language Models (LLMs) to everyday hardware (and it’s also the inference engine that powers Docker Model Runner). Developers love llama.cpp for its performance and simplicity. And we at...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/llama-cpp-pulls-gguf-models-from-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Distribute AI Agents and Workflows with cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            cagent is a new open-source project from Docker that makes it simple to build, run, and share AI agents, without writing a single line of code. Instead of writing code and wrangling Python versions and dependencies when creating AI agents, you define your agent&#39;s behavior, tools, and persona in a single YAML file, making it...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/cagent-build-and-distribute-ai-agents-and-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker and CNCF: Partnering to Power the Future of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, open source is not just something we support; it&#39;s a core part of our culture. It’s part of our DNA. From foundational projects like Docker Compose (35.5k stars, 5.4k forks) and Moby (69.8k stars, 18.8k forks) to our continued code contributions, we remain committed to strengthening the open-source ecosystem. Today, we are announcing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-cncf-partnership/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner General Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_09_2025/18_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to share that Docker Model Runner is now generally available (GA)! In April 2025, Docker introduced the first Beta release of Docker Model Runner, making it easy to manage, run, and distribute local AI models (specifically LLMs). Though only a short time has passed since then, the product has evolved rapidly, with continuous...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/announcing-docker-model-runner-ga/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
