<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Join Docker CEO Scott Johnston at SwampUP 2024 in Austin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_09_2024/06_09_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover how Docker and JFrog are enhancing secure software development at SwampUP 2024 in Austin, Texas, from September 9-11. Docker CEO Scott Johnston will highlight the critical roles of Docker Desktop, Docker Hub, and Docker Scout in building secure, efficient applications, showcasing their integration within JFrog’s platform.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/swampup-2024-austin/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Docker Desktop Enterprise Admin Features: MSI Installer and Login Enforcement Alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to launch the general availability for two significant updates: the Docker Desktop MSI installer and a new sign-in enforcement alternative. These updates aim to streamline administration, improve security, and ensure users can take full advantage of Docker Business subscription features.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-msi-installer-login-enforcement-alternatives/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.34: MSI Installer GA, Upgraded Host Networking, and Powerful Enhancements for Boosted Productivity &amp; Administration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_09_2024/03_09_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover Docker Desktop 4.34&#39;s enhancements that boost security, scalability, and productivity for developers. This release includes a readily available MSI installer for simpler Windows deployment, improved authentication processes, smart storage compaction for WSL2, and seamless NVIDIA AI Workbench integration for streamlined model training and local development.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-34/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
