<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:55:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I joined Docker: security at the center of the software supply chain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mark Lechner, Docker’s CISO, shares his vision for a future where Docker not only powers the software supply chain, but actively safeguards it. Cybersecurity has reached a turning point. The most significant threats no longer exploit isolated systems; they move through the connections between them. The modern attack surface includes every dependency, every container, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-i-joined-docker-security-at-the-center-of-the-software-supply-chain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Must-Have MCP Servers (and How to Use Them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The era of AI agents has arrived, and with it, a new standard for how they connect to tools: the Model Context Protocol (MCP). MCP unlocks powerful, flexible workflows by letting agents tap into external tools and systems. But with thousands of MCP servers (including remote ones) now available, it’s easy to ask: Where do...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/top-mcp-servers-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; Unsloth: Build Custom Models, Faster</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building and Running Custom Models Is Still Hard Running AI models locally is still hard. Even as open-source LLMs grow more capable, actually getting them to run on your machine, with the right dependencies, remains slow, fragile, and inconsistent. There’s two sides to this challenge: Model creation and optimization: making fine-tuning and quantization efficient. Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-unsloth-build-custom-models-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch a Chat UI Agent with Docker and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running a Chat UI Agent doesn’t have to involve a complicated setup. By combining Docker with the Vercel AI SDK, it’s possible to build and launch a conversational interface in a clean, reproducible way. Docker ensures that the environment is consistent across machines, while the Vercel AI SDK provides the tools for handling streaming responses...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/launch-chat-ui-agent-docker-vercel-ai-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Trial – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First steps: Run your first secure, production-ready image Container base images form the foundation of your application security. When those foundations contain vulnerabilities, every service built on top inherits the same risk. Docker Hardened Images addresses this at the source. These are continuously-maintained, minimal base images designed for security: stripped of unnecessary packages, patched proactively,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-trial-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Great AI Productivity Divide: Why Are Some Developers 5x Faster?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered developer tools claim to boost your productivity, doing everything from intelligent auto-complete to (https://openai.com/index/introducing-codex/). But the productivity gains users report have been something of a mixed bag. Some groups claim to get 3-5x (or more), productivity boosts, while other devs claim to get no benefit at all—or even losses of up to 19%. I...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-productivity-divide-developers-5x-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cagent Comes to Docker Desktop with Built-In IDE Support through ACP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop now includes cagent bundled out of the box. This means developers can start building AI agents without a separate installation step. For those unfamiliar with cagent: it’s Docker’s open-source tool that lets you build AI agents using YAML configuration files instead of writing code. You define the agent’s behavior and tools, and cagent...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/cagent-comes-to-docker-desktop-with-built-in-ide-support-through-acp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The WhatsApp Data Exfiltration Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 5 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that highlight the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker’s comprehensive AI security platform provides protection against these threats. Model Context Protocol (MCP) promises seamless integration between AI agents and communication platforms like WhatsApp, enabling automated message...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-whatsapp-data-exfiltration-issue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.50: Indispensable for Daily Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.50 represents a major leap forward in how development teams build, secure, and ship software. Across the last several releases, we&#39;ve delivered meaningful improvements that directly address the challenges you face every day: faster debugging workflows, enterprise-grade security controls that don&#39;t get in your way, and seamless AI integration that makes modern development...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-50/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
