<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Most DevSecOps Advice Is Useless without Context—Here’s What Actually Works</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Generic DevSecOps advice may sound good on paper, but it often fails in practice because it ignores team context, workflow, and environment-specific needs. Overloaded controls, broad policies, and misapplied tools disrupt the flow of development. And once flow breaks, security measures are the first to get bypassed. The way forward isn&#39;t more rules but smarter...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/context-aware-devsecops-what-works/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic MCPs with Docker: Stop Hardcoding Your Agents’ World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MCP protocol is almost one year old and during that time, developers have built thousands of new MCP servers. Thinking back to MCP demos from six months ago, most developers were using one or two local MCP servers, each contributing just a handful of tools. Six months later and we have access to thousands...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/dynamic-mcps-stop-hardcoding-your-agents-world/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Multimodal AI Models With Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the most exciting advances in modern AI is multimodal support, the ability for models to understand and generate multiple types of input, such as text, images, or audio. With multimodal models, you’re no longer limited to typing prompts; you can show an image or play a sound, and the model can understand it....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-use-multimodel-ai-with-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Doesn’t Have to Hurt</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you ever wish security would stop blocking the tools you need to do your job? Surprise: your security team wants the same. There you are, just trying to get your work done, when… You need an AI to translate documentation, but all the AI services are blocked by a security web monitoring tool. You...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-shadow-it-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Bones: A Pirate-Voiced Halloween Chatbot Powered by Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My name is Mike Coleman, a staff solution architect at Docker. This year I decided to turn a Home Depot animatronic skeleton into an AI-powered, live, interactive Halloween chatbot. The result: kids walk up to Mr. Bones, a spooky skeleton in my yard, ask it questions, and it answers back — in full pirate voice...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/talking-skeleton-docker-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
