<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:10:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Supply Chain Paradox: When “Hardened” Images Become a Vendor Lock-in Trap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The market for pre-hardened container images is experiencing explosive growth as security-conscious organizations pursue the ultimate efficiency: instant security with minimal operational overhead. The value proposition is undeniably compelling—hardened images with minimal dependencies promise security &amp;quot;out of the box,&amp;quot; enabling teams to focus on building and shipping applications rather than constantly revisiting low-level configuration management....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-container-images-security-vendor-lock-in/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamline NGINX Configuration with Docker Desktop Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker periodically highlights blog posts featuring use cases and success stories from Docker partners and practitioners. This story was contributed by Dylen Turnbull and Timo Stark. With over 29 years in enterprise and open-source software development, Dylen Turnbull has held roles at Symantec, Veritas, F5 Networks, and most recently as a Developer Advocate for NGINX....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/streamline-nginx-configuration-with-docker-desktop-extension/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents with Docker MCP Toolkit: A Developer’s Real-World Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_08_2025/19_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents in the real world often involves more than just making model calls — it requires integrating with external tools, handling complex workflows, and ensuring the solution can scale in production. In this post, we’ll walk through a real-world developer setup for creating an agent using the Docker MCP Toolkit. To make things...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-ai-agent-developer-setup/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker @ Black Hat 2025: CVEs have everyone’s attention, here’s the path forward</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            CVEs dominated the conversation at Black Hat 2025. Across sessions, booth discussions, and hallway chatter, it was clear that teams are feeling the pressure to manage vulnerabilities at scale. While scanning remains an important tool, the focus is shifting toward removing security debt before it enters the software supply chain. Hardened images, compliance-ready tooling, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-black-hat-2025-secure-software-supply-chain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practitioner’s view on how Docker enables security by default and makes developers work better</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_08_2025/15_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post was written by Docker Captains, experienced professionals recognized for their expertise with Docker. It shares their firsthand, real-world experiences using Docker in their own work or within the organizations they lead. Docker Captains are technical experts and passionate community builders who drive Docker’s ecosystem forward. As active contributors and advocates, they share...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-enables-security-by-default/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.44: Smarter AI Modeling, Platform Stability, and Streamlined Kubernetes Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 20:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Docker Desktop 4.44, we’ve focused on delivering enhanced reliability, tighter AI modeling controls, and simplified tool integrations so you can build on your terms. Docker Model Runner Enhancements Inspectable Model Runner Workflows Now you can inspect AI inference requests and responses directly from Docker Model Runner (DMR), helping you troubleshoot and debug model behavior...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-44/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The GitHub Prompt Injection Data Heist</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_08_2025/14_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 3 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that validate the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker MCP Toolkit provides enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to revolutionize how AI agents interact with developer tools, making GitHub repositories, Slack channels, and databases...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-github-prompt-injection/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GPT-5 Launch Broke the AI Internet (And Not in a Good Way)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_08_2025/13_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What That Means for Devs and AI App Companies When GPT-5 dropped, OpenAI killed off a bunch of older APIs without much warning. A whole lot of apps face-planted overnight. If your app hard-codes itself to one provider, one API shape, or one model, this is the nightmare scenario. This is also different from losing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/gpt5-api-deprecation-ai-app-failure/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
