<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:23:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a Recipe AI Agent with Koog and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_08_2025/08_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m Philippe Charriere, a Principal Solutions Architect at Docker. I like to test new tools and see how they fit into real-world workflows. Recently, I set out to see if JetBrains&#39; Koog framework could run with Docker Model Runner, and what started as a quick test turned into something a lot more interesting than...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-a-recipe-ai-agent-with-koog-and-docker/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The Supply Chain Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_08_2025/07_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 2 of our MCP Horror Stories series, an in-depth look at real-world security incidents exposing the vulnerabilities in AI infrastructure, and how the Docker MCP Toolkit delivers enterprise-grade protection. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) promised to be the &amp;quot;USB-C for AI applications&amp;quot; – a universal standard enabling AI agents like ChatGPT, Claude,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-the-supply-chain-attack/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating FedRAMP Compliance with Docker Hardened Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) compliance costs typically range from $450,000 to over $2 million and take 12 to 18 months to achieve, time your competitors are using to capture government contracts. While you’re spending months configuring FIPS cryptography, hardening security baselines, and navigating 400+ security controls, your competitors are already shipping to...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fedramp-compliance-with-hardened-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Evolution of Docker Hardened Images: Customizable, FedRAMP Ready, AI Migration Agent, and Deeper Integrations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_08_2025/06_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We launched Docker Hardened Images (DHI) in May, and in just two and a half months, adoption has accelerated rapidly across industries. From nimble startups to global enterprises, organizations are turning to DHI to achieve near-zero CVEs, shrink their attack surface, and harden their software supply chain, all without slowing down developers. In a short...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/the-next-evolution-of-docker-hardened-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone’s a Snowflake: Designing Hardened Image Processes for the Real World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 18:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_08_2025/05_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hardened container images and distroless software are the new hotness as startups and incumbents alike pile into the fast-growing market. In theory, hardened images provide not only a smaller attack surface but operational simplicity. In practice, there remains a fundamental – and often painful – tension between the promised security perfection of hardened images and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-image-best-practices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Docker MCP Toolkit Works with VS Code Copilot Agent Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 20:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of software development, integrating modern AI tools is essential to boosting productivity and enhancing the developer experience. One such advancement is the integration of Docker&#39;s Model Context Protocol (MCP) Toolkit with Visual Studio Code’s GitHub Copilot Agent Mode. This powerful combination transforms how developers interact with containerized applications, enabling autonomous...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-and-vs-code-copilot-agent/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Questions: What You Should Really Be Asking Your Hardened Image Provider Before You Press the Buy Button</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When evaluating hardened image providers, don&#39;t just look for buzzwords like &amp;quot;zero-CVE&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;minimal.&amp;quot; True security in a dynamic environment demands a nuanced understanding of their process, their commitment, and their flexibility. For platform, DevOps, and SecOps teams, these are the critical questions that reveal whether a provider offers genuine security that enhances your workflow,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/container-security-hardened-images-questions/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
