<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:11:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Hardened Images: crafted by humans, protected by AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Docker, we are building our hardened images to exacting standards. That means carefully crafting by hand, because humans are still the best security architects. That said, we understand the value of AI and deploy it as an extra set of eyes at critical junctures in our Docker Hardened Image (DHI) build process. With this...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-crafted-by-humans-protected-by-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add MCP Servers to Gemini CLI with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of AI-assisted development, most developers continue to struggle with clunky web interfaces, resource-intensive IDEs, and fragmented toolchains. But what if we told you there&#39;s a combination that pairs Google&#39;s 76.3K-star Gemini CLI (in just 5 months) with Docker&#39;s innovative MCP Toolkit, quietly revolutionizing how modern AI developers work? Enter the...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-set-up-gemini-cli-with-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Multi-Agent System in 5 Minutes with cagent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Models are advancing quickly. GPT-5, Claude Sonnet, Gemini. Each release gives us more capabilities. But most real work isn’t solved by a single model. Developers are realizing they need a system of agents: different types of agents working together to accomplish more complex tasks. For example, a researcher to find information, a writer to summarize,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-a-multi-agent-system/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us in Rebooting the Docker Model Runner Community!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce that we&#39;re breathing new life into the Docker Model Runner community, and we want you to be a part of it! Our goal is to make it easier than ever for you to contribute, collaborate, and help shape the future of running AI models with Docker. From a Limited Beta to...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/rebooting-model-runner-community/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner on the new NVIDIA DGX Spark: a new paradigm for developing AI locally</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to bring NVIDIA DGX™ Spark support to Docker Model Runner. The new NVIDIA DGX Spark delivers incredible performance, and Docker Model Runner makes it accessible. With Model Runner, you can easily run and iterate on larger models right on your local machine, using the same intuitive Docker experience you already trust. In this...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/new-nvidia-dgx-spark-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100% Transparency and Five Pillars</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 21:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_10_2025/13_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to Do Hardened Images (and Container Security) Right Container security is understandably a hot topic these days, with more and more workloads running atop this mainstay of the cloud native landscape. While I might be biased because I work at Docker, it is safe to say that containers are the dominant form factor for...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/100-transparency-and-five-pillars/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add MCP Servers to Claude Code with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_10_2025/10_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI coding assistants have evolved from simple autocomplete tools into full development partners. Yet even the best of them, like Claude Code, can’t act directly on your environment. Claude Code can suggest a database query, but can&#39;t run it. It can draft a GitHub issue, but can&#39;t create it. It can write a Slack message,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/add-mcp-servers-to-claude-code-with-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRA Explained: Faster, More Efficient Fine-Tuning with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_10_2025/09_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Fine-tuning a language model doesn’t have to be daunting. In our previous post on fine-tuning models with Docker Offload and Unsloth, we walked through how to train small, local models efficiently using Docker’s familiar workflows. This time, we’re narrowing the focus. Instead of asking a model to be good at everything, we can specialize it:...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/lora-explained/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Captain’s Chair: Pradumna Saraf</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Captains are leaders from the developer community that are both experts in their field and are passionate about sharing their Docker knowledge with others. “From the Captain’s Chair” is a blog series where we get a closer look at one Captain to learn more about them and their experiences. Today, we are interviewing Pradumna...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/from-the-captains-chair-pradumna-saraf/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Local AI on Any GPU: Docker Model Runner Now with Vulkan Support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_10_2025/08_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running large language models (LLMs) on your local machine is one of the most exciting frontiers in AI development. At Docker, our goal is to make this process as simple and accessible as possible. That’s why we built Docker Model Runner, a tool to help you download and run LLMs with a single command. Until...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-vulkan-gpu-support/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
