<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop Accelerates Innovation with Faster Release Cadence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_08_2025/27_08_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce a major evolution in how we deliver Docker Desktop updates to you. Starting with Docker Desktop release 4.45.0 on 28 August we&#39;re moving to releases every two weeks, with the goal of reaching weekly releases by the end of 2025. Why We&#39;re Making This Change You&#39;ve told us you want faster...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-updates-every-two-weeks/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping an AI Tutor with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_08_2025/21_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer remembers their first docker run hello-world. The mix of excitement and wonder as that simple command pulls an image, creates a container, and displays a friendly message. But what if AI could make that experience even better? As a technical writer on Docker’s Docs team, I spend my days thinking about developer experience....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-to-build-an-ai-tutor-with-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supply Chain Paradox: When “Hardened” Images Become a Vendor Lock-in Trap</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_08_2025/20_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The market for pre-hardened container images is experiencing explosive growth as security-conscious organizations pursue the ultimate efficiency: instant security with minimal operational overhead. The value proposition is undeniably compelling—hardened images with minimal dependencies promise security &amp;quot;out of the box,&amp;quot; enabling teams to focus on building and shipping applications rather than constantly revisiting low-level configuration management....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/hardened-container-images-security-vendor-lock-in/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
