<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:35:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using MCP Servers: From Quick Tools to Multi-Agent Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers are a spec for exposing tools, models, or services to language models through a common interface. Think of them as smart adapters: they sit between a tool and the LLM, speaking a predictable protocol that lets the model interact with things like APIs, databases, and agents without needing to know...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-servers-docker-toolkit-cagent-gateway/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Dependencies Don’t Care About Your FIPS Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            FIPS compliance is a great idea that makes the entire software supply chain safer. But teams adopting FIPS-enabled container images are running into strange errors that can be challenging to debug. What they are learning is that correctness at the base image layer does not guarantee compatibility across the ecosystem. Change is complicated, and changing...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fips-dependencies-and-prebuilt-binaries/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making (Very) Small LLMs Smarter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello, I’m Philippe, and I am a Principal Solutions Architect helping customers with their usage of Docker. I started getting seriously interested in generative AI about two years ago. What interests me most is the ability to run language models (LLMs) directly on my laptop (For work, I have a MacBook Pro M2 max, but...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-small-llms-smarter/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permission-Aware RAG: End-to-End Testing with the SpiceDB Testcontainer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We use GenAI in every facet of technology now - internal knowledge bases, customer support systems, and code review bots, to name just a few use cases. And in nearly every one of these, someone eventually asks: What stops the model from returning something the user shouldn’t see?” This is a roadblock that companies building...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/rag-permission-testing-testcontainers-spicedb/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCode with Docker Model Runner for Private AI Coding</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_01_2026/15_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered coding assistants are becoming a core part of modern development workflows. At the same time, many teams are increasingly concerned about where their code goes, how it’s processed, and who has access to it. By combining OpenCode with Docker Model Runner, you can build a powerful AI-assisted coding experience while keeping full control over...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/opencode-docker-model-runner-private-ai-coding/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
