<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Launch a Chat UI Agent with Docker and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running a Chat UI Agent doesn’t have to involve a complicated setup. By combining Docker with the Vercel AI SDK, it’s possible to build and launch a conversational interface in a clean, reproducible way. Docker ensures that the environment is consistent across machines, while the Vercel AI SDK provides the tools for handling streaming responses...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/launch-chat-ui-agent-docker-vercel-ai-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Trial – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First steps: Run your first secure, production-ready image Container base images form the foundation of your application security. When those foundations contain vulnerabilities, every service built on top inherits the same risk. Docker Hardened Images addresses this at the source. These are continuously-maintained, minimal base images designed for security: stripped of unnecessary packages, patched proactively,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-trial-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Great AI Productivity Divide: Why Are Some Developers 5x Faster?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered developer tools claim to boost your productivity, doing everything from intelligent auto-complete to (https://openai.com/index/introducing-codex/). But the productivity gains users report have been something of a mixed bag. Some groups claim to get 3-5x (or more), productivity boosts, while other devs claim to get no benefit at all—or even losses of up to 19%. I...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-productivity-divide-developers-5x-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cagent Comes to Docker Desktop with Built-In IDE Support through ACP</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop now includes cagent bundled out of the box. This means developers can start building AI agents without a separate installation step. For those unfamiliar with cagent: it’s Docker’s open-source tool that lets you build AI agents using YAML configuration files instead of writing code. You define the agent’s behavior and tools, and cagent...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/cagent-comes-to-docker-desktop-with-built-in-ide-support-through-acp/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Horror Stories: The WhatsApp Data Exfiltration Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_11_2025/13_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 5 of our MCP Horror Stories series, where we examine real-world security incidents that highlight the critical vulnerabilities threatening AI infrastructure and demonstrate how Docker’s comprehensive AI security platform provides protection against these threats. Model Context Protocol (MCP) promises seamless integration between AI agents and communication platforms like WhatsApp, enabling automated message...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-horror-stories-whatsapp-data-exfiltration-issue/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.50: Indispensable for Daily Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/12_11_2025/12_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.50 represents a major leap forward in how development teams build, secure, and ship software. Across the last several releases, we&#39;ve delivered meaningful improvements that directly address the challenges you face every day: faster debugging workflows, enterprise-grade security controls that don&#39;t get in your way, and seamless AI integration that makes modern development...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-50/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Engine v29: Foundational Updates for the Future</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post is for Linux users running Docker Engine (Community Edition) directly on their hosts. Docker Desktop users don’t need to take any action — Engine updates are included automatically in future Desktop releases. Docker Engine v29 is a foundational release that sets the stage for the future of the Docker platform. While it may...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-engine-version-29/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Remote MCP Servers with OAuth in Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In just a year, the Model Context Protocol (MCP) has become the standard for connecting AI agents to tools and external systems. The Docker MCP Catalog now hosts hundreds of containerized local MCP servers, enabling developers to quickly experiment and prototype locally. We have now added support for remote MCP servers to the Docker MCP...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/connect-to-remote-mcp-servers-with-oauth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
