<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publishing AI models to Docker Hub</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_06_2025/11_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first released Docker Model Runner, it came with built-in support for running AI models published and maintained by Docker on Docker Hub. This made it simple to pull a model like llama3.2 or gemma3 and start using it locally with familiar Docker-style commands. Model Runner now supports three new commands: tag, push, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/publish-ai-models-on-docker-hub/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.42: Native IPv6, Built-In MCP, and Better Model Packaging</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 16:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_06_2025/10_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.42 introduces powerful new capabilities that enhance network flexibility, improve security, and deepen AI toolchain integration, all while reducing setup friction. With native IPv6 support, a fully integrated MCP Toolkit, and major upgrades to Docker Model Runner and our AI agent Gordon, this release continues our commitment to helping developers move faster, ship...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-42-native-ipv6-built-in-mcp-and-better-model-packaging/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Management for Docker Desktop now generally available in the Admin Console</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that Settings Management for Docker Desktop is now Generally Available! Settings Management can be configured in the Admin Console for customers with a Docker Business subscription. After a successful Early Access period, this powerful administrative solution has been enhanced with new compliance reporting capabilities, completing our vision for centralized Docker Desktop...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/settings-management-for-docker-desktop-now-generally-available-in-the-admin-console/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
