<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; E2B: Building the Future of Trusted AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trusted Software Starts Here The era of agents is here. Some teams are experimenting, others are just getting started, and a few are already running agents in production. But one challenge stands out: trust. Trust that your agents will act securely. Over 20 million developers already rely on Docker to build and ship software safely...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-e2b-building-the-future-of-trusted-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Offload: Automating Everyday Workflows with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every developer eventually hits a wall with their local machine. Maybe it’s training an AI model that drains your CPU, compiling a massive codebase that makes your fan sound like a jet engine, or simply trying to run GPU workloads on a laptop that doesn’t have one. The result is the same: slow builds, limited...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/getting-started-docker-offload/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a Richer ”docker model run” Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The command line is where developers live and breathe. A powerful and intuitive CLI can make the difference between a frustrating task and a joyful one. That’s why we’re excited to announce a major upgrade to the interactive chat experience in Docker Model Runner, our tool for running AI workloads locally. We&#39;ve rolled out a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-run-prompt/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner Meets Open WebUI: A Simpler Way to Run Local AI Models</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hi, I’m Sergei Shitikov - a Docker Captain and Lead Software Engineer living in Berlin. I&#39;m focused on DevOps, developer experience, open source, and local AI tools. I created this extension to make it easier for anyone - even without a technical background - to get started with local LLMs using Docker Model Runner and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/open-webui-docker-desktop-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add MCP Servers to OpenAI’s Codex with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI assistants are changing how we write code, but their true power is unleashed when they can interact with specialized, high-precision tools. OpenAI&#39;s Codex is a formidable coding partner, but what happens when you connect it directly to your running infrastructure? Enter the Docker MCP Toolkit. The Model Context Protocol (MCP) Toolkit acts as a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/connect-codex-to-mcp-servers-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Still Use jQuery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            jQuery is a household name among web developers who have been around the block. Initially released in 2006, it took the web development world by storm with its easy and intuitive syntax for navigating a document, selecting DOM elements, handling events, and making AJAX requests. At its peak in 2015, jQuery featured on 62.7 percent...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-i-still-use-jquery-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Docker Builds with Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building Docker images is an important component of the software delivery pipeline for modern applications. It’s how we package our apps and services so that they can be distributed to others and deployed to production. While the Dockerfile has long been the standard for defining container images, it is known to be challenging to make...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/debug-docker-builds-with-visual-studio-code/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
