<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:57:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.43: Expanded Model Runner, Reimagined MCP Catalog, MCP Server Submissions, and Smarter Gordon</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 14:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_07_2025/03_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.43 just rolled out a set of powerful updates that simplify how developers run, manage, and secure AI models and MCP tools. Model Runner now includes better model management, expanded OpenAI API compatibility, and fine-grained controls over runtime behavior. The improved MCP Catalog makes it easier to discover and use MCP servers, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-desktop-4-43/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gordon to Containerize Your Apps and Work with Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            These days, almost every tech company is looking for ways to integrate AI into their apps and workflows, and Docker is no exception. They&#39;ve been rolling out some impressive AI capabilities across their products. This is my first post as a Docker Captain and in this post, I want to shine a spotlight on a...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/containerize-your-apps-with-ask-gordon/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker State of App Dev: Dev Ex &amp; Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_07_2025/02_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Report: What’s helping devs thrive — and what’s still holding them back? A look at how culture, tooling, and habits are shaping the developer experience today, per Docker’s 2025 State of Application Development Survey. Great culture, better tools — but developers often still feel stuck. From pull requests stuck in review to tasks without clear...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-state-of-app-dev-dev-ex-productivity/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Docker MCP Catalog: the Secure Way to Discover and Run MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_07_2025/01_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) ecosystem is exploding. In just weeks, our Docker MCP Catalog has surpassed 1 million pulls, validating that developers are hungry for a secure way to run MCP servers. Today, we&#39;re excited to share major updates to the Docker MCP Catalog, including enhanced discovery features and our new open submission process....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-catalog-secure-way-to-discover-and-run-mcp-servers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool Calling with Local LLMs: A Practical Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_06_2025/30_06_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Which local model should I use for tool calling? When building GenAI and agentic applications, one of the most pressing and persistent questions is: “Which local model should I use for tool calling?” We kept hearing again and again, from colleagues within Docker and the developer community, ever since we started working on Docker Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/local-llm-tool-calling-a-practical-evaluation/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Easy Private AI Assistant with Goose and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_06_2025/27_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Goose is an innovative CLI assistant designed to automate development tasks using AI models. Docker Model Runner simplifies deploying AI models locally with Docker. Combining these technologies creates a powerful local environment with advanced AI assistance, ideal for coding and automation. Looking for a seamless way to run AI-powered development tasks locally without compromising on...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-an-ai-assistant-with-goose-and-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
