<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Security Doesn’t Have to Hurt</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you ever wish security would stop blocking the tools you need to do your job? Surprise: your security team wants the same. There you are, just trying to get your work done, when… You need an AI to translate documentation, but all the AI services are blocked by a security web monitoring tool. You...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-shadow-it-collaboration/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Bones: A Pirate-Voiced Halloween Chatbot Powered by Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            My name is Mike Coleman, a staff solution architect at Docker. This year I decided to turn a Home Depot animatronic skeleton into an AI-powered, live, interactive Halloween chatbot. The result: kids walk up to Mr. Bones, a spooky skeleton in my yard, ask it questions, and it answers back — in full pirate voice...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/talking-skeleton-docker-llm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>theCUBE Research economic validation of Docker’s development platform</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker&#39;s impact on agentic AI, security, developer productivity, costs, ROI. An independent study by theCUBE Research. To investigate Docker&#39;s impact on developer productivity, software supply chain security, agentic AI development, cost savings, and ROI, theCUBE Research asked nearly 400 enterprise IT &amp;amp; AppDev leaders from medium to large global enterprises. The industry context is that...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/thecube-research-economic-validation-of-docker-development-platform/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect MCP Servers to Claude Desktop with Docker MCP Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What if you could turn Claude from a conversational assistant into a development partner that actually does things—safely, securely, and without touching your local machine? If you&#39;ve been exploring Claude Desktop and wondering how to connect it with real developer tools, Docker MCP Toolkit is the missing piece you&#39;ve been looking for. Here&#39;s the reality:...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/connect-mcp-servers-to-claude-desktop-with-mcp-toolkit/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Hub Incident Report – October 20, 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 23:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker experienced significant disruptions due to a widespread outage in AWS’s US-East-1 region on October 20, 2025. Developers worldwide rely on Docker as part of their daily workflow, and we regret the disruption this caused. In this post, we want to provide transparency about what happened, what we have learned, and how we are strengthening...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hub-incident-report-october-20-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Org, Your Tools: Building a Custom MCP Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 19:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I’m Mike Coleman, a staff solutions architect at Docker. In this role, I spend a lot of time talking to enterprise customers about AI adoption. One thing I hear over and over again is that these companies want to ensure appropriate guardrails are in place when it comes to deploying AI tooling. For instance, many...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-custom-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Guide to the Galaxy: MCP Toolkit and Gateway, Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is an abridged version of the interview we had in AI Guide to the Galaxy, where host Oleg Šelajev spoke with Jim Clark, Principal Software Engineer at Docker, to unpack Docker’s MCP Toolkit and MCP Gateway. TL;DR What they are: The MCP Toolkit helps you discover, run, and manage MCP servers; the MCP Gateway...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-gateway-explained/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why More People Are Taking Control of Their Digital Lives with Self-Hosted Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remember when owning software meant you bought a CD, installed it, and it was yours until your computer died? Even if you got a new computer, you could install that same software on the new one. Only “serious” software packages had strict licensing restrictions. These days, most of our tools live in the cloud, guarded...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/self-hosted-alternatives-control-your-data/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
