<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Shell Scripts to Science Agents: How AI Agents Are Transforming Research Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It’s 2 AM in a lab somewhere. A researcher has three terminals open, a half-written Jupyter notebook on one screen, an Excel sheet filled with sample IDs on another, and a half-eaten snack next to shell commands. They’re juggling scripts to run a protein folding model, parsing CSVs from the last experiment, searching for literature,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-science-agents-research-workflows/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Local Models with Docker Offload and Unsloth</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I&#39;ve been experimenting with local models for a while now, and the progress in making them accessible has been exciting. Initial experiences are often fantastic, many models, like Gemma 3 270M, are lightweight enough to run on common hardware. This potential for broad deployment is a major draw. However, as I&#39;ve tried to build meaningful,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/fine-tuning-models-with-offload-and-unsloth/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Docker Hardened Images: Secure Helm Charts for Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Development teams are under growing pressure to secure their software supply chains. Teams need trusted images, streamlined deployments, and compliance-ready tooling from partners they can rely on long term. Our customers have made it clear that they’re not just looking for one-off vendors. They’re looking for true security partners across development and deployment. That’s why...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-helm-charts-beta/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Toolkit: MCP Servers That Just Work</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_09_2025/29_09_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we want to highlight Docker MCP Toolkit, a free feature in Docker Desktop that gives you access to more than 200 MCP servers. It’s the easiest and most secure way to run MCP servers locally for your AI agents and workflows. The MCP toolkit allows you to isolate MCP servers in containers, securely configure...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/mcp-toolkit-mcp-servers-that-just-work/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
