<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Docker Hardened Images Patches Vulnerabilities in 24 hours</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 19, 2025, the Golang project published two Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs) affecting the widely-used golang.org/x/crypto/ssh package. While neither vulnerability received a critical CVSS score, both presented real risks to applications using SSH functionality in Go-based containers. CVE-2025-58181 affects SSH servers parsing GSSAPI authentication requests. The vulnerability allows attackers to trigger unbounded memory...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/how-docker-hardened-images-patch-cves-in-24-hours/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Hype: How to Use AI to Actually Increase Your Productivity as a Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I started incorporating AI tools into my workflow, I was first frustrated. I didn&#39;t get the 5x or 10x gains others raved about on social. In fact, it slowed me down. But I persisted. Partly because I see it as my professional duty as a software engineer to be as productive as possible, partly...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-developer-productivity-workflow/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Model Runner Integrates vLLM for High-Throughput Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Expanding Docker Model Runner’s Capabilities Today, we’re excited to announce that Docker Model Runner now integrates the vLLM inference engine and safetensors models, unlocking high-throughput AI inference with the same Docker tooling you already use. When we first introduced Docker Model Runner, our goal was to make it simple for developers to run and experiment...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-model-runner-integrates-vllm/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I joined Docker: security at the center of the software supply chain</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mark Lechner, Docker’s CISO, shares his vision for a future where Docker not only powers the software supply chain, but actively safeguards it. Cybersecurity has reached a turning point. The most significant threats no longer exploit isolated systems; they move through the connections between them. The modern attack surface includes every dependency, every container, and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/why-i-joined-docker-security-at-the-center-of-the-software-supply-chain/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Must-Have MCP Servers (and How to Use Them)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The era of AI agents has arrived, and with it, a new standard for how they connect to tools: the Model Context Protocol (MCP). MCP unlocks powerful, flexible workflows by letting agents tap into external tools and systems. But with thousands of MCP servers (including remote ones) now available, it’s easy to ask: Where do...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/top-mcp-servers-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; Unsloth: Build Custom Models, Faster</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building and Running Custom Models Is Still Hard Running AI models locally is still hard. Even as open-source LLMs grow more capable, actually getting them to run on your machine, with the right dependencies, remains slow, fragile, and inconsistent. There’s two sides to this challenge: Model creation and optimization: making fine-tuning and quantization efficient. Model...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-unsloth-build-custom-models-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch a Chat UI Agent with Docker and the Vercel AI SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Running a Chat UI Agent doesn’t have to involve a complicated setup. By combining Docker with the Vercel AI SDK, it’s possible to build and launch a conversational interface in a clean, reproducible way. Docker ensures that the environment is consistent across machines, while the Vercel AI SDK provides the tools for handling streaming responses...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/launch-chat-ui-agent-docker-vercel-ai-sdk/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Most of Your Docker Hardened Images Trial – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            First steps: Run your first secure, production-ready image Container base images form the foundation of your application security. When those foundations contain vulnerabilities, every service built on top inherits the same risk. Docker Hardened Images addresses this at the source. These are continuously-maintained, minimal base images designed for security: stripped of unnecessary packages, patched proactively,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/making-the-most-of-your-docker-hardened-images-trial-part-1/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Great AI Productivity Divide: Why Are Some Developers 5x Faster?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_11_2025/14_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered developer tools claim to boost your productivity, doing everything from intelligent auto-complete to (https://openai.com/index/introducing-codex/). But the productivity gains users report have been something of a mixed bag. Some groups claim to get 3-5x (or more), productivity boosts, while other devs claim to get no benefit at all—or even losses of up to 19%. I...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/ai-productivity-divide-developers-5x-faster/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
