<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 Recap: The Year Software Development Changed Shape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_12_2025/20_12_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            2025 was the year software teams stopped optimizing models and started optimizing systems. By December, a few truths were impossible to ignore. 1. Developer Productivity Became the Real Competitive Advantage By mid-year, every major AI lab had cleared the “good enough reasoning” bar. With model quality converging, the differentiator was no longer raw intelligence. It...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2025-recap-the-year-software-development-changed-shape/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Captain’s Chair: Igor Aleksandrov</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Captains are leaders from the developer community that are both experts in their field and are passionate about sharing their Docker knowledge with others. “From the Captain’s Chair” is a blog series where we get a closer look at one Captain to learn more about them and their experiences. Today we are interviewing Igor...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/from-the-captains-chair-igor-aleksandrov/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Hardened Images: Security Independently Validated by SRLabs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_12_2025/19_12_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Earlier this week, we took a major step forward for the industry. Docker Hardened Images (DHI) is now available at no cost, bringing secure-by-default development to every team, everywhere. Anyone can now start from a secure, minimal, production-ready foundation from the first pull, without a subscription. With that decision comes a responsibility: if Docker Hardened Images become...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-hardened-images-security-independently-validated-by-srlabs/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
