<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:22:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Error Handling: How Docker Desktop 4.29 Aims to Simplify Developer Challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the Docker Desktop 4.29 release, we&#39;ve embarked on an ambitious journey to elevate the user experience by fundamentally redefining error management. Learn more about this intuitive new prompt that sheds light on the mysterious seas of error messages.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/next-level-error-handling/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Desktop 4.29: Docker Socket Mount Permissions in ECI, Advanced Error Management, Moby 26, and New Beta Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_04_2024/10_04_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Desktop 4.29 introduces enhancements to secure and streamline the development process and to improve error management and workflow efficiency. With the integration of Enhanced Container Isolation (ECI) with Docker socket mount permissions, the debut of Moby 26 within Docker Desktop, and exciting features such as Docker Compose enhancements via synchronized file shares reaching Beta, we&#39;re equipping developers with the essential resources to tackle the complexities of modern development head-on.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with the latest updates for Dockerfile syntax (v1.7.0)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2024/09_04_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 15:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_04_2024/09_04_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dockerfiles are fundamental tools for developers working with Docker, serving as a blueprint for creating Docker images. Learn about new Dockerfile (v1.7.0) capabilities and how you can leverage them in your projects to further optimize your Docker workflows.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/new-dockerfile-capabilities-v1-7-0/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian’s Dedication to Security: A Robust Foundation for Docker Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We outline how and why Debian operates as a secure basis for development and makes a good choice for Docker Official Images.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/debian-for-docker-developers/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Misconceptions to Mastery: Enhancing Security and Transparency with Docker Official Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 14:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_04_2024/04_04_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Official Images are an important component of Docker&#39;s commitment to the security of both the software supply chain and open source software. We address three common misconceptions about Docker Official Images and outline seven ways they help secure the software supply chain.
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/enhancing-security-and-transparency-with-docker-official-images/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
