<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:21:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Securing the Docker MCP Catalog: Commit Pinning, Agentic Auditing, and Publisher Trust Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_12_2025/03_12_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Trust is the most important consideration when you connect AI assistants to real tools. While MCP containerization provides strong isolation and limits the blast radius of malfunctioning or compromised servers, we’re continuously strengthening trust and security across the Docker MCP solutions to further reduce exposure to malicious code. As the MCP ecosystem scales from hundreds...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/enhancing-mcp-trust-with-the-docker-mcp-catalog/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI agents shouldn’t be hard. According to theCUBE Research, Docker makes it easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_12_2025/02_12_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            For most developers, getting started with AI is still too complicated. Different models, tools, and platforms don’t always play nicely together. But with Docker, that’s changing fast. Docker is emerging as essential infrastructure for standardized, portable, and scalable AI environments. By bringing composability, simplicity, and GPU accessibility to the agentic era, Docker is helping developers...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/building-ai-agents-shouldnt-be-hard-according-to-thecube-research-docker-makes-it-easy/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Embedding Models and Unlock Semantic Search with Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_12_2025/01_12_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings have become the backbone of many modern AI applications. From semantic search to retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and intelligent recommendation systems, embedding models enable systems to understand the meaning behind text, code, or documents, not just the literal words. But generating embeddings comes with trade-offs. Using a hosted API for embedding generation often results in...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/run-embedding-models-for-semantic-search/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Want Microservices, But Do You Really Need Them?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_11_2025/28_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you know who managed to cut costs by a staggering 90% by abandoning microservices for a monolith in May 2023? Not a cash-strapped startup or an indie project—Amazon itself, for its Prime Video service. The same AWS that earns billions every year by selling microservices infrastructure admitted that, sometimes, a good old monolith wins. ...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/do-you-really-need-microservices/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security that strengthens the ecosystem: Docker’s upstream approach to CVE-2025-12735</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_11_2025/26_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On November 24, 2025, Docker Hardened Images resolved CVE-2025-12735 in the Kibana project, which is the visualization and user interface layer for Elasticsearch. This CVE is a critical remote code execution vulnerability that scored 9.8 on the CVSS scale. While images from other hardened image vendors were still carrying the vulnerability, Docker’s security team and...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/security-that-strengthens-the-ecosystem-dockers-upstream-approach-to-cve-2025-12735/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
