<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 11:59:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/docker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a GenAI App With Java Using Spring AI and Docker Model Runner</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 11:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When thinking about starting a Generative AI (GenAI) project, you might assume that Python is required to get started in this new space. However, if you’re already a Java developer, there’s no need to learn a new language. The Java ecosystem offers robust tools and libraries that make building GenAI applications both accessible and productive....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-genai-app-with-java-spring-ai-docker-model-runner/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 17:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Executive summary The 2025 Docker State of Application Development Report offers an ultra high-resolution view of today’s fast-evolving dev landscape. Drawing insights from over 4,500 developers, engineers, and tech leaders — three times more users than last year — the survey explores tools, workflows, pain points, and industry trends. In this our third report, key...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/2025-docker-state-of-app-dev/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Brings Compose to the Agent Era: Building AI Agents is Now Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 10:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_07_2025/10_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents are the future, and if you haven’t already started building agents, you probably will soon. Across industries and use cases, agents can act on our behalf, and offload repetitive work, because they can act on our behalf with judgment and context. But while agentic development is moving fast, today it’s tedious, hard, and not...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/build-ai-agents-with-docker-compose/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compose your way with Provider services!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the release of Docker Compose v2.36.0, we&#39;re excited to introduce a powerful new feature: provider services. This extension point opens up Docker Compose to interact not only with containers but also with any kind of external system, all while keeping the familiar Compose file at the center of the workflow. In this blog post,...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-with-provider-services/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker MCP Gateway: Open Source, Secure Infrastructure for Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_07_2025/09_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Since releasing the Docker MCP Toolkit, we’ve seen strong community adoption, including steady growth in MCP server usage and over 1 million pulls from the Docker MCP Catalog. With the community, we’re laying the groundwork by standardizing how developers define, run, and share agent-based workloads with Docker Compose. Now, we’re expanding on that foundation with...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-mcp-gateway-secure-infrastructure-for-agentic-ai/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Docker Hub MCP Server: A New Way to Discover, Inspect, and Manage Container Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/08_07_2025/08_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Docker Hub has become an essential resource for developers worldwide, serving 11 billion monthly image downloads and hosting over 14 million container images. As agentic AI proliferates, we&#39;re seeing a significant shift in how developers work. More and more developers are leveraging MCP (Model Context Protocol) servers to power their AI agents and automated workflows....
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/introducing-docker-hub-mcp-server/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Dev to Deploy: Compose as the Spine of the Application Lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_07_2025/07_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Nobody wants a spineless application development process. What do I mean by this? The spine is the backbone that supports and provides nerve channels for the human body. Without it, we would be floppy, weaker, and would struggle to understand how our extremities were behaving. A slightly tortured analogy, but consider the application lifecycle of...
Link to article: https://www.docker.com/blog/docker-compose-powering-the-full-app-lifecycle/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
