<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dotnettips.wordpress.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/dotnettips.wordpress.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dotnettips.wordpress.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/dotnettips.wordpress.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Day the Software Community Died: Let’s Stop Coding in Isolation and Start Creating Community—And Software—People Truly Love</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author reflects on the vital role of the software community in shaping their career as an engineer, emphasizing its decline post-COVID-19. They highlight the diminishing local user groups and conferences, attributing this to a lack of appreciation from younger developers and reduced corporate support, particularly from Microsoft. A call to action urges developers to engage, companies to invest, and veterans to mentor, reinforcing the importance of community in fostering quality software.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Add Thread-Safety with ConcurrentHashSet from Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2025/13_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/13_07_2025/13_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The HashSet in .NET is efficient for storing unique elements but is not thread-safe. To overcome this issue, ConcurrentHashSet was created, offering thread-safe operations while maintaining HashSet behavior. It features various constructors, supports custom comparers, and includes methods for adding, removing, and checking elements. Available via NuGet.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/13/boost-your-net-projects-add-thread-safety-with-concurrenthashset-from-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Rocks ØREDEV DEVELOPERS CONFERENCE 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_07_2025/11_07_2025_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            dotNetDave will speak at the Øredev Developers Conference in Malmö, Denmark, from November 5-7, 2025. His session focuses on optimizing .NET code performance, sharing techniques to improve execution speed by up to 98%. Attendees will learn about effective memory management, enhancing application efficiency while gaining practical insights from his book series.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/07/11/dotnetdave-rocks-oredev-developers-conference-2025/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
