<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dotnettips.wordpress.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/dotnettips.wordpress.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dotnettips.wordpress.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/dotnettips.wordpress.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding Extension Properties with State to Types, (Sort of) In Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_06_2025/06_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author discusses the upcoming .NET 10 release and its new Extension Members feature, particularly focusing on extension properties. Despite direct support lacking, a workaround using ConditionalWeakTable enables tracking exception logging states via extension methods. The author integrates this approach into Spargine, encouraging others to try it for managing exceptions in their code.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/06/adding-extension-properties-to-types-sort-of-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Mastering Unit Testing with Spargine’s UnitTester Class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The UnitTester class in the DotNetTips.Spargine.Tester assembly aids developers in logging unit test data efficiently. It features methods like PropertiesToString, PrintToDebug, and SaveToFile, which facilitate outputting results to the Debug panel or saving them to files. This tool enhances the debugging and reporting processes in .NET unit testing.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/04/boost-your-net-projects-mastering-unit-testing-with-spargines-unittester-class/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotNetDave Says… Soft Skills at Conferences Matter—A Lot!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The author reflects on two decades of speaking engagements, emphasizing the importance of soft skills in software engineering over mere technical knowledge. They argue that communication, empathy, and collaboration are crucial for career growth. While major conferences often overlook these topics, community-driven events showcase their value, urging attendees to advocate for more sessions on soft skills.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/02/dotnetdave-says-soft-skills-at-conferences-matter-a-lot/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Untapped Power of Veteran Engineers: Why Companies Are Overlooking Their Most Valuable Assets – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The article emphasizes the critical value of veteran software engineers, highlighting their extensive experience, technical expertise, and leadership in innovation. It addresses age bias in the tech industry, advocating for the recognition and utilization of senior talent. Companies that embrace this perspective can significantly enhance their performance and resilience.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/01/the-untapped-power-of-veteran-engineers-why-companies-are-overlooking-their-most-valuable-assets-part-2/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost Your .NET Projects: Enhance Your Workflow with AssemblyHelper in Spargine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_06_2025/01_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AssemblyHelper class from the DotNetTips.Spargine.Core assembly is an essential tool for .NET developers, offering numerous high-performance methods to manage assemblies efficiently. It simplifies tasks like loading, locating, and inspecting assemblies, enhancing productivity by reducing complexity in large projects. Incorporate AssemblyHelper into your toolkit for improved development processes.
Link to article: https://dotnettips.wordpress.com/2025/06/01/boost-your-net-projects-enhance-your-workflow-with-assemblyhelper-in-spargine/ 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
