<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:00:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Learning Paths Now Available on Pluralsight for VS Subscribers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_07_2025/22_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve been thrilled to see so many of you jump back into your Pluralsight benefit after our April 3rd announcement about extended access. Your enthusiasm for learning and leveling up with Visual Studio inspires us every day. If you
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/vss-pluralsight-2025-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java OpenJDK July 2025 Patch &amp; Security Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 22:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java customers! We are happy to announce the latest July 2025 patch &amp;amp; security update release for the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK. Download and install the binaries today. OpenJDK 21.0.8 OpenJDK 17.0.16 OpenJDK 11.0.28 Check our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-openjdk-july-2025-patch-security-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask Mode vs Agent Mode - Choosing the Right Copilot Experience for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a .NET developer, productivity and problem-solving are at the heart of your workflow. GitHub Copilot Chat offers two powerful modes, Ask Mode and Agent Mode, that can dramatically accelerate your development, but knowing when to use each is essential to getting the most out of this tool. In this post, we’ll break down the differences,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/ask-mode-vs-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Smarter with the Microsoft 365 Agents Toolkit MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI agents become central to how we build and interact with modern productivity apps, developers need tools that are flexible, standard-based, and deeply integrated with AI. That’s where the Microsoft 365 Agents Toolkit MCP Server
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-smarter-with-the-microsoft-365-agents-toolkit-mcp-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: From Dev to Prod with One Click</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how to implement a &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; pattern using Azure Developer CLI (azd) that provisions environment-specific infrastructure and promotes applications from dev to prod with t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-from-dev-to-prod-with-one-click 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing for Go applications using Testcontainers and containerized databases</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 15:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Integration testing has always presented a fundamental challenge: how do you test your application against real dependencies without the complexity of managing external services? Traditional approaches often involve either mocking dependencies (which can miss integration issues) or maintaining separate test environments (which can be expensive
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/integration-testing-for-go-applications-using-testcontainers-and-containerized-databases 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens if C&#43;&#43;/WinRT is unable to resume execution on a dispatcher thread?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The C++/WinRT library provides the winrt::resume_foreground() function for resuming a coroutine on the foreground thread of a dispatcher. It supports three types of dispatchers: Windows.UI.Core.CoreDispatcher, Windows.System.DispatcherQueue, Micros
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250721-00/?p=111396 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code CMake Tools Extension 1.21 Release: Multi-root improvements, CMake Presets v10, and more…</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the latest 1.21 release of the CMake Tools extension for Visual Studio Code. This update brings a host of new updates, including addressing one of our top-voted issues for multi-root improvements and adding
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/visual-studio-code-cmake-tools-extension-1-21-release-multi-root-improvements-cmake-presets-v10-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Building Multi-Agent Solutions with Semantic Kernel and A2A Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 08:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_07_2025/21_07_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the rapidly evolving landscape of AI application development, the ability to orchestrate multiple intelligent agents has become crucial for building sophisticated, enterprise-grade solutions. While individual AI agents excel at specific tasks, complex business scenarios often require coordination between specialized agents running on differ
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-building-multi-agent-solutions-with-semantic-kernel-and-a2a-protocol 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the invalid instruction exception on an instruction that should never have executed</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The image processing folks added specialized AVX2 versions of their code, but found that it was crashing with an illegal instruction exception. The code went something like this: void SwizzleAVX2(uint32_t* source, uint32_t* destination, uint32_t count) { ⟦ do stuff using AVX-only instructions ⟧ ⟦ such as _mm256_cv
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250718-00/?p=111390 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Model Promotion with dstoolkit-mlops-v2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_07_2025/18_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In a recent engagement, our team of Data Scientists and Software Engineers, developed a series of custom AI models to meet our customer&#39;s specific use case. While doing so, consideration was given to how best to allow Data Scientists the freedom to quickly experiment and iterate on model development, while also incorpora
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/ai-model-promotion-with-dstoolkit-v2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build reliable Go applications: Configuring Azure Cosmos DB Go SDK for real-world scenarios</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When building applications that interact with databases, developers frequently encounter scenarios where default SDK configurations don&#39;t align with their specific operational requirements. They need to customize SDK behavior to address real-world challenges like network instability, performance bottlenecks, debugging complexity, monitoring re
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/build-reliable-go-applications-configuring-azure-cosmos-db-go-sdk-for-real-world-scenarios 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If the Window Runtime PropertyValue is for boxing non-inspectables, why is there a PropertyValue.CreateInspectable?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Windows Runtime provides a class named Property­Value which is a helper class for boxing non-inspectables. &amp;quot;Boxing&amp;quot; means taking a value type and wrapping inside an object so it can be used as an object type, and in the Windows Runtime, &amp;quot;objects&amp;quot; are represented by the IInspectable interface. There are
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250717-00/?p=111388 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command GitHub&#39;s Coding Agent from VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_07_2025/17_07_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            VS Code&#39;s integration with GitHub Copilot Coding Agent allows you to delegate tasks to the agent and let it handle them in the background. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/command-github&#39;s-coding-agent-from-vs-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Microsoft MCP Servers to Accelerate Your Development Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 19:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been talking a lot about the Model Context Protocol (MCP) lately, including recent blog posts and sessions at Microsoft Build. In this post, I&#39;d like to share some top tips for how you can use MCP servers we&#39;ve been building to improve yo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//10-microsoft-mcp-servers-to-accelerate-your-development-workflow 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring your own agents into Microsoft 365 Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Custom Engine Agents now generally available—build and integrate your own AI into the flow of work Microsoft 365 Copilot is redefining how people interact with AI—embedding it directly into the flow of work as the intuitive, natural interface for agents: the ‘UI for AI’ As Copilot becomes the interface for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/bring-your-own-agents-into-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and LangChain4j: A Partnership for Secure, Enterprise-Grade Java AI Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsoft-and-langchain4j-a-partnership-for-secure-enterprise-grade-java-ai-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamental Failure-Mode Theorem: Systems lie about their proper functioning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_07_2025/16_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I have on occasion referred to Le Chatelier&#39;s Principle for complex systems, as presented by John Gall in the book Systemantics: &amp;quot;Every complex system r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250716-00/?p=111383 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your First MCP Server with .NET and Publishing to NuGet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Want to extend AI assistants with custom capabilities? In this post, we&#39;ll show you how to build a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server using .NET 10 and publish it to NuGet — making your AI tools discoverable and reusable by the entire .NET community. We&#39;ll also show you some new features we&#39;ve added to .NET 10 and NuGet to support this, and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mcp-server-dotnet-nuget-quickstart 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Warning Suppressions in Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Code Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft C++ Code Analysis is a powerful static analysis tool integrated into Visual Studio that helps you identify and fix potential issues in your C++ code. Large projects require effective management of analysis warnings to maintain code quality and you sometimes need to suppress warnings, but must do so in a clear and auditable way.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/updates-to-warning-suppressions-in-microsoft-c-code-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Platform API and SDKs: From UX-First to API-First</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Historically, Power Platform has empowered administrators through the Power Platform Admin Center (PPAC). This UX-first experience offered a seamless, intuitive interface for managing environments, automating everyday tasks, and discovering new capabilities within the platform. Today, we’re taking a bold step forward. We’re tran
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/power-platform-api-and-sdks-from-ux-first-to-api-first 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension concerns when replacing the OS disk</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One confusing area regarding extensions on Azure VMs is - what happens when the OS disk is swapped out? Well, in that case the extensions will run again. Is this the desired behavior? Well, we don&#39;t know. There are many types of extensions. Some handle monitoring and security, so those you&#39;ll probably want to keep. Some install applications
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-vm-runtime/extension-concerns-when-replacing-the-os-disk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 6 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the sixth preview release of .NET 10 with enhancements across the .NET Runtime, SDK, libraries, C#, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, .NET MAUI, and more. Check out the full release notes linked below and get started today. [cta-button align=&amp;quot;center&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;Download .NET 10 Preview 6&amp;quot; url=&amp;quot;https://get.d
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-6 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perhaps not a recommended usage for an emergency power outlet</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_07_2025/15_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It is not uncommon for Microsoft employees who are aficionados of arcade video games to set up a unit in free play mode in a public space for anyone to play. For example, the Habitrail in the Building 16-18 complex
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250715-00/?p=111381 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
