<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:57:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to build ChatGPT-like enterprise search on your own data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2024/25_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you find yourself drowning in company documentation, spending hours searching through SharePoint, knowledge bases, and contract repositories for one specific piece of information? You’re not alone. Organizations now have plenty of information – the challenge lies in finding the right information when you need it. We have built a packaged GitHub template that helps […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-build-chatgpt-like-enterprise-search-on-your-own-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (November 2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2024/23_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 19:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_11_2024/23_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2024.11.16 registry release, 2024-11-12 tool release, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout November. This release includes a command line option to force vcpkg to use classic mode even if a manifest file is found along with bug fixes. Some […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-november-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.7</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.7! If you’re not familiar with TypeScript, it’s a language that builds on JavaScript by adding syntax for type declarations and annotations. This syntax can be used by the TypeScript compiler to type-check our code, and it can also be erased to emit clean, idiomatic JavaScript […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-7 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;, how can I make a default parameter be the this pointer of the caller?, revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Expanding on the previous pattern.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241122-00/?p=110560 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 GitHub Copilot Features in Visual Studio from Microsoft Ignite 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_11_2024/22_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At this year’s Microsoft Ignite, it was truly exciting to see Scott, Dalia, and Jessie demo some of the most innovative features of GitHub Copilot that are transforming the developer experience in Visual Studio. From the breakout session, we highlighted five standout features that are pushing productivity to the next level. Whether you’re working on […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/top-5-github-copilot-features-in-visual-studio-from-microsoft-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Intelligent Application Templates in the Azure AI Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is no longer a futuristic concept—it’s transforming how developers build and innovate applications today. To help Java developers harness the full potential of AI, Microsoft’s Azure AI App Templates gallery offers a growing collection of AI-powered application templates. These templates are designed to streamline development, showcase integration patterns, and accelerate your AI […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-intelligent-application-templates-in-the-azure-ai-gallery 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the GA Release of Filters for .NET and Python in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 21:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the General Availability (GA) release of Filters for our .NET and Python Semantic Kernel! This vital enhancement strengthens the control and visibility developers have when running functions, ensuring responsible AI practices are instilled from the ground up. Filters not only improve security but also contribute to building enterprise-ready solutions that […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-the-ga-release-of-filters-for-net-and-python-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Announcing the Microsoft Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Connector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 19:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to feature the Elastic team to share more about their Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch connector. Read the entire announcement here. I’ll turn it over to Srikanth Manvi to dive into it. In collaboration with the Microsoft Semantic Kernel team, we are announcing the availability of Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Vector Store connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel (.NET) users. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-announcing-the-microsoft-semantic-kernel-elasticsearch-connector 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the GA Release of the OpenAPI Plugin for .NET and Python in Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 19:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the General Availability (GA) release of the OpenAPI package for Semantic Kernel, available for both .NET and Python! With this significant milestone, developers can easily integrate existing APIs as plugins, enhancing the capabilities of their AI agents while making them more versatile in real-world applications. Why OpenAPI Plugins Matter In […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/announcing-the-ga-release-of-the-openapi-plugin-for-net-and-python-in-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect which menu my item was invoked from?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just give them all different IDs. But this might itself by an XY problem.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241121-00/?p=110554 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making you more productive with Visual Studio v17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2024/21_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The 12th update to Visual Studio 2022 is packed with lots of exciting new features that users have been asking for! Here are some of the awesome highlights from this release that are some of my personal favorites. For all the details, be sure to check out our release notes. Copy from the Error List […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/making-you-more-productive-with-visual-studio-v17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the enhanced MSSQL Extension for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 19:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL extension for Visual Studio Code is designed to support developers in building applications that use Azure SQL (including Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL Server on Azure VMs), SQL Database in Fabric (Preview) or SQL Server as backend databases. With a comprehensive suite of features for connecting to databases, designing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/mssql-extension-visual-studio-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotnet scaffold – Next Generation Project Creation for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing a new command line tool dotnet scaffold, a new interactive way to create projects in .NET.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-dotnet-scaffold 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the new Linux-based Azure Cosmos DB Emulator (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the preview release of the new Linux-based Azure Cosmos DB Emulator! This latest version is built to provide faster startup times and broader platform compatibility, addressing one of the most requested features in the Azure Cosmos DB User Voice community. The emulator can now seamlessly run on Apple silicon and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/introducing-the-new-linux-based-azure-cosmos-db-emulator-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I determine whether Explorer is showing or hiding file extensions?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can ask, but maybe you&#39;re asking the wrong question.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241120-00/?p=110547 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy files across instances of Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2024/20_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Transferring code files between different instances of Visual Studio has often been a tedious task. To simplify this process, Visual Studio 2022 now includes a feature that allows you to easily copy and paste code files and folders between instances using the Solution Explorer. This enhancement aims to streamline workflow and save time. Until now, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/copy-files-across-instances-of-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Shines at Microsoft Ignite 2024!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2024 took over the Windy City this week, bringing with it new technological innovation and exciting product announcements aplenty! If you missed the first day of the show, don’t worry – we’ve got you covered with all the latest and greatest Azure Cosmos DB news. This year’s event saw great enthusiasm and attendance […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-shines-at-microsoft-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of AI Shell</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce the public preview of AI Shell.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-the-public-preview-of-ai-shell 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new for Office Add-ins at Ignite 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Office Platform team has been busy working on improvements to the platform since we last reported. This blog covers the new features from the office-js team announced at Ignite 2024.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/whats-new-for-office-add-ins-at-ignite-2024 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing LangChain integration for your SQL-based AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s data-driven world, the ability to seamlessly integrate various technologies is crucial for efficient data management and analysis. We’re excited to announce LangChain integration with Azure SQL Database and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric! LangChain, a powerful tool for building solutions with language models, can be effectively combined with these services to build AI-ready […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/langchain-with-sqlvectorstore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LangChain Integration for Vector Support for SQL-based AI applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            LangChain Integration for Vector Support for Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric Microsoft SQL now supports native vector search capabilities in Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. We also released the langchain-sqlserver package, enabling the management of SQL Server as a Vectorstore in LangChain. In this step-by-step tutorial, we will show […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/langchain-with-sqlvectorstore-example 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility 17.12: CodeLens support is here!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to invest in the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK to allow users like you to create extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main Visual Studio IDE process for improved performance and reliability, and can be installed without the need to restart Visual Studio. Additional […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-17-12-codelens-support-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Microsoft 365 Agents SDK with Semantic Kernel for Enhanced Multichannel AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the landscape of AI continues to evolve, meeting users where they are is vital. We want to spotlight the newly released Microsoft 365 Agents SDK and its seamless integration with Semantic Kernel. This powerful combination empowers developers to create robust AI agents that operate across various channels where users are already engaged. Extend the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/leveraging-microsoft-365-agents-sdk-with-semantic-kernel-for-enhanced-multichannel-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wrinkle in how Windows 95 setup bootstrapped its initial GUI step</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Getting access to the common controls that don&#39;t exist until Windows 95.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241119-00/?p=110543 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a new landing page and welcome tour for Microsoft developer portal!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we are dedicated to shaping a developer experience that is efficient, user-friendly, and tailored to your needs. With the new landing page and welcome tour, we’re excited to empower you to work more effectively and unlock new levels of productivity. Together, we’re building a platform that evolves with you. At Microsoft, we’re focused […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/introducing-a-new-landing-page-and-welcome-tour-for-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI apps faster and easier with SQL database in Fabric – now Public Preview!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2024/19_11_2024_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The SQL Server and Azure SQL team has embarked on a mission to make building AI apps faster and easier than ever, announcing the Public Preview of SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. This new simple, autonomous and secure, and optimized for AI service will help you in the era of AI, where 1 billion new […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-ai-apps-faster-and-easier-with-sql-database-in-fabric-now-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: Fujitsu Kozuchi AI Agent Powered by Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customer Case Study: Fujitsu Kozuchi AI Agent Powered by Semantic Kernel Japanese multinational Fujitsu, a pioneer of information and communications technology, has been transforming industries since 1935. With a workforce of 124,000 dedicated professionals across 50 countries, Fujitsu’s mission is to “make the world more sustainable by building trust in society through innovation.” After introducing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-fujitsu-kozuchi-ai-agent-powered-by-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your .NET Developer Productivity with GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to get started with GitHub Copilot for .NET development for AI assisted development in Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/enhance-your-dotnet-developer-productivity-with-github-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Managed DevOps Pools (MDP) for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that Managed DevOps Pools for Azure DevOps is now generally available! This milestone marks a significant advancement in our mission to improve developer productivity in the CI/CD loop, reduce your cloud bill for ES infra and to reduce the toil associated with creating and maintaining custom CI/CD infrastructure for your […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/managed-devops-pools-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is a team sport: Building the future of software development together</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we strive to build the world’s most beloved developer tools and services. Our vision is to empower every developer to transform their concepts into reality, from idea to code to cloud, at lightning speed. The Visual Studio family, Azure, GitHub, and GitHub Copilot empower developers around the world to do just that. Since […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//building-the-future-of-software-development-together 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell 7.5 RC-1 is now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Availability of PowerShell 7.5 RC1
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/powershell-7-5-rc-1-is-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s Agentic Frameworks: AutoGen and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft’s agentic AI frameworks, Semantic Kernel and AutoGen are deeply collaborating to provide the best-in-class agentic developer experience. With Semantic Kernel’s enterprise ready AI capabilities, customers can already use and get support for building agent applications and, moving forward, we’ll align the multi-agent runtime in AutoGen (called autogen-core) with Semantic Kernel, allowing customers to create […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/autogen/microsofts-agentic-frameworks-autogen-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git tooling updates in Visual Studio 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce the latest updates to Git tooling in Visual Studio, designed to enhance your development experience and streamline your workflow. These new features are in direct response to user feedback, ensuring that you have the tools you need to be more productive and efficient. For the full list, check out the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/git-tooling-updates-in-visual-studio-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The operations for reading and writing single elements for C&#43;&#43; standard library maps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2024/18_11_2024_17/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Breaking down the options.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241118-00/?p=110535 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
