<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:30:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) – May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post announces the May release of the Azure Developer CLI (azd).
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we built our startup in C#</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tracebit built their B2B SaaS security product using C#.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/why-we-built-our-startup-in-csharp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.24.3-1 and 1.23.9-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 16:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-24-3-1-and-1-23-9-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB with DiskANN Part 4: Stable Vector Search Recall with Streaming Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector search with Azure Cosmos DB In Part 1 and Part 2 of this series, we explored vector search with Azure Cosmos DB and best practices for scaling it to 1 billion vector datasets while maintaining low query latency. In Part 3, we saw how we can create efficient sharded DiskANN indices for multi-tenant apps. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-with-diskann-part-4-stable-vector-search-recall-with-streaming-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Availability for Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Title: General Availability for Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB We’re excited to announce the general availability of the Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB! Overview The Data API is a RESTful HTTPS interface that enables developers to interact with their MongoDB data hosted in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/general-availability-for-data-api-in-vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the MS-DOS programs that the moricons.dll icons were intended for?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_05_2025/07_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Tallying them up.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250507-00/?p=111157 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested App Authentication: Now generally available across Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 17:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get started with Nested App Authentication, a modern protocol for simplifying authentication for Personal Tab Teams apps that run across Microsoft 365.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/nested-app-authentication-now-generally-available-across-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Linux is now an official WSL distro</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re pleased to announce that one of the latest additions to the list of official WSL distros is Fedora Linux! The Fedora Project has taken advantage of WSL’s new tar-based architecture to produce WSL images beginning with Fedora 42. Try it out To install it, run wsl –-install FedoraLinux-42and then launch it with wsl –d […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/fedora-linux-is-now-an-official-wsl-distro 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently and Elegantly Modeling Embeddings in Azure SQL and SQL Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Storing and querying text embeddings in a database it might seem challenging, but with the right schema design, it’s not only possible, it’s powerful. Whether you’re building AI-powered search, semantic filtering, or recommendation features, embeddings, and thus vectors, are now a first-class data type. So how do you model them well inside a database like […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/efficiently-and-elegantly-modeling-embeddings-in-azure-sql-and-sql-server 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Language Updates in MSVC in Visual Studio 2022 17.14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In this update, we continue the tradition of bucketing bugs into helpful categories for you all to filter through along with even more notes from the compiler team as to what, exactly, was fixed. This blog is also complemented by the recent Pure Virtual C++ pre-conference talk by RanDair Porter; so please check out […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/c-language-updates-in-msvc-in-visual-studio-2022-17-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the MS-DOS programs that Windows used the progman.exe stock icons for?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Mostly generic-looking icons.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250506-00/?p=111149 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing Legacy App Modernization: Crowdbotics’ AI-Native Platform on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Author: Charath Ranganathan, CTO, Crowdbotics Modernizing legacy applications is one of the most daunting tasks facing enterprises today. These systems, often built decades ago using technologies like COBOL on mainframes, power critical business functions but are notoriously difficult, time-consuming, and expensive to update or replace. The process typically involves painstaking manual efforts to understand undocumented […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/reinventing-legacy-app-modernization-crowdbotics-ai-native-platform-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC1: Semantic Kernel for Java Agents API</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 09:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_05_2025/06_05_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the release candidate of the Semantic Kernel for Java Agents API! This marks a major step forward in bringing the power of intelligent agents to Java developers, enabling them to build rich, contextual, and interactive AI experiences using the Semantic Kernel framework. What Are Agents in Semantic Kernel? Agents are intelligent, autonomous […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/preview-release-semantic-kernel-for-java-agents-api 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the updated Teams AI Library and MCP support</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new and improved Teams AI Library, designed to help developers create even more powerful agents for Microsoft Teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-updated-teams-ai-library-and-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What were the intended uses of those icons in moricons.dll?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_05_2025/05_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Icons for old MS-DOS apps.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250505-00/?p=111143 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (April 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 21:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.04.09 registry release, 2025-03-22, 2025-04-01, and 2025-04-07 tool releases, as well as changes to vcpkg documentation throughout April. This release contains bug fixes, a new documentation article on offline usage of vcpkg, and other minor improvements. Arm64 Linux users of vcpkg […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-april-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Blog: Orchestrating AI Agents with Semantic Kernel Plugins: A Technical Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 21:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we’re excited to welcome Jarre Nejatyab as a guest blog to highlight a technical deep dive on orchestrating AI Agents with Semantic Kernel Plugins. In the rapidly evolving world of Large Language Models (LLMs), orchestrating specialized AI agents has become crucial for building sophisticated cognitive architectures capable of complex reasoning and task execution. While […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/guest-blog-orchestrating-ai-agents-with-semantic-kernel-plugins-a-technical-deep-dive 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using type aliasing to avoid the ODR problem with conditional compilation, part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ensuring that you pick a side.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250502-00/?p=111140 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure DevOps ID Token Refresh and Terraform Task Version 5</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 08:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to share some recent updates that improve the experience of using Workload identity federation (OpenID Connect) with Azure DevOps and Terraform on Microsoft Azure. Many working parts have come together to make this possible and we’ll share those here. We are also very pleased to announce version 5 of the Microsoft DevLabs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-azure-devops-id-token-refresh-and-terraform-task-version-5 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running RAG with ONNX Runtime GenAI for On-Prem Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_05_2025/02_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Exploring how to efficiently run a RAG pipeline with structured language models (SLMs) and guardrails on Windows, achieving inference under 5 seconds with ONNX Runtime GenAI.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/running-rag-onnxruntime-genai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Project Files with AI: A Success Story from the .NET Team</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft, we are constantly exploring innovative ways to enhance our workflows, improve productivity, and ensure we have a secure supply chain that uses modern tools. One of our recent initiatives was to rebuild the .NET Framework build system by leveraging AI to automate the process. Here’s the story of how we successfully achieved this […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/modernizing-project-files-with-ai-a-success-story-from-the-dotnet-team 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code April 2025 Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 17:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code April 2025 Update Azure AI Foundry is a trusted platform for designing, customizing, and managing AI applications, with a portal that enables secure data integration, model customization, and enterprise-grade governance. Earlier this month, we announced the public preview of the Azure AI Foundry extension. And today, the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-ai-foundry-extension-for-visual-studio-code-april-2025-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There’s a Linux File Explorer built into Visual Studio!?!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Remote File Explorer in Visual Studio provides developers with a convenient way to browse, view, and edit files on remote machines—directly from within the IDE. It’s a powerful tool for managing remote environments without leaving your development workflow. Scott Hanselman published a new YouTube video to his channel, taking us on the journey of […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/theres-a-linux-file-explorer-built-into-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly prototype with gpt-image-1 from Azure OpenAI Service in the Images Playground in Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the next-gen images playground in Azure AI Foundry, a high-fidelity UX sandbox for developers to rapidly prototype with state-of-the-art image generation models like gpt-image-1 from Azure OpenAI Service 1. This playground enables real-time experimentation, prompt optimization, and integration with developer tools like VS Code, accelerating the &amp;quot;Build-Measure-Learn&amp;quot; development loop and enhancing productivity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/images-playground-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using C&#43;&#43; type aliasing to avoid the ODR problem with conditional compilation, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Still one definition, but two types.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250501-00/?p=111134 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.27 with generating TypeSpec files and configuring using natural language</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 06:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_05_2025/01_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dev Proxy v0.27 is even more developer-friendly, helping you generate API specs faster, improving suggestions while editing, and laying the foundation for more flexible AI integrations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-27-with-generating-typespec-files-and-configuring-using-natural-language 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
