<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:24:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Expectations</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Although the process may seem slow, we are steadily progressing toward rolling out the New Boards Hub to all customers. Our plan is to deprecate the old Boards experience for all Azure DevOps service users by the end Q1 2025. The rollout is advancing on two fronts. First, we are setting the New Boards Hub […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Box Ready-To-Code Dev Box images template</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft One Engineering System (1ES) team shares a sample for building Ready-To-Code Dev Box environments pre-configured with the necessary tools, repositories, and settings, ensuring consistency and reliability across teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/dev-box-ready-to-code-dev-box-images-template 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless publishing with Azure Functions Flex Consumption</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Struggling with complex deployment processes for your serverless applications? Visual Studio 2022 introduces a seamless solution with the new Azure Functions Flex Consumption hosting plan, now generally available. Imagine a world where deploying your serverless applications to a hosting plan that supports fast scaling and VNet is as simple as a right-click. With the Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-publishing-with-azure-functions-flex-consumption 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the CONTINUE_IF_FAILED equivalent of RETURN_IF_FAILED?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_12_2024/11_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Be careful how you write it, or better: Don&#39;t write it at all.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241211-00/?p=110629 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoking Async Power: What Awaits WinForms in .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With .NET 9, we’re bringing a suite of new async APIs to WinForms, aimed at making UI updates, dialog interactions, and control management more efficient.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-winforms-async-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effortless publishing to Azure WebJobs on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the cumbersome process involved in publishing your .NET console applications to Azure WebJobs on Linux? For developers yearning for a seamless and efficient method to deploy their applications, Visual Studio 2022 introduces a much-anticipated solution. Visual Studio 2022 now supports right-click publishing to Azure WebJobs on Linux, making the deployment process […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/effortless-publishing-to-azure-webjobs-on-linux 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compute scaling in Azure Fluid Relay</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore the journey of identifying and fine-tuning the optimal Kubernetes autoscaling configuration for Azure Fluid Relay.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/compute-scaling-in-azure-fluid-relay 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONNX GenAI Connector for Python (Experimental)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ONNX GenAI Connector for Python (Experimental) With the latest update we added support for running models locally with the onnxruntime-genai. The onnxruntime-genai package is powered by the ONNX Runtime in the background, but first let’s clarify what ONNX, ONNX Runtime and ONNX Runtime-GenAI are. ONNX ONNX is an open-source format for AI models, both for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/onnx-genai-connector-for-python-experimental 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It rather involved being on the other side of this airtight hatchway: Disabling anti-malware scanning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_12_2024/10_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you have already infiltrated the process, then you can disable things from the inside.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241210-00/?p=110626 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Local AI models with .NET Aspire</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let&#39;s look at how to build and run local AI models with .NET Aspire.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/local-ai-models-with-dotnet-aspire 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Python in VS Code Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As the year comes to a close, we would like to take the time to reflect and celebrate the incredible progress the Python extension for VS Code has made in the past year. From merging in top requested features to countless lines of code written and deleted, keep reading to get an inside look to all things
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/2024-python-vscode-wrapped 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Unified Data Model is Critical: Lessons from Building Microsoft’s Semantic Layer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Some years ago, we were wrestling with a persistent issue in our data stack. Every team had their own way of collecting and structuring data. What was a simple query for one team became a debugging nightmare for another. Discovering the right dataset felt like looking for a needle in a haystack, and standardizing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/unified-data-models-101 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Global System Integrators can make the most of their GitHub Copilot licenses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI-powered code assistant tools like GitHub Copilot have revolutionized the development landscape. We’ve observed significant Copilot adoption among Global System Integrators (GSIs), who are leading the charge in harnessing its potential. While many developers are already utilizing GitHub Copilot in their internal projects, GSI’s are eager to integrate Copilot into their own application development lifecycles. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/dont-let-your-github-copilot-licenses-collect-dust-how-gsis-can-make-their-every-license-count 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep working with non-blocking Code Cleanup</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 16:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of waiting for Code Cleanup to finish every time you save your work? Visual Studio 2022 will no longer lock up and get in the way of your tasks as it’s cleaning up the code under the covers. Every developer knows the importance of maintaining clean code. However, the traditional Code Cleanup […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/keep-working-with-non-blocking-code-cleanup 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Failing to create a shared_ptr</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/09_12_2024/09_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Understanding what you asked the compiler to do, and why it couldn&#39;t comply.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241209-00/?p=110619 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Case Study: How to use Elasticsearch Vector Store Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel for AI Agent development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            How to use Elasticsearch Vector Store Connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel for AI Agent development Today we’re excited to feature the Elastic team to share more about their Semantic Kernel Elasticsearch Vector Store connector for Microsoft Semantic Kernel. Read the entire announcement here. I’ll turn it over to Srikanth Manvi and Florian Bernd to dive […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/customer-case-study-how-to-use-elasticsearch-vector-store-connector-for-microsoft-semantic-kernel-for-ai-agent-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deletion of Outdated Azul Zulu for Azure Container Images for Better Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We at Microsoft are committed to providing customers with a secure ecosystem of tools for building and deploying applications. As part of this commitment, we continuously update our Java container image offerings to ensure they meet the highest security standards. Back in January 2022, we announced the End of Updates for the Azul Zulu for Azure build of OpenJDK. As […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/deletion-of-outdated-azul-zulu-for-azure-container-images-for-better-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSVC Compiler Language Updates in Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In alignment with the Visual Studio 2022 version 17.12 release, and based upon feedback received from the community, the MSVC compiler team would like to provide greater visibility into the C++ language-level fixes for customer-reported issues that made it into the release. This is similar to how the standard library team publishes regular changelogs […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/msvc-compiler-language-updates-in-visual-studio-2022-version-17-12 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Microsoft 365 app performance: Introducing tree shaking in TeamsJS</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Microsoft Teams JavaScript client library (TeamsJS) version 2.31.0, we’re excited to make the TeamsJS library fully tree-shakable.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/boost-your-microsoft-365-app-performance-introducing-tree-shaking-in-teamsjs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Nonsensical errors from a function declaration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Look closely at what the error message is complaining about.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241206-00/?p=110614 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Evaluation platform on Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_12_2024/06_12_2024_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Machine Learning is known for training and deploying models, but can also be used for running experiments. This blog post will show us how we have implemented our Evaluation platform on Azure Machine Learning.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/implement-evaluation-platform-on-aml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Code Referencing for GitHub Copilot Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Are you tired of the uncertainty that comes with using code suggestions from AI tools? We’ve got exciting news for you! Visual Studio 2022 now includes code referencing in GitHub Copilot, ensuring greater transparency and control for developers. We are thrilled to announce that code referencing is now available in GitHub Copilot Chat within Visual […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-code-referencing-for-github-copilot-chat-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dependabot to Manage .NET SDK Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to use Dependabot to keep your .NET SDK version up to date with the latest security patches and improvements.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-dependabot-to-manage-dotnet-sdk-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure Cosmos DB Integration with Spring AI and Langchain4J!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re continuing to simplify AI app development by integrating Azure Cosmos DB’s cost-effective and scalable vector search directly with Spring AI and LangChain4J! These frameworks empower Java developers to efficiently manage fast and accurate data retrieval with Azure Cosmos DB’s scalability and efficient vector indexing and search capabilities, allowing for efficient handling of high-dimensional vectors. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-azure-cosmos-db-integration-with-spring-ai-and-langchain4j 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won’t waiting for multiple threads one at a time introduce a severe performance issue?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_12_2024/05_12_2024_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It depends on how long you plan on waiting.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241205-00/?p=110609 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latest enhancements in Fluid Framework 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Catch up on all of the Fluid Framework 2 announcements highlighted at Ignite including the AI Collab library, Fluid presence library, and more.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/latest-enhancements-in-fluid-framework-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to develop AI Apps and Agents in Azure – A Visual Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations explore new AI-powered experiences and automated workflows, there’s a growing need to move beyond experiments and proofs-of-concept to production-ready applications. This guide walks you through the essential steps and decisions for building robust AI applications in Azure, focusing on reliability, security, and enterprise-grade quality. Why Choose Azure’s Managed Services? It’s easy to experiment […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-develop-ai-apps-and-agents-in-azure-a-visual-guide 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Copilot for Code Refactoring</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I share GitHub Copilot tips every few days, if you are new to the series, below I have linked some of the previous tips. In this article, I am sharing a tip about using GitHub Copilot for code refactoring. GitHub Copilot Tip: Interactive Debugging with GitHub Copilot Chat How to use GitHub Copilot for Efficient […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/how-to-use-copilot-for-code-refactoring 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.23.4-1 and 1.22.10-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 18:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new set of Microsoft Go builds is now available for download.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-23-4-1-and-1-22-10-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Inline Return Values Simplify Debugging in Visual Studio 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Have you ever found yourself creating temporary variables just to inspect return values from functions? It’s a small task that can quickly become tedious, breaking your rhythm and cluttering up your code. Visual Studio 2022 introduces a smarter way to handle this with “Inline Return Values,” allowing you to stay focused on coding without the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/how-inline-return-values-simplify-debugging-in-visual-studio-2022 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does my DLL reference count go up by one every time I create and exit a thread?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you use a wrapper, you need to follow the wrapper&#39;s rules.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241204-00/?p=110604 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Microsoft Entra ID for enhanced security in three-tier architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 14:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_12_2024/04_12_2024_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explore how to secure three-tier architecture with Microsoft Entra ID in this first part of a three-part series. Learn how to implement robust authentication and authorization across client app, API, and data layers, ensuring secure and reliable application design in an Azure cloud environment.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/microsoft-entra-id-and-three-tier-arhcitecture 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
