<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 05:35:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure OpenAI Realtime API Support in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 05:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the new Realtime API support in the OpenAI JavaScript library, enabling developers to create highly interactive and responsive applications by instantly sending and receiving messages from Azure OpenAI models.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/introducing-azure-openai-realtime-api-support-in-javascript 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning AI Prompts into Playing Cards: A Platform Engineering Experiment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 03:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The inspiration for this project came from my desire to leverage AI to create a tangible product that you can hold, touch, and share. Cardmaker showcases the capabilities of modern AI as a tool to help its user craft a custom card deck. But that’s not all. It also provides a unique and tangible product […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/turning-ai-prompts-into-playing-cards-a-platform-engineering-experiment 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure OpenAI Chat Completion with data source and Function Calling</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 01:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_02_2025/05_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure OpenAI Chat Completion with data source provides powerful capabilities for integrating conversational AI into applications. However, using a data source and function calling in a single request is not supported yet. When both features are enabled, function calling is ignored, and only the data source is used. This presents a challenge when retrieving information, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/using-azure-openai-chat-completion-with-data-source-and-function-calling 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET Core on .NET Framework servicing release advisory: ASP.NET Core 2.3</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            ASP.NET Core 2.1 has been reshipped as ASP.NET Core 2.3 to help users on the unsupported ASP.NET Core 2.2 move to a supported version.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/servicing-release-advisory-aspnetcore-23 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full web support for conditional access policies across Azure DevOps and partner web properties</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 17:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that we’ve made significant progress in updating our web authentication stack on Azure DevOps services and partner web properties to utilize Microsoft Entra tokens to handle web sessions. By replacing our previous cookies with Entra tokens, we’ve deepened the integration we have with Microsoft Entra ID on our web experience. This […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/full-web-support-for-conditional-access-policies-across-azure-devops-and-partner-web-properties 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Kiota support for Dart, now in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What is Kiota, why and how to use it to create API clients for any OpenAPI described APIs and the new language support, Dart.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/openapi/kiota-dart-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing, querying and keeping embeddings updated: options and best practices</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Embeddings and vectors are becoming common terms not only for engineers involved in AI-related activities but also for those using databases. Some common points of discussion that frequently arise among users familiar with vectors and embeddings include: How can I quickly “vectorize” the content already present in my database? How can I keep the vectors […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/storing-querying-and-keeping-embeddings-updated-options-and-best-practices 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The original name for Flexible Single Master Operations in Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not that kind of F-word.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250204-00/?p=110834 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your fonts are now preserved when changing theme</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Do you find yourself adjusting your font settings every time you change themes in Visual Studio, We’ve made some changes that we think will help. The latest update in Visual Studio 2022 allows theme switching without affecting font settings. This feature maintains the selected font face and size regardless of the chosen theme, while font […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/your-fonts-are-now-preserved-when-changing-theme 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Roadmap H1 2025: Accelerating Agents, Processes, and Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 05:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we move into the first half of 2025, I’m excited to share our ambitious roadmap that we hope will enable you to build even more sophisticated AI applications with Semantic Kernel. Agent Framework 1.0 By the end of Q1 2025, the SK Agent Framework will transition from preview to general availability (GA). This milestone […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-roadmap-h1-2025-accelerating-agents-processes-and-integration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-Step Guide: User Provisioning with SAML Authentication in GitHub Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2025/04_02_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This guide demonstrates how to seamlessly set up user access in GitHub Enterprise using Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) authentication. The process connects a user’s GitHub account with your organization’s identity provider (such as Microsoft Entra ID or Okta), enabling secure and streamlined access management. The diagram above describes the process when a user […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/step-by-step-guide-user-provisioning-with-saml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctors generate faster, more accurate medical charts with Sayvant and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article is guest authored by Justin Mardjuki, CEO, Sayvant. Emergency rooms and urgent care facilities handle an estimated 350 million visits each year. Acute care environments are fast-paced, unpredictable, and high stakes. In these settings, providing care quickly is paramount. That’s why we created Sayvant, the leading clinical documentation AI solution for acute care. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/doctors-generate-faster-more-accurate-medical-charts-with-sayvant-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the ‘Simplify Microsoft Power Platform Deployments by Using Pipelines’ Learning Path</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 17:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Learn offers many Power Platform learn modules. Now, we are expanding the collection with a new release! Pipelines in Power Platform is a managed environments feature that has been released a while back now! Over time, it has improved significantly with updates like SPN support, deployment pages, extensibility, and personal pipelines. Many people requested […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/announcing-the-simplify-microsoft-power-platform-deployments-by-using-pipelines-learning-path 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stored Procedure Caching in Data API builder Now Supported</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing Procedure Cache Data API builder (DAB) has long supported Level 1 cache for tables and views. Level 1 is an in-memory cache that automatically stores frequent queries or slow-changing data in the API layer, bypassing several database queries. Today, Data API builder (DAB) also supports Level 1 cache for stored procedures. This is important. […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/procedure-caching-in-data-api-builder-now-supported 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to Azure DevOps Allowed IP addresses</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce some important upgrades to our networking infrastructure that will enhance the performance and reliability of our service. As part of these infrastructure upgrades, we are introducing new IP addresses that you will need to allow list in your firewall configurations. What’s Changing And Why? We are transitioning from the current […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/update-to-ado-allowed-ip-addresses 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customize your AI-generated git commit messages</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When it comes to collaborative software development, clear and effective communication is key. One area that often gets overlooked is the Git commit message. Poorly crafted commit messages can lead to confusion and inefficiencies within a team. That’s why we’ve built on the suggestions and feedback for the AI-generated commit messages, and now you can […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/customize-your-ai-generated-git-commit-messages 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On trying to log an exception as it leaves your scope</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2025/03_02_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can&#39;t watch it from an object on the outside.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250203-00/?p=110830 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Intelligent Apps with .NET and DeepSeek R1 Today!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 20:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to easily integrate DeepSeek R1 with .NET applications using the Microsoft.Extensions.AI library.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/start-building-an-intelligent-app-with-dotnet-and-deep-seek 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look into the new architecture on RNW 0.76 and 0.77!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve recently released React Native Windows 0.76 and 0.77- marking the first time we invite developers to create RNW experiences on the new architecture.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/2025-01-29-new-architecture-on-0-76-0-77 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (January 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 17:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_01_2025/31_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SDK releases every month. In this post, you find this month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-january-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Microsoft Graph Export-Import APIs for Exchange in public preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 22:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce the launch of Export-Import APIs in limited Public Preview (Beta), a set of Microsoft Graph APIs that empower applications to discover, export and import contents from Exchange Online mailboxes in full fidelity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-microsoft-graph-export-import-apis-for-exchange-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing AMQP v2 stack engine support in the Azure Messaging Event Hubs library for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 20:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post announces a new stable release of the Azure Event Hubs library for Java, with enhanced reliability and performance.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-amqp-v2-stack-engine-support-in-the-azure-messaging-event-hubs-library-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing collapsed text Indicators</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 19:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 introduces new options for customizing the collapsed text indicator, which helps in distinguishing between different sections of collapsed text in the editor. This aims to make the coding environment more intuitive and easier to use by providing additional customization for visual cues. Customizing your coding environment You can now personalize the color […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/customizing-collapsed-text-indicators 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Migration on February 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that the Q# blog will be moving to a new home at Azure Quantum Technical Blog on February 5, 2025. This will enable us to offer you a more seamless and enhanced experience through a single integrated platform, featuring the latest information and resources in quantum computing. Best regards, The […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/qsharp/blog-migration-on-february-5th 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2501.30-preview: Application Specific Driver State, Recreate At GPUVA and Tight Alignment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2501.30-preview, available for download here. This release has initial support for the exciting new D3D12 features that were released in a preview DirectX Agility SDK today. Please visit this blog post for more information about the Agility SDK release. 2501.30-preview is a preview version of PIX. It is identical to 2501.30 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2501-30-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2501.30 – Support for Shader Hash Bypass, bug fixes, and everything in 2412.12</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2501.30, which can be downloaded here. This release includes support for everything that was in the 2412.12 version of PIX, plus the following improvements: Support for Shader Hash Bypass PIX has full support for this new D3D12 feature that allows apps to bypass shader hash validation in D3D12 runtime by […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2501-30 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.716.0-preview: New D3D12 Video Encode Features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 18:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today DirectX 12 provides APIs to support GPU video encode acceleration for several applications, as detailed in D3D12 Video Encoding – Windows drivers | Microsoft Learn previous blog posts such as Announcing new DirectX 12 feature – Video Encoding! – DirectX Developer Blog. In this blog post we’re happy to announce a series of new features […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-716-0-new-d3d12-video-encode-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.716.0-preview &amp; 1.615-retail: Shader hash bypass</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The D3D runtime as of 1.615 officially supports applications opting to bypass shader hash validation. The historical purpose of the hash that the DX shader compiler embeds in every shader binary was to give the D3D runtime to confidence that shaders being given to it are well formed. The assumption was that a hashed shader […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-716-0-preview-1-615-retail-shader-hash-bypass 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AgilitySDK 1.716.0-preview and 1.615-retail</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 17:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce both a retail release of Shader hash bypass and a preview AgilitySDK release with several new features, available on Agility SDK Downloads today! You can find detailed information about all the features on the individual blog pages: 1.615 Shader hash bypass officially supports applications opting to bypass shader hash validation. It is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agilitysdk-1-716-0-preview-and-1-615-retail 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document build instructions and more with enhanced C&#43;&#43; awareness from Copilot Chat in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 15:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2025/30_01_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ development often involves nuances beyond the file you’re developing in. This can leave developers with many mental tabs open, balancing all the relevant context for their project to develop their C++ code properly. Copilot Chat in Visual Studio can already utilize context provided by specified files and invoked agents such as @workspace to generate […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/document-build-instructions-and-more-with-enhanced-c-awareness-from-copilot-chat-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.8 Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the availability of TypeScript 5.8 Beta. To get started using the beta, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@beta Let’s take a look at what’s new in TypeScript 5.8! Checked Returns for Conditional and Indexed Access Types Consider an API that presents […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-8-beta 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I create an inserter iterator that does unhinted insertion into an associative container like std::map?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2025/29_01_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Curiously missing from the standard library.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250129-00/?p=110817 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
