<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 19:01:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code quicker with Azure AI Foundry playgrounds and Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 19:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The &amp;quot;Open in VS Code&amp;quot; workflow, part of the Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code, accelerates developer velocity by integrating agent or model API endpoints and code samples into a new workspace in VS Code for Web. This feature streamlines the development process, enabling rapid prototyping and deployment with just one click.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/open-in-vscode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB TV – Everything New in Azure Cosmos DB from Microsoft Build 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2025 brought major innovations to Azure Cosmos DB, and in Episode 105 of Azure Cosmos DB TV, Principal Program Manager Mark Brown sits down with Kirill Gavrylyuk, Vice President and GM of Azure Cosmos DB, to break it all down. Whether you’re developing AI-native apps, building with MongoDB, or just looking for better […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-tv-everything-new-in-azure-cosmos-db-from-microsoft-build-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing dotnet run app.cs – A simpler way to start with C# and .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are super excited to introduce a new feature that was released as part of .NET 10 Preview 4 that makes getting started with C# easier than ever. You can now run a C# file directly using dotnet run app.cs. This means you no longer need to create a project file or scaffold a whole […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-run-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the commands in your extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 15:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Visual Studio extension authors, our goal is to create tools that empower developers across diverse environments. A key part of this mission involves ensuring that your extension commands remain accessible and consistent across all Visual Studio locales. In your VSSDK extensions, by adding the CanonicalName property to your commands in the .vsct file, you […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improve-the-commands-in-your-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DocumentDB Local – MongoDB API on Your Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 15:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction DocumentDB Local provides a lightweight, containerized environment that lets you develop and test applications locally using a MongoDB-compatible interface. It’s ideal for prototyping or running integration tests without needing a cloud setup. When paired with the DocumentDB Extension for Visual Studio Code, it creates a focused and consistent local development environment. DocumentDB Local is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/documentdb-local-mongodb-api-on-your-machine 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I convert a WIC bitmap back to a GDI HBITMAP?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can copy the bits into a DIB section.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250528-00/?p=111225 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel and Microsoft.Extensions.AI: Better Together, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 13:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 2 of our series on integrating Microsoft.Extensions.AI with Semantic Kernel. In Part 1, we explored the relationship between these technologies and how they complement each other. Now, let’s dive into practical examples showing how to use Microsoft.Extensions.AI abstractions with Semantic Kernel in non-agent scenarios. Getting Started with Microsoft.Extensions.AI and Semantic Kernel Before we […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-and-microsoft-extensions-ai-better-together-part-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure AI Foundry MCP Server May 2025 Update: Adding Models, Knowledge &amp; Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Major expansion of Azure AI Foundry MCP Server with new Models, Knowledge Management, and Evaluation capabilities joining the existing Agent Services, enabling developers to interact with Azure AI through natural language.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-ai-foundry-mcp-server-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing New Tools and Features in the Responses API in Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With the introduction of the Responses API, Microsoft is enabling a new standard for AI development within the Azure ecosystem. Originally launched by OpenAI and now natively supported in Azure AI Foundry, the Responses API combines the simplicity of the Chat Completions API with the advanced tool-calling capabilities of the Assistants API. It offers a […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-new-tools-and-features-in-the-responses-api-in-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Address Sanitizer Updates for Visual Studio 2022 Version 17.14</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 20:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction It has been an exciting few months for the Address Sanitizer (ASan) since our last update. In addition to our continuous focus on quality and correctness, our internal “dogfooding” (i.e. internal adoption) effort has reached several important milestones. In this update, I want to go over some of the quality improvements since Visual Studio […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/address-sanitizer-updates-for-visual-studio-2022-17-14 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps with GitHub Repositories – Your path to Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 19:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot has evolved beyond a coding assistant in the IDE into an agentic teammate – providing actionable feedback on pull requests, fixing bugs and implementing new features, creating pull requests and responding to feedback, and much more. These new capabilities will transform every aspect of the software development lifecycle, as we are already seeing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-with-github-repositories-your-path-to-agentic-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circuit Breaker Policy Fine-tuning Best Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Summary of some best practice and insights about circuit breaker resilience policy fine-tuning.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/circuit-breaker-policy-finetuning-best-practice 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel: Multi-agent Orchestration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 16:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The field of AI is rapidly evolving, and the need for more sophisticated, collaborative, and flexible agent-based systems is growing. With this in mind, Semantic Kernel introduces a new multi-agent orchestration framework that enables developers to build, manage, and scale complex agent workflows with ease. This post explores the new orchestration patterns, their capabilities, and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-multi-agent-orchestration 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VisualStudio.Extensibility: Editor classification and updates to user prompt</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to invest in the VisualStudio.Extensibility SDK to allow users like you to create extensions that run faster and smoother than ever before! VisualStudio.Extensibility helps you build extensions that run outside the main Visual Studio IDE process for improved performance, reliability, and installation without restarting Visual Studio. Additional benefits include a sleek and intuitive […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visualstudio-extensibility-editor-classification-and-updates-to-user-prompt 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What was origin of the code name Redpill for Windows 8 feature lockout?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_05_2025/27_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Pretty obvious, actually.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250527-00/?p=111220 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Enum­Process­Modules report no modules on a process that was created suspended?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_05_2025/26_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There are no modules yet because you didn&#39;t give them a chance to load.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250526-00/?p=111218 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of JavaScript SDK v4 for Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 22:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to launch version 4 of the Azure Cosmos DB JavaScript SDK! This update delivers major improvements that make it easier and faster to build high-performance apps with the Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL API. Version 4 is available now and targets Node.js v18 and above, introducing a host of new capabilities, including: Improved […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-general-availability-of-javascript-sdk-v4-for-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confluent Cloud Releases Managed V2 Kafka Connector for Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 18:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was co-authored by Sudhindra Sheshadrivasan, Staff Product Manager at Confluent. We’re excited to announce the General Availability (GA) of the Confluent Cloud-managed V2 Kafka Connector for Azure Cosmos DB! This release marks a major milestone in our mission to simplify and streamline real-time data streaming from and into Azure Cosmos DB using Apache […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/confluent-cloud-releases-managed-v2-kafka-connector-for-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the DocumentDB Extension for VS Code and DocumentDB Local — A Fast, Friendly Way to Work with DocumentDB, Locally and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 16:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Say hello to the new DocumentDB extension for Visual Studio Code—an efficient open-source database tool that brings your MongoDB API and DocumentDB databases right into your editor. Designed for developers building cloud apps, working in hybrid or local setups, or debugging live production systems, this extension lets you browse, manage, and query your data directly […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/meet-the-documentdb-extension-for-vs-code-and-documentdb-local-a-fast-friendly-way-to-work-with-documentdb-locally-and-beyond 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now in Public Preview: Azure Functions Trigger for Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB vCore</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Cosmos DB trigger for Azure Functions is now in public preview—available for C# Azure Functions using Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB vCore! This new capability allows developers to easily trigger Azure Functions in response to changes in a MongoDB vCore collection, making it simple to build real-time, event-driven applications with minimal setup. 🔍 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-in-public-preview-azure-functions-trigger-for-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-vcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I detect if one of my helper processes is launching child processes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can ask a job object to keep track for you.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250523-00/?p=111216 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durable Functions for Indexing in RAG: A Practical Python Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 08:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_05_2025/23_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Durable Functions streamline RAG indexing by combining push flexibility with pull reliability for scalable,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/durable-functions-for-rag-indexing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Add-ins announces Copilot agents with add-in actions and more at Build 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 22:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of the expanding capabilities for agents across Microsoft 365, Office Platform announces add-in actions for Copilot agents are available in preview. This blog is an overview of all the new capabilities across the platform: APIs, developer tools, and add-in distribution options—making it simpler to build new or iterate on JavaScript add-ins.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/office-addins-at-build-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Available: Migrate from RU to vCore for Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB via Azure Portal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 22:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to introduce a cost-effective, simple, and efficient solution for migrating from RU-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB to vCore-based. You can now move to vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB at no cost using the Azure portal. How is the vCore model different? Azure Cosmos DB offers two pricing models: Request Units […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/migrate-mongo-db-ru-to-vcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New AI Features in SQL Server 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 20:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have some great new AI Features in SQL Server 2025. I also figured a video would be better than reading a blog…. but, you can also read all about it here.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/new-ai-features-in-sql-server-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Seamless Migration from Serverless to Provisioned Throughput in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 20:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce the general availability (GA) of a highly requested capability in Azure Cosmos DB: the ability to migrate from serverless to provisioned throughput mode—without manual recreation, or downtime. This release builds on the momentum of our public preview and is now fully supported across all regions. Why it matters Azure Cosmos […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/generally-available-seamless-migration-from-serverless-to-provisioned-throughput-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Shape and Control Workloads with Throughput Buckets in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 17:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine your application is processing customer checkouts in real-time, while a background process synchronizes data for reporting. Suddenly, the seamless user experience falters because the sync job consumes more RU/s than anticipated. Many teams face a common challenge: multiple workloads share the same container resources, yet each has different performance requirements. We’re excited to introduce […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/public-preview-shape-and-control-workloads-with-throughput-buckets-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Agent Store: Build, publish, and discover agents in Microsoft 365 Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce the Agent Store — a centralized, curated marketplace that features agents built by Microsoft, trusted partners, and customers. The Agent Store offers a new, immersive experience within Microsoft 365 Copilot that enables users to browse, install, and try agents tailored to their needs.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-agent-store-build-publish-and-discover-agents-in-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript Native Previews</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 15:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This past March we unveiled our efforts to port the TypeScript compiler and toolset to native code. This port has achieved a 10x speed-up on most projects – not just by using a natively-compiled language (Go), but also through using shared memory parallelism and concurrency where we can benefit. Since then, we have made several […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-native-previews 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Entra ID integration with Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB (vCore)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Security is no longer a nice-to-have—it’s a foundational requirement for any cloud-native architecture. As organizations adopt managed database services to support mission-critical applications, they must prioritize robust, scalable, and centralized security. Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB (vCore) delivers high performance and flexibility, but it provides the most value when paired with well-implemented security practices. Authentication […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/microsoft-entra-id-integration-with-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-vcore 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I create a window the size of the screen without it being treated as a fullscreen window?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_05_2025/22_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can declare that you aren&#39;t rude.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250522-00/?p=111211 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
