<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for .NET Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Conf 2025 is just one week away! Join us November 11-13 for this free, three-day virtual conference showcasing the latest advancements in the .NET platform, open-source projects, and developer tools - including the official release of .NET 10 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/get-ready-for-dotnet-conf-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JDConf 2026 Is Coming With Modern Solutions for an Agentic World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Technology is accelerating faster than ever, and developers are once again at the helm, shaping the future of applications, intelligence, and enterprise systems. With the rise of large language models (LLMs), agent-oriented architectures, and AI-driven development paradigms, Java developers find themselves in a uniquely po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jdconf-2026-is-coming-with-modern-solutions-for-an-agentic-world 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft SoftCard for the Apple II: Getting two processors to share the same memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Z-80 SoftCard was a plug-in expansion card for the Apple II that added the ability to run CP/M software. According to Wikipedia, it was Microsoft&#39;s first hardware product and in 1980 was the single largest revenue source for the company. CP/M runs on an 8080 pr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251104-00/?p=111758 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New developer resource page for Microsoft 365 interoperability and data portability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has long provided interoperability information, interfaces, and tools to help our vibrant ecosystem of partners integrate their products
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/new-developer-resource-page-for-microsoft-365-interoperability-and-data-portability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does &lt;code&gt;SHFormat­Date­Time&lt;/code&gt; take an unaligned &lt;code&gt;FILETIME&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I noted some time ago Windows requires that pointers be aligned unless explicitly permitted to be unaligned. I gave as an example of a function that explicitly permits unaligned po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251103-00/?p=111753 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Growth: Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accelerate Your Growth: Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program Unlock 360° Success with the Cosmos DB Engineering Team Are you ready to elevate your cloud data practice and drive innovation for your customers? The Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program—spearheaded by the Cosmos DB Engineering
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/accelerate-your-growth-azure-cosmos-db-partner-acceleration-program 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Universe demo: From prompt to production with VS Code, GitHub Copilot and the Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At this year’s GitHub Universe, we set out to answer a simple question: What would it take to go from an idea to production in under 30 minutes – using only natural language, your editor, and AI? On stage, we built a cloud-native, intelligent app from scratch using
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/behind-the-universe-demo-with-vs-code-copilot-and-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💫 Welcome to Aspire: Your stack, streamlined</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a new chapter for Aspire and a new home at aspire.dev. What started two years ago as an experiment to simplify distributed app development has become a thriving, community-driven, extensible, code-first pl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspirepolyglot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-region Expansion for Azure Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why Financial Services Organizations Should Consider Expanding to Other Azure Regions for New Workloads As a Cloud Architect, I work closely with financial services organizations to help them unlock the full potential of Azure innovations. One of the most impactful strategies I r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/multi-region-expansion-for-azure-deployments 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Team at CppCon 2025: Trip Report</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Another year and another CppCon is all wrapped up! Microsoft was pleased to once again be an exhibitor and to have several of our employees present sessions at the conference. Here are my major takeaways from the keynotes, sessions, conversations, and the general vibe. AI tooling is finding a footing with the C++ community. The ne
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/cppcon2025-trip-report 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at .NET Conf: Dive into the future of development with Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to invite you to one of the most exciting events in the .NET ecosystem: .NET Conf. It runs from November 11th through the 13th and you’re invited! This annual virtual conference is a must-attend for developers, architects, and enthusiasts looking t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/join-us-at-net-conf-dive-into-the-future-of-development-with-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: turn into a pumpkin</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The English idiom turn into a pumpkin comes from the fairy tale story of Cinderella, in which the protagonist&#39;s ragged clothes are magically transformed into an elegant gown and a pumpkin is transformed into a carriage, allowing her to attend a royal ball. She is warned that the magic wears off at midnight, upon which her clot
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251031-00/?p=111750 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning and Optimization of Speech-to-Text (STT), Text-to-Speech (TTS), and Custom Keyword Recognition in Azure Speech Services</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_10_2025/31_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Optimizing Speech-to-Text (STT) and Text-to-Speech (TTS) is essential for developers building voice-enabled applications, as it enhances recognition accuracy and overall user experience. Additionally, custom keyword recognition enables hands-free activation for voice assistants. This blog outlines: Method
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/azure-speech-to-text-optimization 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failures Happen in Cloud, but how Azure Cosmos DB keeps your Applications Online</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The only thing that’s constant in distributed systems is failures. No cloud platform is immune to failures — from regional outages and transient network blips to human errors or hardware faults. What defines resiliency &amp;amp; reliability isn’t the absence of failure, but how systems anticipate, isolate, and recover from them. Here is a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/failures-happen-in-cloud-but-how-azure-cosmos-db-keeps-your-applications-online 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the azd extension to configure GitHub Copilot coding agent integration with Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This new azd extension makes it easy to use the GitHub Copilot coding agent with Azure Want Copilot to help you build apps in the cloud? This tool does all the boring setup work for you. Instead of spending hours figuring out permissions and security, you can get Copilot coding agent connected to your cloud resources i
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-copilot-coding-agent-config 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading C&#43;&#43; Projects to Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With Visual Studio 2026 version 18.0 getting closer to General Availability (GA), we want to share with you how you can upgrade your projects from your current versions of Visual Studio and the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools to the latest versions.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/upgrading-c-projects-to-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to build a XAML tree in code throws a &#34;No installed components were detected&#34; exception</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You might, for some reason, be building some XAML in code rather than markup. Starting with this XAML: &amp;lt;Grid.ColumnDefinitions&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Grid.ColumnDefinitions&amp;gt; Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251030-00/?p=111746 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to be humbled by the incredible momentum of SharePoint Framework (SPFx) and the growth it is driving with our customers and partners. There are tens of millions of users across the world using custom SPFx solutions on a daily basis in Microsoft 365 – built by our customers and pa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio October Update – new models, memories, planning, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The October 2025 update for Visual Studio 2022 (v17.14) is now available. In this month, we are bringing you improvements to model choices, agentic flows, and chat thread management.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-october-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v1.3 with exporting to HAR, LLM usage tracking, and enhanced permissions analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_10_2025/30_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the release of Dev Proxy v1.3.0! This update introduces two powerful new plugins: HAR file generation for universal debugging and LLM usage tracking for cost optimization, along with enhanced permissions analysis and improved OpenAPI spec generation for complex testing scenarios. In this version: New
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v1-3-with-exporting-to-har-llm-usage-tracking-and-enhanced-permissions-analysis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java OpenJDK October 2025 Patch &amp; Security Update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 21:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Hello Java customers! We are happy to announce the latest July 2025 patch &amp;amp; security update release for the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK. Download and install the binaries today. OpenJDK 25.0.1 OpenJDK 21.0.9 OpenJDK 17.0.17 OpenJDK 11.0.29
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-openjdk-oct-2025-patch-security-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from IDCRL authentication to modern authentication in SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the next few months, Microsoft will be removing the legacy authentication protocol known as IDCRL (Identity Client Run Time Library) in SharePoint and force calls to rely on OpenID connect and OAuth Protocols. Since 2018, regular sign-in for services such as OneDrive and SharePoint has always relied on the more secure OpenID Connect and OAu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/migrating-from-idcrl-authentication-to-modern-authentication-in-sharepoint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put your AI to the Test with Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, but it also introduces new challenges: how do you know if your AI application is giving the right answers and producing the right outcomes? Evaluations (often referred to simply as ‘evals’) provide a structured way to measure quality so you can trust your results. In this blog, we’ll introduce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/put-your-ai-to-the-test-with-microsoft-extensions-ai-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GitHub Copilot capabilities for C&#43;&#43; developers: Upgrade MSVC, improve build performance, and refactor C&#43;&#43; code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot;]GitHub Copilot app modernization for C++, GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows, and C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot will be available soon in Private Preview. Join the waitlist for Private Preview today.[/alert] Yesterday at GitHub Universe, Gi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-github-copilot-capabilities-for-c-developers-upgrade-msvc-improve-build-performance-and-refactor-c-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of the previewImageUrl property for Insights items that reference file attachments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re deprecating the previewImageUrl property in the resourceVisualization complex type for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-the-previewimageurl-property-for-insights-items-that-reference-file-attachments 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when you have a crash in the runtime control flow guard check</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows Control Flow Guard (CFG) is a defense in depth feature which validates indirect call targets. The idea is that each module that is enabled for CFG provides a bitmap that describes which addresses in the module are intended to be targets of indirect calls. When CFG is enabled in a process, indirect function calls are checked against
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251029-00/?p=111738 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Custom Agents for .NET Developers: C# Expert &amp; WinForms Expert</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With GitHub’s announcement of Copilot Custom Agents, developers now have powerful new tools to automate and accelerate their workflows. These custom agents enhance Copilot by serving as intelligent accelerators with specialized expertise, able to analyze codebases, plan tasks, and execu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-custom-agents-for-dotnet-developers-csharp-expert-winforms-expert 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure MCP Server 1.0.0 Stable Release – A New Era for Agentic Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re not just shipping software, we’re opening the door to a new era of cloud automation and AI-powered development. Azure MCP server 1.0 is now officially available as a stable release! If you’re a developer, an AI enthusiast, or just someone who loves seeing what’s possible when cloud a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-azure-mcp-server-stable-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java and AI for Beginners: a practical video series for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-and-ai-for-beginners-a-practical-video-series-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls for Copilot in JetBrains and Eclipse Now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP registry and allowlist controls for GitHub Copilot in JetBrains IDEs and Eclipse are now available in public preview in nightly/pre-release builds.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/mcp-registry-and-allowlist-controls-for-copilot-in-jetbrains-and-eclipse-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls Now Available in GitHub Copilot for Xcode (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls in GitHub Copilot for Xcode are now available in public preview in pre-release builds. These capabilities help Xcode developers discover, install, and manage Model Context Protocol (MCP)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/mcp-registry-and-allowlist-controls-now-available-in-github-copilot-for-xcode-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Backup to Discovery: Veeam’s Search Engine Powered by Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was co-authored by Zack Rossman, Staff Software Engineer, Veeam; Ashlie Martinez, Staff Software Engineer, Veeam; and James Nguyen, Senior Principal Cloud Solution Architect, AI/ML, Microsoft. Don&#39;t miss: Hear all about about Veeam&#39;s AI-powered semantic search use case and architecture setup
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/from-backup-to-discovery-veeams-search-engine-powered-by-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did the Windows 95 user interface code get brought to the Windows NT code base?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A long time ago, somebody asked, &amp;quot;How did the new Windows 95 user interface get brought to the Windows NT code base? The development of Windows 95 lined up with the endgame of Windows NT 3.1, so how did the finished Windows 95 code get brought to the Windows NT code base for Windows NT 4.0? Did they reimplement it based on the existing spec
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251028-00/?p=111733 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
