<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:54:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build like Microsoft: Developer agents in action</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Take a deep dive into Athena, an AI-powered collaborative agent, to learn how it was built and how to create your own version of Athena right within Microsoft Teams.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/build-like-microsoft-developer-agents-in-action 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riffing on a typo in the name of the opera Turandot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On the dot.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250604-01/?p=111247 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I programmatically find the network path by which a folder has been shared?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_06_2025/04_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            There is no direct query. You&#39;ll have to infer it.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250604-00/?p=111245 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Conversational Agents with Azure AI Language Conversational Language Understanding and Custom Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 22:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As we focus our work on empowering the agent design experience, a list of the new features in the we published earlier this week, including the intent triage agent and the exact question-answering agent, utilizing Conversational language understanding (CLU) and Custom question answering (CQA). We’re excited to share new enhancements to the customization experiences in CLU and CQA […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/enhancing-conversational-agents-with-azure-ai-language-conversational-language-understanding-and-custom-question-answering 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Foundry with .NET MAUI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Using AI Foundry with .NET MAUI brings the power of LLMs to mobile and desktop applications.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/using-ai-foundry-with-dotnet-maui 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (May 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 16:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure SDK releases every month. In this post, you&#39;ll find this month&#39;s highlights and release notes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-may-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Academy: Unlock Your Azure Skills and Accelerate Your Career</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we launched the Cloud Academy benefit for Visual Studio Professional and Enterprise subscribers back in March 2025, our goal was simple: give you the hands-on, practical learning experience you need to confidently master Azure and cloud technologies — without spending a dime beyond your subscription. Why? Because in today’s fast-changing tech world, knowing theory […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/cloud-academy-benefit-for-visual-studio-subscribers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The symbolism of the magnifying glass is not universal</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_06_2025/03_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Just making things bigger?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250603-00/?p=111240 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A story of collaborating agents: chatting with your database the right way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 18:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, more and more customers are embracing AI with one clear goal in mind: they want to chat with their data. And by “data,” they mean all of it: structured tables, unstructured documents, images, audio, and more. This demand has given rise to hybrid approaches that blend semantic understanding with precise data retrieval. But here’s […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/a-story-of-collaborating-agents-chatting-with-your-database-the-right-way 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension Manager updates in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 18:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest updates in Visual Studio 2022 introduced features specifically designed to improve how you manage extensions. These updates offer tools that help you automate processes, provide detailed controls for configuration, and enhance the user interface to streamline your development workflows. Seamless auto updates Visual Studio now automatically triggers updates whenever you open the Extension […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/extension-manager-updates-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3D12 Cooperative Vector</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the preview release for Cooperative Vector support in D3D12. This exposes powerful new hardware acceleration for vector and matrix operations, enabling developers to efficiently drive neural rendering techniques directly from individual shader threads in real-time graphics pipelines. In research and in industry, machine learning based approaches have made their way to mainstream, replacing/augmenting […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/cooperative-vector 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Secret Protection and GitHub Code Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 14:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Following the changes to GitHub Advanced Security on GitHub, we’re launching the standalone security products of GitHub Secret Protection and GitHub Code Security for Azure DevOps today. You can bring the protection of Advanced Security to your enterprise with the flexibility to enable the right level of protection for your repositories. GitHub Secret Protection for […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/github-secret-protection-and-github-code-security-for-azure-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stating the obvious about debugging an invalid parameter error when freeing memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_06_2025/02_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing it down for posterity.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250602-00/?p=111236 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Real-Time Messaging at Scale with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Teams, Copilot, Azure Communication Services and many other product offerings from Microsoft, rely on a unified messaging platform that powers real-time communication and collaboration at an unprecedented scale. This messaging platform has become critical for enabling boundary-less collaboration, supporting hundreds of millions of users worldwide. To ensure global discovery, durable storage and performance needed […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/powering-real-time-messaging-at-scale-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3D12 Opacity Micromaps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            DirectX Raytracing (DXR) now supports Opacity Micromaps (OMMs), enabling hardware to handle alpha tested geometry more efficiently than relying only on costly AnyHit shader invocations. At GDC 2025 DXR 1.2 was announced including OMMs, and you can see it discussed in this: GDC DirectX State Of The Union YouTube Recording. In the video, Remedy showed […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/omm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3D12 Shader Execution Reordering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Shader Execution Reordering (SER) is an addition to DirectX Raytracing that enables application shader code inform hardware how to find coherency across rays so they can be sorted to execute better in parallel. At GDC 2025 DXR 1.2 was announced including SER, and you can see it discussed in this: GDC DirectX State Of The […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/ser 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2505.30 and 2505.30-preview: support for DXR 1.2, Cooperative Vectors and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released two new versions of PIX, which can be downloaded here. These complement the new D3D12 Agility SDKs released today. The new versions of PIX are: PIX 2505.30 – supports the new retail D3D12 features released today in Agility SDK 1.616, including: Opacity Micromaps (OMMs) Tiled Resources Tier 4 PIX 2505.30-preview – supports the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2505-30-and-2505-30-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agility SDK 1.717-preview and 1.616-retail</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 16:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are pleased to announce both a retail and preview Agility SDK release with several new features, available on Agility SDK Downloads today! As usual, the features in this release come with Day One PIX support. Please read the PIX blog post for more information. Agility SDK 1.717-preview features Cooperative Vectors unlocks powerful new hardware acceleration for vector […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/agility-sdk-1-717-preview-and-1-616-retail 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an oracle to see where your code is producing the wrong output</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If there is a reference implementation, then use it as a check.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250530-00/?p=111232 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Semantic Kernel: A Commitment to Innovation and Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel is Microsoft’s core framework for enterprise AI orchestration, remaining secure, stable, and rapidly evolving with unified multi-agent support and deep Azure integration, backed by ongoing investment and a clear long-term roadmap.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/semantic-kernel-commitment-ai-innovation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Ground Truth Generation for Search Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_05_2025/30_05_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article discusses the challenges and methodologies for creating a reliable groundtruth dataset for search evaluation. It highlights the use of TREC Pooling and GPT-4o assisted ranking to overcome the labor-intensive process of manual labeling, ensuring high-quality search evaluations even with limited data.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/efficient-ground-truth-generation-search-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go from prompt to playback with Sora from Azure OpenAI in the video playground in Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 20:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The video playground in Azure AI Foundry is a high-fidelity testbed for prototyping with cutting-edge video generation models like Sora from Azure OpenAI. It offers a controlled environment for developers to experiment with prompt structures, evaluate model consistency, and optimize outputs for industry use cases.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/sora-in-video-playground 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SQL Cryptozoology AI Embeddings Lab Now Available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Missed out on MS Build 2025? No worries! Our lab is now available for your exploration. Dive into a unique cryptozoology experience using Azure SQL and Azure AI to uncover intriguing (and true) connections among cryptids worldwide. Curious about who would reign supreme in a battle royal or which regions of the world hold the […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/azure-sql-cryptozoology-ai-embeddings-lab-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic DevOps in action: Reimagining every phase of the developer lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 19:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What if your dev tools could take the first pass at a feature, file a bug report, propose a fix—and deploy it? With Agentic DevOps and GitHub Copilot, they can. Here&#39;s how agents will reshape every step of the software development lifecycle.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/reimagining-every-phase-of-the-developer-lifecycle 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Support Public Preview now extended to Azure SQL MI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 17:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are thrilled to announce that Azure SQL Managed Instance now supports Vector type and functions in public preview. This builds on the momentum from Azure SQL Database, where vector support has been in public preview since December. Check out the detailed announcement 💡 Why Choose Azure SQL Managed Instance for AI-Driven Modernization? Effortless Cloud […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/4561-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tune the volume of logs your app produces</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Explores the new log sampling feature
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/finetune-the-volume-of-logs-your-app-produces 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Multi-Agent AI Apps in Java with Spring AI and Azure Cosmos DB!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As AI-driven apps become more sophisticated, there’s an increasing need for them to mimic collaborative problem solving – like a team of domain experts working together. Multi-agent apps offer exactly that: collections of specialized agents that cooperate to handle complex tasks. But to make them production-grade, you need more than just clever prompts – you […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-multi-agent-ai-apps-in-java-with-spring-ai-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of creating new instances when you wanted to use the same one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_05_2025/29_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            C++ language backward compatibility makes legal what you had hoped wasn&#39;t.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250529-00/?p=111228 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code quicker with Azure AI Foundry playgrounds and Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 19:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The &amp;quot;Open in VS Code&amp;quot; workflow, part of the Azure AI Foundry extension for Visual Studio Code, accelerates developer velocity by integrating agent or model API endpoints and code samples into a new workspace in VS Code for Web. This feature streamlines the development process, enabling rapid prototyping and deployment with just one click.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/open-in-vscode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB TV – Everything New in Azure Cosmos DB from Microsoft Build 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 17:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Build 2025 brought major innovations to Azure Cosmos DB, and in Episode 105 of Azure Cosmos DB TV, Principal Program Manager Mark Brown sits down with Kirill Gavrylyuk, Vice President and GM of Azure Cosmos DB, to break it all down. Whether you’re developing AI-native apps, building with MongoDB, or just looking for better […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-tv-everything-new-in-azure-cosmos-db-from-microsoft-build-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing dotnet run app.cs – A simpler way to start with C# and .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are super excited to introduce a new feature that was released as part of .NET 10 Preview 4 that makes getting started with C# easier than ever. You can now run a C# file directly using dotnet run app.cs. This means you no longer need to create a project file or scaffold a whole […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-run-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the commands in your extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 15:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As Visual Studio extension authors, our goal is to create tools that empower developers across diverse environments. A key part of this mission involves ensuring that your extension commands remain accessible and consistent across all Visual Studio locales. In your VSSDK extensions, by adding the CanonicalName property to your commands in the .vsct file, you […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/improve-the-commands-in-your-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DocumentDB Local – MongoDB API on Your Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 15:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction DocumentDB Local provides a lightweight, containerized environment that lets you develop and test applications locally using a MongoDB-compatible interface. It’s ideal for prototyping or running integration tests without needing a cloud setup. When paired with the DocumentDB Extension for Visual Studio Code, it creates a focused and consistent local development environment. DocumentDB Local is […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/documentdb-local-mongodb-api-on-your-machine 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I convert a WIC bitmap back to a GDI HBITMAP?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            You can copy the bits into a DIB section.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250528-00/?p=111225 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel and Microsoft.Extensions.AI: Better Together, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 13:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_05_2025/28_05_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This is Part 2 of our series on integrating Microsoft.Extensions.AI with Semantic Kernel. In Part 1, we explored the relationship between these technologies and how they complement each other. Now, let’s dive into practical examples showing how to use Microsoft.Extensions.AI abstractions with Semantic Kernel in non-agent scenarios. Getting Started with Microsoft.Extensions.AI and Semantic Kernel Before we […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-and-microsoft-extensions-ai-better-together-part-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
