<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The OS for Intelligence: How GitHub Bridges the Fragmented AI Landscape</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are currently living through the &amp;quot;fragmentation phase&amp;quot; of the AI revolution. If you’re a developer, you know the drill: You have
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/the-os-for-intelligence-how-github-bridges-the-fragmented-ai-landscape 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Bowl LX creates an opportunity for symphonic friendly wagering</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This upcoming Sunday is Super Bowl LX, the championship game of the top professional American football league. The Super Bowl thinks that it is so important that it uses Roman numerals.) The Super Bowl is the single largest sporting event in the United States.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260204-01/?p=112039 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I prevent the user from changing the widths of ListView columns?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_02_2026/04_02_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Suppose you are using a Win32 ListView control in report mode, and you&#39;ve got all your columns set up perfectly, and you don&#39;t want the user to resize them. How do you do that? There is no ListView style for preventing column resize, but there is a header control style to prevent sizing: HDS_NOSIZING. This style
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260204-00/?p=112037 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation notice: Teams Live Events meeting creation via Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re announcing an important change for developers using Microsoft Graph APIs to create Teams Live Events. Starting March 31, 2026, the beta endpoint will no longer support the isBroadcast property of the on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-notice-teams-live-events-meeting-creation-via-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Building a Python CRUD API with Azure Functions and Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Series: Building Serverless Applications with Azure Functions and Azure Cosmos DB In the first post of this series, we focused on establishing the fundamentals of serverless architectur
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/part-2-building-a-python-crud-api-with-azure-functions-and-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance improvements to MEF-based editor productivity extensions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you use editor productivity extensions for Visual Studio 2026, there&#39;s good news—they can now load faster! Extension developers with existing MEF-based editor productivity extensions should read this blog to learn about recent changes and how they might be affected.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/performance-improvements-to-mef-based-editor-productivity-extensions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some small stories about the giant satellite dish antenna that was behind Microsoft Building 11</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_02_2026/03_02_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Back in the day, if you wandered into the parking area behind Building 11 on the original Redmond Microsoft campus, you would find a very large satellite dish antenna. This antenna was used for receiving video signals, such as cable television feeds for distribution to the Redmond campus. One purpose was to provide cable TV service for inte
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260203-00/?p=112035 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer now supports Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 20:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you spend time in the Azure Portal’s using Azure Cosmos DB Data Explorer, you know it’s a “lots of screens, lots of tabs, lots of work happening” kind of place. So I’m excited to share a small upgrade that makes a big difference: Dark Mode is now supported in Cosmos DB Data Explorer.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-data-explorer-now-supports-dark-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying compiler error messages closely: Input file paths</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_02_2026/02_02_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague was working in a project that used a number of data files to configure how the program worked. They wanted one portion of the configuration file to be included only if a particular build flag was set. Let&#39;s say that the configuration file is C:\repos\contoso\config\Contoso.config. &amp;amp;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260202-00/?p=112027 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build AI Agents with Claude Agent SDK and Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Agent Framework now integrates with the Claude Agent SDK, enabling you to build AI agents powered by Claude&#39;s full agentic capabilities. This integration brings together the Agent Framework&#39;s consistent agent abstraction with Claude&#39;s powerful features, including fil
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/build-ai-agents-with-claude-agent-sdk-and-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why not store the &lt;code&gt;SAFEARRAY&lt;/code&gt; reference count as a hidden allocation next to the &lt;code&gt;SAFEARRAY&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When I described how Safe­Array­Add­Ref keeps its reference count in a side table, commenter Koro Unhallowed wondered
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260130-00/?p=112025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - January 2026: Configuration &amp; Performance</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_01_2026/30_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the round up of the azd releases in January 2026! This blog post (covers release versions 1.23.0, 1.23.1,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-january-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (January 2026)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-january-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Cosmos DB TV Recap - From Burger to Bots – Agentic Apps with Cosmos DB and LangChain.js | Ep. 111</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In Episode 111 of Azure Cosmos DB TV, host Mark Brown is joined by Yohan Lasorsa to explore how developers can build agent-powered applications using a fully serverless architecture. This episode focuses on a practical, end-to-end exa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-tv-recap-from-burger-to-bots-agentic-apps-with-cosmos-db-and-langchain-js-ep-111 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I retain access to the data in a &lt;code&gt;SAFEARRAY&lt;/code&gt; after my method returns?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The original problem our customer had was that the data in a SAFEARRAY disappeared even though they had called Safe­Array­Add­Ref. We learned why this is the case,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260129-00/?p=112023 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v2.1 with configuration hot reload and stdio proxying</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_01_2026/29_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce the release of Dev Proxy v2.1.0! This release brings two major productivity features that developers have been asking for: automatic configuration hot reload and stdio traffic proxying - perfect for testing MCP servers and other stdio-based tools. In this version:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v2-1-with-configuration-hot-reload-and-stdio-proxying 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Microsoft Graph User Configuration API (preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the public preview of the User Configuration API in the Microsoft Graph beta endpoint. The User Configuration API is a new set of endpoints that you can use to create, read, update, and delete user configuration objects in Exchange Online mail folders. User configuration objects—also
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-the-microsoft-graph-user-configuration-api-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing instability in production-scale agent reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            On January 28, 2026, Hugging Face announced that they have upstreamed the Post-Training Toolkit into TRL as a first-party integration, making these diagnostics directly usable in production RL and agent post-training pipelines. This enables closed-loop monitoring and control patterns that are increasingly necessary for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/engineering-at-microsoft/diagnosing-instability-in-production-scale-agent-rl 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Cosmos DB Infrastructure with GitHub Copilot CLI and Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Modern infrastructure work is increasingly agent driven, but only if your AI actually understands the platform you’re deploying. This guide shows how to turn GitHub Copilot CLI into an Azure Cosmos DB aware infrastructure expert by loading the Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit. In under a minute, you’ll give Copil
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/accelerate-your-cosmos-db-infrastructure-with-github-copilot-cli-and-azure-cosmos-db-agent-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET AI Essentials - The Core Building Blocks Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming how we build applications. The .NET team has prioritized keeping pace with the rapid changes in generative AI and continue to provide tools, libraries, and guidance for .NET developers building intelligent apps. With .NET, developers have a powerful ecosystem to integrate AI seamlessly into their ap
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-ai-essentials-the-core-building-blocks-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – January 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We enter 2026 with the SharePoint Framework stronger than ever. Adoption has expanded, feedback has sharpened our priorities, and the platform continues to power intelligent and scalable experiences across Microsoft 365. December marked an important milestone with the release of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-january-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I lose the data even though I called &lt;code&gt;Safe­Array­Add­Ref&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_01_2026/28_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer had a method that received a SAFEARRAY, and they called Safe­Array­Add­Ref to add a reference to it so that they could continue using the array after the method returned, but they found that if they tried to use the array later, the safearray-&amp;gt;pData was NULL, and if they c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260128-00/?p=112021 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
