<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 22:30:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Model Context Protocol (MCP) in Azure AI Foundry: Create an MCP Server with Azure AI Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 22:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how to integrate Azure AI Foundry&#39;s Agent Service with Claude Desktop using the Model Context Protocol (MCP) for powerful integration for MCP clients.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/integrating-azure-ai-agents-mcp 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removal of Deprecated SharePoint &amp; OneDrive Permission Resource Properties</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are announcing the phased rollout of an update to remove the grantedTo and grantedToIdentities properties from the Permission resource type in Microsoft Graph.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/removal-of-deprecated-sharepoint-onedrive-permission-resource-properties 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the critical section that let multiple threads enter a block of code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            It had one job.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250321-00/?p=110984 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign Up for the free Pure Virtual C&#43;&#43; 2025 Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 11:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Every year we run Pure Virtual C++: a free one-day virtual conference for the whole C++ community. Next month we’re doing it again! Sign-up for free to get access to our five live sessions and a host of pre-conference content. The live event will start at April 30th 14:00 UTC. Videos will be available to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/sign-up-for-the-free-pure-virtual-c-2025-conference 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Azure AI Foundry Blog!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introducing the Azure AI Foundry Blog—your essential guide to building, customizing, and scaling AI solutions with Microsoft’s open and modular AI platform.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/welcome-to-azure-ai-foundry-blog 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Java, JS and Python support in Test Plans</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce new capabilities in Azure Test Plans that will enhance your testing workflows. This feature is currently available in Public Preview. You can find instructions at the end of the article on how to request it for your Azure DevOps project. With this latest release, we are introducing the ability to […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/introducing-java-javascript-and-python-support-in-azuredevops-test-plans 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>引入对SLNX的支持，.NET CLI 中更简洁的解决方案文件格式</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_03_2025/21_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            本文翻译自Chet Husk的Introducing support for SLNX, a new, simpler solution file format in the .NET CLI 多年来，解决方案文件已成为 .NET 和 Visual Studio 体验中的一部分，并且它们一直拥有相同的自定义格式。最近，Visual Studio 解决方案团队已开始预览一种新的基于 XML 格式的解决方案文件格式，称为 SLNX。从 .NET SDK 9.0.200 开始，dotnet CLI 支持生成这些文件并与之交互，其方式与使用现有解决方案文件的方式相同。在本文的其余部分，我们将展示如何迁移到新格式，探索 dotnet CLI 对该格式的新支持，并讨论该格式走向正式发布的后续计划。 快速开始 在 SDK 9.0.200 之前，创建 SLNX 文件的唯一方式是通过 Visual Studio 设置。勾选 环境 &amp;gt; 预览功能 &amp;gt; 使用解决方案文件持久性模型 设置后，用户可以将现有的 .sln 文件另存为新的 .slnx 格式。 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet-ch/%e5%bc%95%e5%85%a5%e5%af%b9slnx%e7%9a%84%e6%94%af%e6%8c%81%ef%bc%8c-net-cli-%e4%b8%ad%e6%9b%b4%e7%ae%80%e6%b4%81%e7%9a%84%e8%a7%a3%e5%86%b3%e6%96%b9%e6%a1%88%e6%96%87%e4%bb%b6%e6%a0%bc%e5%bc%8f 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing DirectX Raytracing 1.2, PIX, Neural Rendering and more at GDC 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 21:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today in the DirectX State of the Union at GDC 2025, we proudly showcased the next evolution in graphics with the announcement of DirectX Raytracing (DXR) 1.2. This update promises groundbreaking performance improvements and breathtaking visual fidelity, marking another milestone in our mission to deliver immersive, realistic experiences to gamers everywhere. We also brought developers […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/directx/announcing-directx-raytracing-1-2-pix-neural-rendering-and-more-at-gdc-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Box roadmap update</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What features and enhancements are planned for Microsoft Dev Box Microsoft Dev Box continues to evolve, providing a secure, scalable, and ready-to-code cloud-based development environment. Over the next few months, significant improvements will focus on three key areas: Ready-to-code environments: Faster setup, enhanced debugging, and GitHub Copilot integration to streamline developer workflows. Developers will benefit […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/microsoft-dev-box-roadmap-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Certification control spotlight: Data at rest</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Read how Microsoft 365 Certification ensures compliance for data at rest.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-certification-control-spotlight-data-at-rest 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enforcement of license checks for PSTN Bot calls</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of Microsoft’s feature parity with Teams Phone extensibility, we’re announcing the enforcement of Phone System license checks for Bot-initiated transfers to Teams users. This current gap in our systems will be addressed in June 2025. Microsoft Teams requires that Teams users behind applications such as queue applications require a phone system license and […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/enforcement-of-license-checks-for-pstn-bot-calls 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Pull Request Reviews with In-Depth Feedback</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Visual Studio 2022 has taken the pull request experience to the next level by making reviews interactive. We previously enabled viewing your pull request comments inline in your working files. Now, the latest update empowers you to add comments directly within the IDE, streamlining the review process. Now, pull request reviewers can conduct deep reviews […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/enhance-pull-request-reviews-with-in-depth-feedback 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could cause a memory corruption bug to disappear in safe mode?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A simplified execution environment means fewer things that you can stumble over.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250320-00/?p=110981 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Risks of Docker Build Time Arguments and How to Secure Your Secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_03_2025/20_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post discusses the security risks of using Docker build-time arguments to pass secrets, and suggests alternative methods for handling secrets securely.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/hidden-risks-of-docker-build-time-arguments-and-how-to-secure-your-secrets 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Dynamic Debugging: Full Debuggability for Optimized Builds</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Over the past 5 years, we’ve had many incredible opportunities to engage with game developers. From AAA studios to indie developers, the passion for slashing iteration times is significant. Amidst all the fantastic feedback we’ve received for Visual Studio, one sentiment has rung loud and clear: a desire to debug optimized C++ code without sacrificing […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/cpp-dynamic-debugging-full-debuggability-for-optimized-builds 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Developer Tools with Authentication Brokers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you’ve used any applications that required connecting your personal Microsoft or Entra ID account, you’re probably familiar with the typical “authentication dance” – you see a browser window pop up, you enter your credentials, then you can close the browser, and the application is magically authenticated. The next application you launch does the same […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//securing-developer-tools-with-authentication-brokers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSTest 3.8: Top 10 features to supercharge your .NET tests!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MSTest 3.8 is here! It&#39;s built on your feedback and packed with powerful new features to simplify and smooth your testing experience.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/mstest-3-8-highlights 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find the IDE features you need with GitHub Copilot and Search</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever find yourself needing to locate a specific menu item, command, or option in Visual Studio, but you don’t know its name or location? Do you often struggle to find detailed instructions on using certain features effectively? Now, there’s a solution to get you the information you need right in the IDE. Visual Studio now […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/find-the-ide-features-you-need-with-github-copilot-and-search 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Search with Azure SQL, Semantic Kernel and Entity Framework Core</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Vector databases like Qdrant and Milvus are specifically designed to efficiently store, manage, and retrieve embeddings. However, many applications already use relational databases like SQL Server or SQL Azure. In such cases, installing and managing another database can be challenging, especially since these vector databases may not offer all the features of a modern relational […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vector-search-with-azure-sql-semantic-kernel-and-entity-framework-core 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can’t simulate keyboard input with PostMessage, revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If it didn&#39;t go through the input system, it only looks like input as much as the app allows itself to be fooled.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250319-00/?p=110979 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Agentic Workflows with NVIDIA AgentIQ, Azure AI Foundry and Semantic Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 03:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_03_2025/19_03_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to announce our collaboration with NVIDIA. In Azure AI Foundry, we’ve integrated NVIDIA NIM microservices and the NVIDIA AgentIQ toolkit into Azure AI Foundry—unlocking unprecedented efficiency, performance, and cost optimization for your AI projects. Read more on the announcement here. Optimizing performance with NVIDIA AgentIQ and Semantic Kernel Once your NVIDIA NIM […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/accelerating-agentic-workflows-with-nvidia-agentiq-azure-ai-foundry-and-semantic-kernel 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Streamlit application with Fabric SQL Database</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building an application allows you to operationalize the data you have in Microsoft Fabric, such that it can be consumed by stakeholders in your organization to generate business insights. Streamlit is easy to use to build simple applications without needing to know front-end application frameworks like Flask, Django etc. It makes it easier to prototype […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-a-streamlit-application-with-fabric-sql-database 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Updates for Azure Pipelines Agents Images</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            To ensure our hosted agents in Azure Pipelines are operating in the most secure and up-to-date environments, we continuously update the supported images and phase out older ones. In October 2024, we announced support for Ubuntu-24.04. Soon, we plan to update the ubuntu-latest image to map to Ubuntu-24.04. Additionally, MacOS 15 Sequoia and Windows 2025 […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/upcoming-updates-for-azure-pipelines-agents-images 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10 Preview 2 is now available!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Find out about the new features in .NET 10 Preview 2 across the .NET runtime, SDK, libraries, ASP.NET Core, Blazor, C#, .NET MAUI, and more!
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-preview-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your GitHub productivity with our new multi-account support!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Managing your GitHub identity in Visual Studio 2022 just got easier! Our latest update overhauls the GitHub account management experience and improves how you work with multiple accounts, especially for GitHub Copilot and version control scenarios. In this post, we’ll detail how these changes will make your GitHub workflow smoother, from the moment you start […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/boost-your-github-productivity-with-our-new-multi-account-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why didn’t Windows 95 setup use a miniature version of Windows 95 as its fallback GUI?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Avoiding an interim GUI environment.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250318-00/?p=110975 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Build Times with Build Insights: How Activision Cut Call of Duty’s Build Time by 50%</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Slow build times are a major headache for developers, especially in large, complex C++ codebases like game engines. Every minute spent waiting on a build is time that could be used to refine features, resolve issues, or push development forward. Activision faced this challenge with Call of Duty: Modern Warfare II, where prolonged build times […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/optimizing-build-times-with-build-insights-how-activision-cut-call-of-dutys-build-time-by-50 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of OpenID Connect external identity provider support for Microsoft Entra External ID</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Discover the new OpenID Connect identity provider support in Microsoft Entra External ID, now generally available. Simplify user sign-in and partner integrations, and improve conversion rates and user satisfaction by federating with external identity providers like Okta, Amazon, Auth0, and Azure AD B2C.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/identity/openid-connect-external-identity-provider-support-ga 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Zero Trust: Never Trust, Always Verify</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft’s 2024 Digital Defense Report found that between July 2023 and July 2024, Microsoft customers faced an astounding 600 million attacks daily from both cybercriminals and nation-state actors. space In this high-risk and rapidly evolving environment, individuals and organizations must not only strengthen digital defenses at every level but also foster a deep and enduring […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/embracing-zero-trust-never-trust-always-verify 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Serve Restoration in Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 04:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers grapple with the anxiety of potential data loss due to unforeseen issues, such as accidental deletions, system failures, or even corrupt files. The Dev Box team is addressing this concern with the self-service restoration feature for the Dev Box, designed to put you back in control. This functionality streamlines recovery by allowing direct restorations […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/self-serve-restoration-in-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing ABAP Support in GitHub Copilot for Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 03:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_03_2025/18_03_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The latest release of GitHub Copilot for Eclipse now includes support for ABAP! This update builds on the recent release of code completion and chat integration, offering a robust toolset for developers working within the SAP environment. ABAP remains a critical language in the enterprise space, powering a wide range of business applications, and its […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/introducing-abap-support-in-github-copilot-for-eclipse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLS 1.3 support in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 17:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article follows announcement on a previous article that mentioned the end of support for Transport Security Layer (TLS) 1.0/1.1. TLS 1.3 is the latest version of the internet’s most deployed security protocol, which encrypts data to provide a secure communication channel between two endpoints. Microsoft has implemented updates to enable TLS 1.3 for Azure […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/tls-1-3-support-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing automatic documentation comment generation in Visual Studio</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are excited to announce that Copilot is now automatically integrated into Visual Studio’s editor to help you generate doc comments for functions. This new feature aims to streamline your documentation process and enhance your coding experience. To access these updates, you will need a GitHub Copilot subscription. If you don’t already have GitHub Copilot, […]
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-automatic-documentation-comment-generation-in-visual-studio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: A program does not run correctly if you run it the wrong way</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_03_2025/17_03_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So what did you expect?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250317-00/?p=110970 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
