<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:19:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s New for C&#43;&#43; Developers in Visual Studio 2026 version 18.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Get ready to level up your C++ productivity, because Visual Studio 2026 version 18.0 is now generally available! You can take advantage of the new features, bug fixes, and performance improvements in your production environment.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-for-cpp-developers-in-visual-studio-2026-version-18-0 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire 13 - Aspireify anything</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Major release, major features Aspire 13 is here and it&#39;s - you guessed it - the biggest release yet. We are so excited to share the next major iteration of Aspire with you all, because it&#39;s packed with features that streamline the existing Aspire experience that you all know and love. From complete process overhauls like asp
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/aspire/aspire13 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are releasing patches that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can download the latest versi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/november-patches-for-azure-devops-server-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2026 is here: faster, smarter, and a hit with early adopters</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Dear developers, We’re thrilled to announce that Visual Studio 2026 is now generally available! This is a moment we’ve built side by side with you. Your feedback has helped shape this release more than any before. Since the introduction of the Insiders Channel in September, more developers have downloaded and tested this preview than an
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-2026-is-here-faster-smarter-and-a-hit-with-early-adopters 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we are excited to announce the launch of .NET 10, the most productive, modern, secure, intelligent, and performant release of .NET yet. It&#39;s the result of another year of effort from thousands of developers around the world. This release includes thousands of performance, security, and functional improvements across the entire .NET s
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-10 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework November 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for November 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of November 11, 2025. This update conta
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-november-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes on how Windows 95 application compatibility patched broken programs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/11_11_2025/11_11_2025_18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whenever possible, Windows 95 made application compatibility tweaks through things like compatibility flags that alter the behavior of the system for any program the flag was applied to. Using compatibility flags allows the fix to be generalized: If one program has a problem, there&#39;s a good chance that another program will also have that sa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251111-00/?p=111781 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did Windows 3.1 distinguish two different programs that happened to share the same executable name?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I described the purpose of the icons in the moricons.dll and progman.exe icon libraries, along with a list of which programs Windows automatically associated the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251110-00/?p=111779 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Advanced High Availability Features in Azure Cosmos DB SDKs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/10_11_2025/10_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB is engineered from the ground up to deliver high availability, low latency, throughput, and consistency guarantees for globally distributed applications. As mission-critical systems increasingly rely on Cosmos DB for performance at scale, understanding and configuring advanced high availability feature
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/configuring-advanced-high-availability-features-in-azure-cosmos-db-sdks 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows MIDI Services and the 10-MIDI driver limit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The USB MIDI 1.0 specification was released in the late 90s around the same time that PCs were starting to move from rectangular beige boxes to things like fake-silvered bulbous plastic shapes. At this point, some of the code in Windows to support USB MIDI 1.0 has become intergenerational – it&#39;s certainly older than my teenagers here at h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/windows-midi-services-and-the-10-midi-driver-limit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.4-2 and 1.24.10-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-4-2-and-1-24-10-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelePeer supercharges its agentic AI platform with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reducing latency by 50% and scaling intelligent CX for SMBs This article was co-authored by Sergey Galchenko, Chief Technology Officer, IntelePeer, and Subhash Ramamoorthi, Director, IntelePeer AI Hub. Don’t miss: Discover how IntelePeer enhances agent intelligence and powers their multi-agent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/intelepeer-supercharges-its-agentic-ai-platform-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Restructuring the tree</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been looking at non-recursive algorithms for deleting the nodes of a binary tree. The previous algorithm performed a postorder traversal, cleverly repurposing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251107-00/?p=111774 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns for Building a Scalable Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction LLMs are enabling a new generation of multi-agent systems that tackle complex, multi-step tasks. Moving from prototype to production is hard—especially when orchestrating dozens or hundreds of specialized agents. Commercial viability depends on intentional design, scalability, latency control, and predictable outcomes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/multi-agent-systems-at-scale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Real-Time Analytics to AI: Your Azure Cosmos DB &amp; DocumentDB Agenda for Microsoft Ignite 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2025 is your opportunity to explore how Azure Cosmos DB, Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric, and DocumentDB power the next ge
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmosdb-documentdb-agenda-microsoft-ignite-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting recent MIDI issues in Windows 11 (and Windows 10)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you are on Windows 11 (or Windows 10 for the UAD issue) and recently had either of these two issues, please read on: You use a Universal Audio (UAD) device and found that all or most of your MIDI devices are no longer recognized in your DAW in Windows 11 or Windows 10 You have a new MIDI 2.0 (UMP Data Format – mo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/troubleshooting-recent-midi-issues-in-windows-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Synthesizing the parent pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at a way to delete a binary tree non-recursively, assuming that we had parent pointers. But nodes in a classical binary tree does not remember t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251106-00/?p=111771 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source AI Editor: Second Milestone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ghost text suggestions are now open source as part of the Copilot Chat extension - the second milestone in making VS Code an open source AI editor. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/open-source-ai-editor:-second-milestone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (November)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to share our public roadmap, which outlines the next steps in evolving Visual Studio with AI-powered agentic experiences. With every month, we aim to deliver smarter, faster, and more intuitive tools that enhance your coding experience. Disclaimer: The items outlined here represent ongoing work for the month. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-november 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Copilot Studio uses .NET and WebAssembly for performance and innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot Studio is at the forefront of conversational AI and automation, empowering organizations to build, customize, and manage intelligent copilots and bots for a wide range of enterprise scenarios. As the platform has evolved, so too have the t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/copilot-studio-dotnet-wasm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Traversal with parent pointers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a challenge, a colleague of mine told me to find a non-recursive constant-space algorithm for deleting a binary tree.¹ After a moment&#39;s thought, I was able to come up with an algorithm. It is often the case that solving a problem is easier once you are told that a solution exists. When I asked the Internet for a non-recu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251105-00/?p=111765 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Available: Sort Geospatial Query Results by ST_Distance in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB’s geospatial capabilities just got even better! We&#39;re excited to announce that you can now sort query results by distance using an ORDER BY ST_DISTANCE(...) clause in the NoSQL query language while leveraging a spatial index. [video width=&amp;quot;1920
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-available-sort-geospatial-query-results-by-st_distance-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Advisor for Azure Cosmos DB: Actionable insights to improve performance and cost</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now features Query Advisor, designed to help you write faster and more efficient queries. Whether you’re optimizing for performance, cost, or scalability, Query Advisor provides actionable recommendations to help you get the most out of your data. Why Query Optimization Matters Azure Cosmos DB’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/query-advisor-for-azure-cosmos-db-actionable-insights-to-improve-performance-and-cost 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Experience for all Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents took over VS Code in 2025. We released agent mode for VS Code, integration for the Copilot coding agent, and the new GitHub Copilot CLI. But Copilot is not the only agent game in town. There are now more coding agents than ever, including options from OpenAI and Anthropic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/a-unified-experience-for-all-coding-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
