<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:04:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Windows MIDI Services and the 10-MIDI driver limit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The USB MIDI 1.0 specification was released in the late 90s around the same time that PCs were starting to move from rectangular beige boxes to things like fake-silvered bulbous plastic shapes. At this point, some of the code in Windows to support USB MIDI 1.0 has become intergenerational – it&#39;s certainly older than my teenagers here at h
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/windows-midi-services-and-the-10-midi-driver-limit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.4-2 and 1.24.10-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-4-2-and-1-24-10-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IntelePeer supercharges its agentic AI platform with Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Reducing latency by 50% and scaling intelligent CX for SMBs This article was co-authored by Sergey Galchenko, Chief Technology Officer, IntelePeer, and Subhash Ramamoorthi, Director, IntelePeer AI Hub. Don’t miss: Discover how IntelePeer enhances agent intelligence and powers their multi-agent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/intelepeer-supercharges-its-agentic-ai-platform-with-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Restructuring the tree</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;ve been looking at non-recursive algorithms for deleting the nodes of a binary tree. The previous algorithm performed a postorder traversal, cleverly repurposing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251107-00/?p=111774 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns for Building a Scalable Multi-Agent System</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_11_2025/07_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction LLMs are enabling a new generation of multi-agent systems that tackle complex, multi-step tasks. Moving from prototype to production is hard—especially when orchestrating dozens or hundreds of specialized agents. Commercial viability depends on intentional design, scalability, latency control, and predictable outcomes.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/multi-agent-systems-at-scale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Real-Time Analytics to AI: Your Azure Cosmos DB &amp; DocumentDB Agenda for Microsoft Ignite 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Ignite 2025 is your opportunity to explore how Azure Cosmos DB, Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric, and DocumentDB power the next ge
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmosdb-documentdb-agenda-microsoft-ignite-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting recent MIDI issues in Windows 11 (and Windows 10)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you are on Windows 11 (or Windows 10 for the UAD issue) and recently had either of these two issues, please read on: You use a Universal Audio (UAD) device and found that all or most of your MIDI devices are no longer recognized in your DAW in Windows 11 or Windows 10 You have a new MIDI 2.0 (UMP Data Format – mo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/windows-music-dev/troubleshooting-recent-midi-issues-in-windows-11 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Synthesizing the parent pointer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at a way to delete a binary tree non-recursively, assuming that we had parent pointers. But nodes in a classical binary tree does not remember t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251106-00/?p=111771 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source AI Editor: Second Milestone</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_11_2025/06_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ghost text suggestions are now open source as part of the Copilot Chat extension - the second milestone in making VS Code an open source AI editor. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/open-source-ai-editor:-second-milestone 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (November)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to share our public roadmap, which outlines the next steps in evolving Visual Studio with AI-powered agentic experiences. With every month, we aim to deliver smarter, faster, and more intuitive tools that enhance your coding experience. Disclaimer: The items outlined here represent ongoing work for the month. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-november 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Copilot Studio uses .NET and WebAssembly for performance and innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft Copilot Studio is at the forefront of conversational AI and automation, empowering organizations to build, customize, and manage intelligent copilots and bots for a wide range of enterprise scenarios. As the platform has evolved, so too have the t
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/copilot-studio-dotnet-wasm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-recursively deleting a binary tree in constant space: Traversal with parent pointers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As a challenge, a colleague of mine told me to find a non-recursive constant-space algorithm for deleting a binary tree.¹ After a moment&#39;s thought, I was able to come up with an algorithm. It is often the case that solving a problem is easier once you are told that a solution exists. When I asked the Internet for a non-recu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251105-00/?p=111765 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Available: Sort Geospatial Query Results by ST_Distance in Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB’s geospatial capabilities just got even better! We&#39;re excited to announce that you can now sort query results by distance using an ORDER BY ST_DISTANCE(...) clause in the NoSQL query language while leveraging a spatial index. [video width=&amp;quot;1920
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-available-sort-geospatial-query-results-by-st_distance-in-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Advisor for Azure Cosmos DB: Actionable insights to improve performance and cost</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now features Query Advisor, designed to help you write faster and more efficient queries. Whether you’re optimizing for performance, cost, or scalability, Query Advisor provides actionable recommendations to help you get the most out of your data. Why Query Optimization Matters Azure Cosmos DB’
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/query-advisor-for-azure-cosmos-db-actionable-insights-to-improve-performance-and-cost 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Unified Experience for all Coding Agents</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/05_11_2025/05_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Agents took over VS Code in 2025. We released agent mode for VS Code, integration for the Copilot coding agent, and the new GitHub Copilot CLI. But Copilot is not the only agent game in town. There are now more coding agents than ever, including options from OpenAI and Anthropic.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/a-unified-experience-for-all-coding-agents 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI: Azure Container Apps Dev-to-Prod Deployment with Layered Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post walks through how to implement &amp;quot;build once, deploy everywhere&amp;quot; patterns using Azure Container Apps with the new azd publish and layered infrastructure features in Azure Developer CLI v1.20.0. You&#39;ll learn how to deploy the same containerized application across multiple environments with proper separation of concerns.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-developer-cli-azure-container-apps-dev-to-prod-deployment-with-layered-infrastructure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for .NET Conf 2025!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET Conf 2025 is just one week away! Join us November 11-13 for this free, three-day virtual conference showcasing the latest advancements in the .NET platform, open-source projects, and developer tools - including the official release of .NET 10 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/get-ready-for-dotnet-conf-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JDConf 2026 Is Coming With Modern Solutions for an Agentic World</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Technology is accelerating faster than ever, and developers are once again at the helm, shaping the future of applications, intelligence, and enterprise systems. With the rise of large language models (LLMs), agent-oriented architectures, and AI-driven development paradigms, Java developers find themselves in a uniquely po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/jdconf-2026-is-coming-with-modern-solutions-for-an-agentic-world 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Microsoft SoftCard for the Apple II: Getting two processors to share the same memory</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft Z-80 SoftCard was a plug-in expansion card for the Apple II that added the ability to run CP/M software. According to Wikipedia, it was Microsoft&#39;s first hardware product and in 1980 was the single largest revenue source for the company. CP/M runs on an 8080 pr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251104-00/?p=111758 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powering Distributed AI/ML at Scale with Azure and Anyscale</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_11_2025/04_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The path from prototype to production for AI/ML workloads is rarely straightforward. As data pipelines expand and model complexity grows, teams can find themselves spending more time orchestrating distributed compute than building the intelligence that powers their products. Scaling from a laptop experiment to a production-grade workload still
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/powering-distributed-aiml-at-scale-with-azure-and-anyscale 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New developer resource page for Microsoft 365 interoperability and data portability</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Microsoft has long provided interoperability information, interfaces, and tools to help our vibrant ecosystem of partners integrate their products
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/new-developer-resource-page-for-microsoft-365-interoperability-and-data-portability 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does &lt;code&gt;SHFormat­Date­Time&lt;/code&gt; take an unaligned &lt;code&gt;FILETIME&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I noted some time ago Windows requires that pointers be aligned unless explicitly permitted to be unaligned. I gave as an example of a function that explicitly permits unaligned po
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251103-00/?p=111753 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Growth: Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_11_2025/03_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Accelerate Your Growth: Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program Unlock 360° Success with the Cosmos DB Engineering Team Are you ready to elevate your cloud data practice and drive innovation for your customers? The Azure Cosmos DB Partner Acceleration Program—spearheaded by the Cosmos DB Engineering
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/accelerate-your-growth-azure-cosmos-db-partner-acceleration-program 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
