<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Memory in Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Give your agents the power to remember Imagine your agent never asks the same question twice. Until now, most agents hav
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-memory-in-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Multi-Agent Workflows in Foundry Agent Service</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Across industries, organizations are moving from experimenting with single agents to running AI at the center of their business operations. While single agents excel at focused tasks, customers quickly discover that real enterprise work stretches across multiple steps, involves different roles, and requires strong governance. To operationalize
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-multi-agent-workflows-in-foundry-agent-service 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation Customization, A Developer&#39;s Guide to Adaptive Custom Translation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Translation isn’t just converting words—it’s enabling global communication. Yet for businesses operating worldwide, achieving accuracy, speed, and domain-specific termino
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/translation-customization-a-developers-guide-to-adaptive-custom-translation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Content Understanding is now generally available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft Ignite this year, we’re excited to announce that Azure Content Understanding in Foundry Tools is now generally available (GA). Over the past months, we’ve seen preview usage across industries, from large consultancies to healthcare leaders, with invaluable customer feedback shaping this release. With this GA release, we’r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-content-understanding-is-now-generally-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assess Agentic Risks with the AI Red Teaming Agent in Microsoft Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re thrilled to announce major enhancements to the AI Red Teaming Agent in Microsoft Foundry for models and AI agentic pipelines, available now in public preview. These new capabilities enable organizations to proactively identify safety and security risks in both models and a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/assess-agentic-risks-with-the-ai-red-teaming-agent-in-microsoft-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing TypeSpec for Microsoft 365 Copilot – Build declarative agents faster with more confidence</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that TypeSpec for Microsoft 365 Copilot is now generally available! This milestone marks the first stable release of the domain-specific language (DSL) designed to streamline how developers build and extend Micro
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/introducing-typespec-for-microsoft-365-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Framework (SPFx) roadmap update – November 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_11_2025/25_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We continue to be humbled by the incredible momentum of the SharePoint Framework (SPFx) and the growth it enables for our customers and partners. Tens of millions of users across the world rely daily on custom SPFx solutions in Microsoft 365 - solutions built and inno
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-framework-spfx-roadmap-update-november-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Introducing Edit Data (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Overview Working with table data is an essential part of database development — whether you’re validating behavior, debugging issues, or quickly seeding data. But switching between tools or writing repetitive T-SQL statements can slow down your workflow.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-edit-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New release cadence and support lifecycle for Microsoft C&#43;&#43; Build Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting with Visual Studio 2026, we are introducing a new support lifecycle for the Microsoft C++ (MSVC) Build Tools. We are also updating the MSVC release cadence. As Visual Studio moves to a Modern
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-release-cadence-and-support-lifecycle-for-msvc-build-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio – Built for the Speed of Modern Development</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The release of Visual Studio 2026 two weeks ago marks the next evolution in Microsoft’s 50-year commitment to deliver the tools that developers love and enterprises trust, built to move at the pace of modern development. Software development is moving faster than ever, and Visual Studio is evolving right along with you. Today, we’re ann
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-built-for-the-speed-of-modern-development 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does XAML break down when I have an element that is half a billion pixels tall?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer reported that their program encountered rendering problems when they created elements that were a half billion pixels tall, and they wondered why this was happening. A half billion pixels is an awful lot of pixels. At 96 pixels per inch, that gives you an element whose height is over 82 miles (132 km). There is no monitor
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251124-00/?p=111811 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Site Creation in Microsoft Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_11_2025/24_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The SharePoint team is excited to (finally) bring Site Collection creation to Graph! Starting in Microsoft Graph beta you can now create new site collections! But that’s not all! Creating site collections through older APIs required that your application have Si
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/sharepoint-site-creation-in-microsoft-graph 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 3 Release</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re happy to announce that OData .NET (ODL) 9 Preview 3 has been officially released and is available on NuGet: Microsoft.OData.Core 9.0.0 Preview 3
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/odata/announcing-odata-net-odl-9-preview-3-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite 2025: A Developer’s Guide to Building Agents for Microsoft 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ignite 2025 brought many innovations for developers building agents for Microsoft 365. From new capabilities in Declarative Agents and Custom Engine Agents to the introduction of Microsoft Agent 365, the platform now enables organizations to arch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/ignite-2025-a-developers-guide-to-building-agents-for-microsoft-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maybe somebody can explain to me how weak references solve the ODR problem</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_11_2025/21_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I proposed Using type aliasing to avoid the ODR problem with conditional compilation. A Reddit thread claimed that &amp;quot;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251121-00/?p=111807 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing how .NET Builds and Ships (Again)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            After I wrote my last post on how .NET builds and ships, I was cautiously optimistic that I wouldn&#39;t be writing another one. Or at least not another one about how we build and ship. That problem was done and dusted. .NET had done it! We&#39;d struck a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/reinventing-how-dotnet-builds-and-ships-again 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs: What’s New and What’s Next</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Build 2025, we introduced the Microsoft 365 Copilot APIs to help developers bring grounded AI into their solutions without rebuilding indexes or compromising security. The response has been encouraging, and your fee
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-365-copilot-apis-whats-new-and-whats-next 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Faster with VS Code for the Web – Azure: Your Browser-Based Dev Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers can now move from idea to Azure-ready code in minutes with VS Code for the Web – Azure. This browser-based environment removes setup time, reduces friction, and gives you immediate access to pre-configured run
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/get-started-with-vs-code-for-the-web 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Complexity to Simplicity: Intelligent JVM Optimizations on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction As cloud-native architectures scale across thousands of containers and virtual machines, Java performance tuning has become more distributed, complex, and error-prone than ever. As highlighted in our public preview announcement, traditional JVM optimization relied on ex
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/from-complexity-to-simplicity-intelligent-jvm-optimizations-on-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Public Preview of Azure Command Launcher for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are announcing the Public Preview of the Azure Command Launcher for Java, a new tool that helps developers, SREs, and infrastructure teams standardize and automate JVM configuration on Azure. The goal is to simplify tuning practices and reduce resource waste across Java workloads.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/announcing-the-public-preview-of-azure-command-launcher-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundry Local comes to Android—plus on-device speech, on-prem support, and a simpler SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re introducing a powerful new way to bring AI directly to your mobile apps: Foundry Local on Android. Starting now, you can build Android applications that run AI on-device—no cloud round trips required. Sign up for the gated preview here: https://aka.m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/foundry-local-comes-to-android 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing: Dynamic Data Masking for Azure Cosmos DB (Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today marks a big step forward with the public preview of Dynamic Data Masking (DDM) for Azure Cosmos DB. This feature helps organizations protect sensitive data without requiring changes to application logic or database interactions. What is Dynamic Data Masking? Dynamic Data Masking (DDM) is a server-side, policy-driven
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-dynamic-data-masking-for-azure-cosmos-db-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Azure SRE Agent with Azure Cosmos DB: Smarter Diagnostics for Your Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/use-azure-sre-agent-with-azure-cosmos-db-smarter-diagnostics-for-your-applications 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Private Preview: Safe Account Key rotation using Account Key Usage Metadata</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Account Key Usage Metadata is a new security and observability feature that helps Azure Cosmos DB customers avoid service disruptions during key rotations. It provides visibility when each account key was last used
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-private-preview-safe-account-key-rotation-using-account-key-usage-metadata 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps to GitHub migration Playbook: Unlocking Agentic DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_11_2025/20_11_2025_19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps or GitHub Enterprise ? Today, in the Microsoft ecosystem, two Software Development Lifecycle management platforms coexist: - Azure DevOps is designed from the ground up for enterprise with advanced planning features through Azure Boards, build and release automation with Azure Pipelines, and a unique
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/azure-devops-to-github-migration-playbook-unlocking-agentic-devops 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignite 2025 - What&#39;s new for Office Add-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog outlines the new and exciting features now available in the Office Add-ins ecosystem for Ignite 2025. Continue reading for platform updates, developer experience improvements, and store enhancements. Copilot Agents work with office.js to read and write document content, enabling powerful workflows At Build earlier this yea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/ignite-2025-whats-new-for-office-add-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharge Your Test Coverage with GitHub Copilot Testing for .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Writing high-quality unit tests is critical for reliable software, but it’s often time-consuming and repetitive. What if GitHub Copilot could take care of that for you? Today we’re thrilled to announce GitHub Copilot testing for .NET is now available in Visual Studio Insiders. This new capability brings AI-powered unit test gen
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/github-copilot-testing-for-dotnet 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the azd AI agent extension: Publish Microsoft Foundry agents directly from your development environment</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Announcing the new azd AI agent extension: Publish Microsoft Foundry agents directly from your development environment If you&#39;ve ever built an AI agent, you know the real challenge is more than writing the code, it&#39;s the complex dance of provisioning resources, managing models, and securely deploying everything to the cloud. We tho
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-foundry-agent-extension 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Agent 365 Interoperability for Smart, Secure Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Yesterday we launched Agent 365 - Microsoft’s enterprise control plane for AI agents, designed to make agents secure, compliant, and ready for large-scale deployment within organizations. Agents enabled with Agent 365 have a unique identi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/microsoft-agent-365-interoperability-for-smart-secure-productivity 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) Nov 2025 - Container Apps (GA), Layered Provisioning (Beta), Extension Framework, and Aspire 13</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the November 2025 edition of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) release blog! This post covers releases 1.20.1 through 1.21.2. To share your feedback and questions, join the November release discussion on GitHub. Highlights: Az
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-november-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is &lt;code&gt;Write­Process­Memory&lt;/code&gt; faster than shared memory for transferring data between two processes?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Say you need to transfer a large amount of data between two processes. One way is to use shared memory. Is that the fastest way to do it? Can you do any better? One argument against shared memory is that the sender will have to copy the data into the shared memory block, and the recipient will have to copy it out, resulting in two e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251119-00/?p=111800 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announced at Ignite 2025: Azure DocumentDB, MCP Toolkit, Fleet Analytics, and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announced-at-ignite-2025-azure-documentdb-mcp-toolkit-fleet-analytics-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.96 is here: endpoints for Advanced Paste, metadata support for PowerRename and more!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_11_2025/19_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-96-is-here-endpoints-for-advanced-paste-metadata-support-for-powerrename-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New T-SQL AI Features are now in Public Preview for Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At the start of this year, we released a new set of T-SQL AI features for embedding your relational data for AI applications. Today, we have brought those features to Azure SQL and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. This post will help you get started usi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/ai-functions-public-preview-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A step-by-step guide to modernizing .NET applications with GitHub Copilot agent mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Upgrading an old .NET app doesn’t have to mean chasing broken builds and cryptic errors. Yet for many developers, a simple version bump turns into hours of dependency conflicts and manual fixes. Modernization isn’t just about staying current. Older frameworks can introduce security risks, slow performance, and block cloud adoptio
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/modernizing-dotnet-with-github-copilot-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps and GitHub Repositories — Next Steps in the Path to Agentic AI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In May, we talked about the evolution of GitHub Copilot from a coding assistant into an AI powered peer programmer. Since then, GitHub has taken a major step forward - becoming an open platform for agentic devel
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-devops-and-github-repositories-next-steps-in-the-path-to-agentic-ai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Microsoft Teams SDK (Formerly the Teams AI Library)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot; heading=&amp;quot;UPDATE November 17: We&#39;re excited to announce that the Teams AI Library is now called the Microsoft Teams SDK.&amp;quot;]The Teams SDK, now generally available in C# and JavaScript and in public preview for Python, remains a developer’s one-stop-shop to build anything, including conversational agents, for Micros
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/announcing-the-updated-teams-ai-library-and-mcp-support 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spend Less Time Upgrading, More Time Coding in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the past, moving to the next major version of Visual Studio could take hours, sometimes days, to recreate your dev environment the way you like it. Visual Studio 2026 makes it easier than ever to stay current with the latest productivity features, performance improvements, and security fixes all without disrupting your flow. With the new Vi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/spend-less-time-upgrading-more-time-coding-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Innovation to Enterprise Trust with Microsoft Agent 365</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The bridge between agent innovation and enterprise readiness While teams can build an agent in just a few days, deployin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/from-innovation-to-enterprise-trust-with-microsoft-agent-365 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: GitHub Copilot Chat GA and New Public Previews for Edit Data, Data-tier Application, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code continues to evolve, delivering features that make SQL development more integrated, more consistent, and more developer-friendly. In version v1.37.0, we’re announcing the Public Preview of Edit Data,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-copilot-ga-edit-data 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Major New Agentic Capabilities for GitHub Copilot in JetBrains and Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            GitHub Copilot is taking a major step forward with expanded, deeply integrated support for JetBrains and Eclipse — bringing a new generation of agentic, intelligent capabilities directly into your favorite Java IDEs. This release strengthens Copilot’s cross-IDE experience, unifies agentic workflows, and unlocks m
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/new-agentic-capabilities-for-github-copilot-in-jetbrains-and-eclipse 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public preview of vector indexing in Azure SQL DB, Azure SQL MI, and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to share that DiskANN vector indexing is now in public preview across Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. DiskANN is a cutting-edge algorithm for efficient vector similarity search, making it ideal for powering recommendation systems
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/public-preview-of-vector-indexing-in-azure-sql-db-azure-sql-mi-and-sql-database-in-microsoft-fabric 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB Fleet Pools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/18_11_2025/18_11_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce two updates to Azure Cosmos DB fleets: Fleet pools – now generally available Fleet analytics – now in public preview Azure Cosmos DB fleets enables developers to build scalable, isolated, and cost-effective multi-tenant or Software as a Service (SaaS) applications. Today,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/now-generally-available-azure-cosmos-db-fleet-pool 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
