<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Enterprise AI Complexity: Multi-Agent Orchestration with the Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Architectural Imperative: Why Multi-Agent Orchestration is Essential In modern enterprise AI systems, the scope and complexity of real-world business ch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unlocking-enterprise-ai-complexity-multi-agent-orchestration-with-the-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Testing with Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Ever had to write tests that need a real database, and found yourself juggling local setups or dummy data? Testcontainers might just be your new best friend. In this article, we&#39;ll explore how Testcontainers can simplify integration testing by spinning up real services in Docker containers on-demand. We&#39;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/testing-with-testcontainers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Context to Copilot: Azure Cosmos DB Best Practices, Right in Your VS Code Workspace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love GitHub Copilot for its instant, intelligent code suggestions. But what if those suggestions could also reflect your specific database and workload patterns? That’s now possible with a new feature in Azure Cosmos DB for VS Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/bringing-context-to-copilot-azure-cosmos-db-best-practices-right-in-your-vs-code-workspace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Planning in Visual Studio (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Quick prompts are great for small fixes, but they fall short on big projects. You end up rewriting instructions, tweaking them constantly, and hoping the model stays on track. It gives Copilot a visible, structured path to follow, one that updates as it works and keeps you in control at every step. In Agent Mode, Copilot can now create plan
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-planning-in-visual-studio-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI Agentic RAG search application with React, SQL Azure and Azure Static Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Leveraging OpenAI for semantic searches on structured databases like Azure SQL enhances search accuracy and context-awareness, providing more relevant and insightful results. This example showcases the use of Azure SQL for storing and searching data with AI. By implementing the RAG pattern with Azure SQL, the sample e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-an-ai-agentic-rag-search-application-with-react-sql-azure-and-azure-static-web-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes &lt;CODE&gt;cheap_&lt;WBR&gt;steady_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt; faster than &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;chrono::&lt;WBR&gt;high_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I noted that There is a std::chrono::high_resolution_clock, but no low_resolution_clock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251022-00/?p=111714 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Model Choice in VS Code with Bring Your Own Key</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the new Language Model Chat Provider API in VS Code is enabling more model choice and extensibility for chat experiences via the Bring Your Own Key experience. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/expanding-model-choice-in-vs-code-with-bring-your-own-key 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Visual Studio Extension Compatibility: Effortless Migration for Extension Developers and Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have great news for extension users and developers: Visual Studio 2026 is introducing an extension compatibility model designed specifically to make your life easier. Our top priority is to ensure that your extensions continue to work seamlessly across Visual Studio releases - with no extra effort required from you. For users: exten
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/modernizing-visual-studio-extension-compatibility-effortless-migration-for-extension-developers-and-users 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: The hockey stick on wheels</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The &amp;quot;hockey stick graph&amp;quot; is a graph which shows slow initial growth, followed by a rapid linear increase. The resulting shape resembles a hockey stick, with the blade of the stick represented by the nearly-flat initial section, and the handle of the stick represented by the rapi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251021-00/?p=111710 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Cost Management” Is Now “Account Throughput” and It’s Moving</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve made a small but important change in the Azure portal for Azure Cosmos DB to make it easier to manage your account-level throughput. The “Cost Management” section has been renamed to “Account Throughput” and can now be found under the Settings section of your Azure Cosmos DB
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/cost-management-is-now-account-throughput 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What about the icons in pifmgr.dll?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I discussed the intended uses of the icons in progman.exe and moricons.dll and we even looked at those icons (
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251020-00/?p=111706 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing latest Azure Cosmos DB Python SDK: Powering the Future of AI with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the stable release of Azure Cosmos DB Python SDK version 4.14.0! This release brings together months of innovation and collaboration, featuring ground-breaking capabilities that have been battle-tested in production environments. Many of these features were developed in c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-latest-azure-cosmos-db-python-sdk-powering-the-future-of-ai-with-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer&#39;s Guide to Fine-Tuning GPT-4o for Image Classification on Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re a machine learning practitioner, app developer, or just curious about the latest in AI, this guide shows how you can quickly boost image classification accuracy using cutting-edge Vision-Language Models (VLM) on Azure—no deep learning expertise required. In this walkthrough, you’ll see how to fine-tune GPT-4o on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/a-developers-guide-to-fine-tuning-gpt-4o-for-image-classification-on-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Azure Cosmos DB Efficiency with Azure Advisor Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB is
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/boost-your-azure-cosmos-db-efficiency-with-azure-advisor-insights 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlined Setup, Stronger Guardrails for Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce a new capability that simplifies Dev Box setup—enabling platform engineers and project admins to specify images and SKUs directly when configuring Dev Box pools, without needing to create Dev Box definitions at the Dev Cent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/streamlined-setup-stronger-guardrails-for-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RAII to remedy a defect where not all code paths performed required exit actions, follow-up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at a way to use the RAII design pattern (Resource Acquisition Is Initialization) to ensure that a function eventually got called on all code paths
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251017-00/?p=111698 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting new capabilities and enhancements for M365 Developer Program - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft 365 Developer Program has long been a great resource for developers building solutions on the Microsoft 365 platform. Today, we’re thrilled to share some exciting updates that make onboarding easier, environments more ca
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/exciting-new-capabilities-and-enhancements-for-m365-developer-program-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA&#39;s Harmonized Landsat and Sentinel-2 (HLS) Data Now Available on Microsoft&#39;s Planetary Computer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NASA’s vast archive of Earth observation data has long been a cornerstone for scientific discovery, environmental monitoring, and global sustainability efforts. Now, Microsoft has made it even easier for researchers, developers, and decision-makers to access and utilize this critical resource. Through a collaboration with NASA, the H
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/nasa-hls-on-mpc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RAII to remedy a defect where not all code paths performed required exit actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A team asked me to review their pull request that fixed a bug that was caused by failing to perform some required action along all code paths. Here&#39;s a simplified sketch: void MySpecialFeature::OnButtonClick() { try { auto file = PickFile(); if (!file) { DismissUI(); return;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251016-00/?p=111691 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
