<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Visual Studio Extension Compatibility: Effortless Migration for Extension Developers and Users</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We have great news for extension users and developers: Visual Studio 2026 is introducing an extension compatibility model designed specifically to make your life easier. Our top priority is to ensure that your extensions continue to work seamlessly across Visual Studio releases - with no extra effort required from you. For users: exten
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/modernizing-visual-studio-extension-compatibility-effortless-migration-for-extension-developers-and-users 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Cost Management” Is Now “Account Throughput” and It’s Moving</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_10_2025/21_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve made a small but important change in the Azure portal for Azure Cosmos DB to make it easier to manage your account-level throughput. The “Cost Management” section has been renamed to “Account Throughput” and can now be found under the Settings section of your Azure Cosmos DB
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/cost-management-is-now-account-throughput 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What about the icons in pifmgr.dll?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I discussed the intended uses of the icons in progman.exe and moricons.dll and we even looked at those icons (
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251020-00/?p=111706 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing latest Azure Cosmos DB Python SDK: Powering the Future of AI with OpenAI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re thrilled to announce the stable release of Azure Cosmos DB Python SDK version 4.14.0! This release brings together months of innovation and collaboration, featuring ground-breaking capabilities that have been battle-tested in production environments. Many of these features were developed in c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/announcing-latest-azure-cosmos-db-python-sdk-powering-the-future-of-ai-with-openai 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer&#39;s Guide to Fine-Tuning GPT-4o for Image Classification on Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_10_2025/20_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Whether you’re a machine learning practitioner, app developer, or just curious about the latest in AI, this guide shows how you can quickly boost image classification accuracy using cutting-edge Vision-Language Models (VLM) on Azure—no deep learning expertise required. In this walkthrough, you’ll see how to fine-tune GPT-4o on
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/a-developers-guide-to-fine-tuning-gpt-4o-for-image-classification-on-azure-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost your Azure Cosmos DB Efficiency with Azure Advisor Insights</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure Cosmos DB is
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/boost-your-azure-cosmos-db-efficiency-with-azure-advisor-insights 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlined Setup, Stronger Guardrails for Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce a new capability that simplifies Dev Box setup—enabling platform engineers and project admins to specify images and SKUs directly when configuring Dev Box pools, without needing to create Dev Box definitions at the Dev Cent
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/streamlined-setup-stronger-guardrails-for-microsoft-dev-box 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RAII to remedy a defect where not all code paths performed required exit actions, follow-up</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/17_10_2025/17_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last time, we looked at a way to use the RAII design pattern (Resource Acquisition Is Initialization) to ensure that a function eventually got called on all code paths
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251017-00/?p=111698 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciting new capabilities and enhancements for M365 Developer Program - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Microsoft 365 Developer Program has long been a great resource for developers building solutions on the Microsoft 365 platform. Today, we’re thrilled to share some exciting updates that make onboarding easier, environments more ca
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/exciting-new-capabilities-and-enhancements-for-m365-developer-program-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA&#39;s Harmonized Landsat and Sentinel-2 (HLS) Data Now Available on Microsoft&#39;s Planetary Computer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NASA’s vast archive of Earth observation data has long been a cornerstone for scientific discovery, environmental monitoring, and global sustainability efforts. Now, Microsoft has made it even easier for researchers, developers, and decision-makers to access and utilize this critical resource. Through a collaboration with NASA, the H
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azuregov/nasa-hls-on-mpc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RAII to remedy a defect where not all code paths performed required exit actions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_10_2025/16_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A team asked me to review their pull request that fixed a bug that was caused by failing to perform some required action along all code paths. Here&#39;s a simplified sketch: void MySpecialFeature::OnButtonClick() { try { auto file = PickFile(); if (!file) { DismissUI(); return;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251016-00/?p=111691 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily connect AI workloads to Azure Blob Storage with adlfs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Easily connect AI workloads to Azure Blob Storage with adlfs We&#39;re excited to announce the newest release of adlfs—a unified Pythonic file system interface to Azure Blob Storage and Azure Data Lake Storage. Microsoft works closely with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/easily-connect-ai-workloads-to-azure-blob-storage-with-adlfs 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can you increment a reference count with relaxed semantics, but you have to decrement with release semantics?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/15_10_2025/15_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When managing reference counts, there is an asymmetry between incrementing and decrementing: Incrementing the reference count can use relaxed semantics, but decrementing requires release semantics (and destroying requires acquire semantics). The asymmetry may strike you as odd, but maybe it shouldn&#39;t. After all, it&#39;s not surprising
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251015-00/?p=111686 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET and .NET Framework October 2025 servicing releases updates</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to our combined .NET servicing updates for October 2025. Let&#39;s get into the latest release of .NET &amp;amp; .NET Framework, here is a quick overview of what&#39;s new in our servicing releases: Security improvements .NET and .NET Framework has been refreshed with the latest update as of October 14, 2025. This update contains securi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-and-dotnet-framework-october-2025-servicing-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing .NET 10 Release Candidate 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            .NET 10 Release Candidate 2 is now available. This is our second and final release candidate and it comes with a go-live support license so you can confidently use this release for your production applications ahead of general availability. This release of
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/dotnet-10-rc-2 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - October 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 21:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Welcome to the October 2025 edition of the Azure Developer CLI (azd) release blog! This post covers releases 1.19.0 and 1.20.0. To share your feedback and questions, join the October release discussion on GitHub. This month brings game-changing features including
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Developer’s Guide to Smarter Fine-tuning: Unlock custom AI for every business challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/the-developers-guide-to-smarter-fine-tuning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the .NET Security Group</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The .NET project is run by Microsoft and follows our security reporting and disclosure practices. We publish vulnerability fixes and disclosures most months on Patch Tuesday. Nothing about that is changing. We are announcin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-security-group 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.3-1 and 1.24.9-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-3-1-and-1-24-9-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing Authentication for Legacy Visual Studio Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of our ongoing commitment to security and modernization, we’re updating outdated authentication mechanisms used by older versions of clients reliant on our older Visual Studio client libraries. For full details on all known impacted clients, refer to the official announcement we made in April 2024:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/modernizing-authentication-for-legacy-visual-studio-clients 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I remember taking a screen shot of a video, and when I opened it in Paint, the video was playing in it! What witchcraft is this?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/14_10_2025/14_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            @ChenCravat In an old version of Windows (Windows 98 iirc) if you took screenshot of a video from media player and paste it into paint, and resume media player, video would play inside paint. Do you why it happened? It is still bugging me to this day.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251014-00/?p=111681 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
