<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changes to inline image representation in Outlook on the web and new Outlook for Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/07_10_2025/07_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’d like to inform you about an update to how inline images are represented in the HTML body of Outlook emails in Outlook on the web and the new Outlook for Windows. This change may impact how your add-in identifies and processes inline images when using the attachment ID. What’s changing? Previously, we represented inline imag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/changes-to-inline-images-in-outlook 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Dev/Test Benefit Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Before joining Microsoft, I served as VP of Application Development at one of the largest temporary staffing companies in the United States. I’ll never forget the look on our CFO’s face when I told him we needed two to three additional cloud environments to support a large-scale modernization project. His
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-dev-test-benefit-explained 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code comments should apply to the state of the system at the point the comment &#34;executes&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/06_10_2025/06_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Comments inside the body of a function should apply to the state of the system at the point the comment &amp;quot;executes&amp;quot;. Here&#39;s an example of poor comment placement: // Widget is already vibrating, so we update the waveform in place. // Else the waveform parameters will be set when we start vibrating. if (waveformParameters !
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251006-00/?p=111655 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap for AI in Visual Studio (October)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re excited to share our public roadmap, which outlines the next steps in evolving Visual Studio with AI-powered agentic experiences. With every month, we aim to deliver smarter, faster, and more intuitive tools that enhance your coding experience. Disclaimer: The items outlined here represent ongoing work for the month. They
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/roadmap-for-ai-in-visual-studio-october 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we get weak functions for static linking? The Visual C&#43;&#43; compiler says &#34;We have weak functions at home&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The ELF object file has this thing called &amp;quot;weak functions&amp;quot;. These are functions present in a library that are used by the linker to resolve a symbol only if the main program doesn&#39;t provide a resolution for them. The Visual C++ compiler doesn&#39;t have &amp;quot;weak functions&amp;quot; in this sense, but that doesn&#39;t mean that equivalent functionality
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251003-00/?p=111650 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Lab to Live: A Blueprint for a Voice-Powered AI Sales Coach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/03_10_2025/03_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Until recently, building real-time voice AI for production was challenging. Developers faced hurdles such as managing audio streams and ensuring low-latency performance. That landscape is changing. The
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/from-lab-to-live-a-blueprint-for-a-voice-powered-ai-sales-coach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VS Live! Orlando – Your Ultimate Learning Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Imagine swapping stories with fellow developers over dinner as the Florida sun sets, then beginning the next morning with a stroll past the resort’s palm-lined walkways before catching your first session across
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-live-orlando-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (September 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with inferring from a function call operator is that there may be more than one</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I wrote briefly on writing a helper class for generating a particular category of C callback wrappers around C++ methods. This particular
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251002-00/?p=111647 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Fabric Eventhouse to Store Great Expectations Validation Results</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In a previous post, we explored how to perform data validations with Great Expectations (GX) in Microsoft Fabric. We walked through how to set up the validation framework and ensure your data meets the quality standards expected. Now, in thi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/leveraging-fabric-eventhouse-to-store-great-expectations-validation-results 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s New in vcpkg (September 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/02_10_2025/02_10_2025_14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This blog post summarizes changes to the vcpkg package manager as part of the 2025.09.17 registry release, the 2025-08-29 and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/whats-new-in-vcpkg-september-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The $150 Secret Hiding in Plain Sight</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Picture this: I’m standing in front of 400+ developers at Visual Studio Live! Redmond, right here on the Microsoft campus in Building 33, about to reveal what I call the hidden value of a Visual Studio subscription. I pull up a simple question on the screen:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/unlock-vss-benefits-myvisualstudio 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Agent Framework (Preview): Making AI Agents Simple for Every Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI agents shouldn&#39;t be rocket science. Yet many developers find themselves wrestling with complex orchestration logic, struggling to connect multiple AI models, or spending weeks building hosting infrastructure just to get a simple agent into production. What if building an AI agent could be as straightforward as creating a web API
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-microsoft-agent-framework-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I convert a &lt;code&gt;FILETIME&lt;/code&gt; to a C&#43;&#43; clock like &lt;code&gt;std::system_clock&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;winrt::clock&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The traditional Win32 data structure for holding a date/time is the FILETIME. How do you interoperate between this and the C++ clocks like std::system_clock and winrt::clock? When C++ introduced the concept of clocks in C++11, it did not require clocks to have any particular epoch. In C++20, th
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251001-00/?p=111643 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Microsoft Agent Framework: The Open-Source Engine for Agentic AI Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_10_2025/01_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why agents need a new foundation Over the last year, developers have been experimenting with AI agents in every imaginable form. Agents are not just chatbots or copilots — they are autonomous software components that can reason about goals, call tools and APIs, collaborate with other agents, and adapt dynamically.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/introducing-microsoft-agent-framework-the-open-source-engine-for-agentic-ai-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript 7 native preview in Visual Studio 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In March of this year Anders Hejlsberg announced TypeScript 7 native preview and in May Daniel posted Announcing TypeScript Native Previews. Visual Studio 2026 Insiders n
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/typescript-7-native-preview-in-visual-studio-2026 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: Convicted</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When you do something with conviction, you do so with full confidence that you are correct. But what is the verb that means &amp;quot;To be fully confident that one is correct&amp;quot;? At Microsoft, it is often backformed into the verb convict (stress on second syllable). This backformation typically happens in speech,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250930-00/?p=111639 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio September Update - profiler agent, app modernization, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The September 2025 update for Visual Studio 2022 (v17.14) is now available. In this month, we are bringing you a fully integrated and game-changing agentic AI experience, from code generation to modernization, profiling, and code reviews.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/visual-studio-september-update 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft’s OpenJDK builds now ready for Java 25</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_09_2025/30_09_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that the Microsoft Build of OpenJDK binaries are now available for Java 25. As always, our builds aim to provide a high-quality, production-ready build of OpenJDK, with binaries tested across plat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/microsofts-openjdk-builds-now-ready-for-java-25 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
