<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:59:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from IDCRL authentication to modern authentication in SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In the next few months, Microsoft will be removing the legacy authentication protocol known as IDCRL (Identity Client Run Time Library) in SharePoint and force calls to rely on OpenID connect and OAuth Protocols. Since 2018, regular sign-in for services such as OneDrive and SharePoint has always relied on the more secure OpenID Connect and OAu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/migrating-from-idcrl-authentication-to-modern-authentication-in-sharepoint 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put your AI to the Test with Microsoft.Extensions.AI.Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            AI is changing how we build software, but it also introduces new challenges: how do you know if your AI application is giving the right answers and producing the right outcomes? Evaluations (often referred to simply as ‘evals’) provide a structured way to measure quality so you can trust your results. In this blog, we’ll introduce the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/blog/put-your-ai-to-the-test-with-microsoft-extensions-ai-evaluation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GitHub Copilot capabilities for C&#43;&#43; developers: Upgrade MSVC, improve build performance, and refactor C&#43;&#43; code</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            [alert type=&amp;quot;important&amp;quot;]GitHub Copilot app modernization for C++, GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows, and C++ code editing tools for GitHub Copilot will be available soon in Private Preview. Join the waitlist for Private Preview today.[/alert] Yesterday at GitHub Universe, Gi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/new-github-copilot-capabilities-for-c-developers-upgrade-msvc-improve-build-performance-and-refactor-c-code 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of the previewImageUrl property for Insights items that reference file attachments</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re deprecating the previewImageUrl property in the resourceVisualization complex type for
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-the-previewimageurl-property-for-insights-items-that-reference-file-attachments 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when you have a crash in the runtime control flow guard check</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_10_2025/29_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Windows Control Flow Guard (CFG) is a defense in depth feature which validates indirect call targets. The idea is that each module that is enabled for CFG provides a bitmap that describes which addresses in the module are intended to be targets of indirect calls. When CFG is enabled in a process, indirect function calls are checked against
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251029-00/?p=111738 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Custom Agents for .NET Developers: C# Expert &amp; WinForms Expert</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            With GitHub’s announcement of Copilot Custom Agents, developers now have powerful new tools to automate and accelerate their workflows. These custom agents enhance Copilot by serving as intelligent accelerators with specialized expertise, able to analyze codebases, plan tasks, and execu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/introducing-custom-agents-for-dotnet-developers-csharp-expert-winforms-expert 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Azure MCP Server 1.0.0 Stable Release – A New Era for Agentic Workflows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we’re not just shipping software, we’re opening the door to a new era of cloud automation and AI-powered development. Azure MCP server 1.0 is now officially available as a stable release! If you’re a developer, an AI enthusiast, or just someone who loves seeing what’s possible when cloud a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/announcing-azure-mcp-server-stable-release 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java and AI for Beginners: a practical video series for Java</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/java-and-ai-for-beginners-a-practical-video-series-for-java 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls for Copilot in JetBrains and Eclipse Now in Public Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP registry and allowlist controls for GitHub Copilot in JetBrains IDEs and Eclipse are now available in public preview in nightly/pre-release builds.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/mcp-registry-and-allowlist-controls-for-copilot-in-jetbrains-and-eclipse-now-in-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls Now Available in GitHub Copilot for Xcode (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that MCP Registry and Allowlist Controls in GitHub Copilot for Xcode are now available in public preview in pre-release builds. These capabilities help Xcode developers discover, install, and manage Model Context Protocol (MCP)
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/mcp-registry-and-allowlist-controls-now-available-in-github-copilot-for-xcode-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Backup to Discovery: Veeam’s Search Engine Powered by Azure Cosmos DB</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This article was co-authored by Zack Rossman, Staff Software Engineer, Veeam; Ashlie Martinez, Staff Software Engineer, Veeam; and James Nguyen, Senior Principal Cloud Solution Architect, AI/ML, Microsoft. Don&#39;t miss: Hear all about about Veeam&#39;s AI-powered semantic search use case and architecture setup
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/from-backup-to-discovery-veeams-search-engine-powered-by-azure-cosmos-db 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did the Windows 95 user interface code get brought to the Windows NT code base?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_10_2025/28_10_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A long time ago, somebody asked, &amp;quot;How did the new Windows 95 user interface get brought to the Windows NT code base? The development of Windows 95 lined up with the endgame of Windows NT 3.1, so how did the finished Windows 95 code get brought to the Windows NT code base for Windows NT 4.0? Did they reimplement it based on the existing spec
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251028-00/?p=111733 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (October 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-october-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubious security vulnerability: Denial of service by loading a very large file</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/27_10_2025/27_10_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A denial of service vulnerability report was filed against a program, let&#39;s call it Notepad. The actual text of the report was very hard to understand because the grammar was all messed up. I&#39;ll give the finder the benefit of the doubt on the assumption that they are not a native English speaker. Here&#39;s a cleaned-up version:
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251027-00/?p=111731 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your 6-Step Guide to Deploying a Website with GitHub Codespaces and Copilot agent mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 22:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            👋everyone! Shree here. I&#39;m sure many of you have had a similar chat with someone you know
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/your-6-step-guide-to-deploying-a-website-with-github-codespaces-and-copilot-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The early history of the Windows Runtime PropertyValue and why there is a PropertyType.Inspectable that is never used</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_10_2025/24_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I mentioned that the Property­Value.Create­Inspectable method doesn&#39;t create a Property­Value
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251024-00/?p=111725 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Sponsorship on NuGet.org</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Package maintainers are the backbone of the NuGet.org ecosystem, building and maintaining the packages we all rely on. Today we are excited to announce the new NuGet.org Sponsorship feature which makes it easier than ever for consumers to recognize and support the authors behind their favorite packages. With Sponsorship on NuG
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-sponsorship-on-nugetdotorg-for-maintainer-appreciation 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading to Microsoft Agent Framework in Your .NET AI Chat App</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The AI App Templates let you spin up a working chat application in minutes, complete with AI integration, custom data ingestion, and all the pieces you need to get started. It&#39;s a cool and solid foundation. But here&#39;s the thing: what if you want to go beyond basic chat? What if you want to build AI agents that can actually reason,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/upgrading-to-microsoft-agent-framework-in-your-dotnet-ai-chat-app 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Runtime design principle: Properties can be set in any order</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One of the design principles of the Windows Runtime is that if an object has multiple writable properties, then you can set them in any order and the effect will be the same. For example, consider an object with three properties: Minimum, Maximum, and Value. Suppose the rule is that you must, a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251023-00/?p=111716 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Enterprise AI Complexity: Multi-Agent Orchestration with the Microsoft Agent Framework</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Architectural Imperative: Why Multi-Agent Orchestration is Essential In modern enterprise AI systems, the scope and complexity of real-world business ch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/unlocking-enterprise-ai-complexity-multi-agent-orchestration-with-the-microsoft-agent-framework 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration Testing with Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_10_2025/23_10_2025_13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Ever had to write tests that need a real database, and found yourself juggling local setups or dummy data? Testcontainers might just be your new best friend. In this article, we&#39;ll explore how Testcontainers can simplify integration testing by spinning up real services in Docker containers on-demand. We&#39;
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/testing-with-testcontainers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Context to Copilot: Azure Cosmos DB Best Practices, Right in Your VS Code Workspace</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Developers love GitHub Copilot for its instant, intelligent code suggestions. But what if those suggestions could also reflect your specific database and workload patterns? That’s now possible with a new feature in Azure Cosmos DB for VS Code.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/bringing-context-to-copilot-azure-cosmos-db-best-practices-right-in-your-vs-code-workspace 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Planning in Visual Studio (Public Preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Quick prompts are great for small fixes, but they fall short on big projects. You end up rewriting instructions, tweaking them constantly, and hoping the model stays on track. It gives Copilot a visible, structured path to follow, one that updates as it works and keeps you in control at every step. In Agent Mode, Copilot can now create plan
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/introducing-planning-in-visual-studio-public-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build an AI Agentic RAG search application with React, SQL Azure and Azure Static Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Leveraging OpenAI for semantic searches on structured databases like Azure SQL enhances search accuracy and context-awareness, providing more relevant and insightful results. This example showcases the use of Azure SQL for storing and searching data with AI. By implementing the RAG pattern with Azure SQL, the sample e
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/build-an-ai-agentic-rag-search-application-with-react-sql-azure-and-azure-static-web-apps 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes &lt;CODE&gt;cheap_&lt;WBR&gt;steady_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt; faster than &lt;CODE&gt;std::&lt;WBR&gt;chrono::&lt;WBR&gt;high_&lt;WBR&gt;resolution_&lt;WBR&gt;clock&lt;/CODE&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I noted that There is a std::chrono::high_resolution_clock, but no low_resolution_clock.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20251022-00/?p=111714 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Model Choice in VS Code with Bring Your Own Key</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_10_2025/22_10_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Learn how the new Language Model Chat Provider API in VS Code is enabling more model choice and extensibility for chat experiences via the Bring Your Own Key experience. Read the full article
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/vscode-blog/expanding-model-choice-in-vs-code-with-bring-your-own-key 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
