<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure Storage Connector for PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to introduce the Azure Storage Connector for PyTorch (azstoragetorch), a new library that brings seamless, performance-optimized integration between Azure Storage and PyTorch. The library makes it easy to access and store data in Azure Blob Storage directly within your training workflows. What is PyTorch?
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/introducing-the-azure-storage-connector-for-pytorch 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I get errors about some weird symbol called ?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform..., part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are investigating why a project is getting an error about a weird C++/CX symbol, and we thought we had figured it out, but our a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250626-00/?p=111314 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Electronic Arts standardized C&#43;&#43; builds across Windows and Linux with Visual Studio Build Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Electronic Arts (EA), the Frostbite Enginering Workflows team has thousands of developers who work on powerful game engines behind popular games. EA has relied on Visual Studio for years due to several features such as IntelliSense, Build Insights, and the overall debugging experience and eagerly use newer integrations such as GitHub Copi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/how-electronic-arts-standardized-c-builds-across-windows-and-linux-with-visual-studio-build-tools 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Proxy v0.29 with refactored architecture, MCP server, and exposed LM prompts</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 07:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce Dev Proxy v0.29, with a major architectural overhaul, control over language model prompts, and improved diagnostics. Whether you&#39;re building, debugging, or customizing your API simulations, this version gives you more power and clarity than ever before. In this version: Architectural refactoring to
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/dev-proxy-v0-29-with-refactored-architecture-mcp-server-and-exposed-lm-prompts 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Configuration Management</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/26_06_2025/26_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Recently, the Microsoft ISE team completed a customer engagement that involved managing edge deployments to factory floors across geographical locations. This system needed to support existing workloads migrated from Azure IoT Hub, new workloads for processing IoT data feeds, and machine learning workloads for performing
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/fleet-configuration-management 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Azure Resource Manager reliance on Azure DevOps sign-ins</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Azure DevOps will no longer depend on the Azure Resource Manager (ARM) resource (https://management.azure.com) when you sign in or refresh Microsoft Entra access tokens. Previously, Azure DevOps required the ARM audience during sign-in and token refresh flows. This requirement meant administrators had to allow all Azure DevOps users to bypa
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/removing-azure-resource-manager-reliance-on-azure-devops-sign-ins 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your information has been permanently deleted, for small values of permanently</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As part of a periodic purge of unused online accounts, I deleted my account from a company ten months ago. Let&#39;s call that company Contoso. I received a confirmation that said, &amp;quot;Your personal information and items associated with your account have now been deleted. This action is permanent and cannot be reversed.&amp;quot; Yesterday, I got a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250625-01/?p=111308 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do I get errors about some weird symbol called ?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform..., part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague was writing a fuzz test and ran into a build error. vccorlib.lib(climain.obj) : error LNK2019: unresolved external symbol &amp;quot;?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform@@$00@Platform@@@Z&amp;quot; (?main@@YAHP$01E$AAV?$Array@PE$AAVString@Platform@@$00@P
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250625-00/?p=111306 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Kernel Python Gets a Major Vector Store Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_06_2025/25_06_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce a significant update to Semantic Kernel Python&#39;s vector store implementation. Version 1.34 brings a complete overhaul that makes working with vector data simpler, more intuitive, and more powerful. This update consolidates the API, improves developer experience, and adds new capabilities that streamline AI development
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/semantic-kernel/semantic-kernel-python-gets-a-major-vector-store-upgrade 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abusing copyright strings to trick software into thinking it&#39;s running on your competitor&#39;s PC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_06_2025/24_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            One very complicated part of bringing up Plug and Play was bootstrapping the entire process. After all, the number of computers that supported the Plug and Play specification started at zero, because the specification was still being written. A lot of clever tricks were used to retrofit Plug and Play onto legacy hardware.¹ The Wind
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250624-00/?p=111299 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Now in Public Preview: Create Dev Boxes on Behalf of Your Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce that one of our most-requested features is officially in Public Preview: You can now create Dev Boxes on behalf of your developers
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/public-preview-create-dev-boxes-on-behalf-of-developers 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecation of MS-APP-ACTS-AS header in Shifts Management Microsoft Graph APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In app-only access scenarios, Shifts Management Graph APIs previously required the MS-APP-ACTS-AS: userId header to indicate the user on whose behalf the application was acting. However, this conflicted with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/microsoft365dev/deprecation-of-ms-app-acts-as-header-in-shifts-management-microsoft-graph-apis 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Access: Join Us at VS Live! Redmond for a Week of Deep Developer Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A long time ago, I stood in a packed room at VS Live! and watched developers erupt in applause after a debugging demo shaved hours off a real-world problem. That was the moment I realized this wasn’t just a conference—it was a place where developers and toolmakers come together to push the craft forward. I’m excited to announce that I
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/inside-access-join-us-at-vs-live-redmond-for-a-week-of-deep-developer-learning 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MIDL compiler still has trouble with double greater-than signs, sadly</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_06_2025/23_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The parser for the Microsoft MIDL compiler has long suffered from the problem of the double greater-than sign. This problem plagued C++ until C++11 added a special rule:¹ [temp.names] (4): When parsing a template-argument-list, the first non-nested &amp;gt; is taken as the ending delimiter rath
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250623-00/?p=111295 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>💻 Spring Cleaning for Dev Boxes: Mastering Manual &amp; Automatic Offboarding</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Let’s face it. Sometimes your Dev Box just… hangs around too long. Whether you’ve moved to a new project, left the company, want to create a new dev box with the latest tools, it&#39;s time to clean things up. 🎯 With Dev Box Auto-Deletion now in public preview, offboarding just got a whole lot easier. Here&#39;s everything
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/%f0%9f%92%bb-spring-cleaning-for-dev-boxes-mastering-manual-automatic-offboarding 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>codex-mini: Fast, Scalable Code Generation for the CLI Era</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re announcing the general availability of Azure OpenAI’s codex-mini in Azure AI Foundry Models. codex-mini is a fine-tuned version of the o4-mini model, designed to deliver rapid, instruction-following performance for developers working in CLI workflows. Whether you&#39;r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/codex-mini-fast-scalable-code-generation-for-the-cli-era 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>o-series Updates: New o3 pricing and o3-pro in Azure AI Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            o-series Updates: New o3 pricing and o3-pro in Azure AI Foundry We are excited to announce the availability of o3-pro, the newest model in the Azure AI Foundry via Azure OpenAI. o3-pro combines more compute with long context and multimodal input to deliver consistently better answers for complex tasks. o3-pro is available via the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/azure-openai-o3-pro-ai-foundry 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The case of the invalid handle error when a handle is closed while a thread is waiting on it</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_06_2025/20_06_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer tracked one of their crashes to an invalid handle exception being raised when one thread closed a handle that another thread was waiting for. Or at least that&#39;s how they presented the problem. The stack trace in the crash dump said ntdll!KiRaiseUserExceptionDispatcher+0x3a KERNELBASE!WaitForMultipleObjectsEx+0x
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250620-00/?p=111291 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of GitHub Copilot for Azure—Now with Agent Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 21:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Unlocking a New DevOps Era GitHub Copilot for Azure was first introduced at Ignite 2024 as a public preview, empowering developers, IT operators, and DevOps practitioners to leverage natural language to provision, configure, and manage r
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/announcing-general-availability-of-github-copilot-for-azure-now-with-agent-mode 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance governance and flexibility with Dev Box project policies</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 18:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            As organizations scale their development efforts, managing access to cloud resources becomes critical. Platform engineers need to strike a balance between enforcing governance and enabling developer agility. At Build 2025, we announced the general availability of project policies in Microsoft Dev Box, which provides a powerful
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/balance-governance-and-flexibility-with-dev-box-project-policies 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control cloud costs with Dev Box hibernation features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 18:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Cost is one of the most important concerns in any cloud-native rollout. IT admins need powerful tools to control costs without slowing development. At Build 2025, we were excited to announce the general availability of hibernat
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/develop-from-the-cloud/control-cloud-costs-with-dev-box-hibernation-features 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of Native Vector Type &amp; Functions in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 15:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We are happy to announce that Native vector support in Azure SQL Database and Azure SQL Managed Instance is moving to General Availability this summer. Deployments are already underway, and several regions have begun receiving the feature. What is going GA? Integrated Vector Data Type Azure SQL introduces a dedicated
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-general-availability-of-native-vector-type-functions-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to read C&#43;&#43; compiler errors: Ambiguous symbol errors after including a header file</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A colleague added another header file to their project, and everything started blowing up with &amp;quot;ambiguous symbol&amp;quot; errors. #include &amp;quot;pch.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;something.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;quot;newheader.h&amp;quot; #include &amp;lt;shlobj.h&amp;gt; ... This resulted in a build error in Visual Studi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250619-00/?p=111285 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PACT Contract Testing - Because Not Everything Needs Full Integration Tests</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_06_2025/19_06_2025_15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            At Microsoft Industry Solutions Engineering, we are big fans of integration tests. They are the best way to test that your system works as a whole, but sometimes, integration tests are overkill or too complex to set up that the return on investment is just not worth it. That&#39;s the situation one of our teams has recently found themselves in.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/pact-contract-testing-because-not-everything-needs-full-integration-tests 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
