<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:17:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate your open-source dependency scanning with Advanced Security</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Any experiences that require additional setup is cumbersome, especially when there are multiple people needed. In GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps, we&#39;re working to make it easier to enable features and scale out enablement across your enterprise. You can now automatically inject the dependency scanning task into a
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/automate-your-open-source-dependency-scanning-with-advanced-security 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Update C&#43;&#43; syntax using Next Edit Suggestions</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 16:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When working in a C++ repo, you often are maintaining and updating existing code just as often as you are writing new code. However, updating code in C++ can often require navigating to several different locations in a file to ensure consistency, which can disrupt your logical workflow. For example, changing a data member’s access level typi
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/dynamically-update-c-syntax-using-next-edit-suggestions 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in Azure AI Foundry | July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            TL;DR Deep Research Agent (Public Preview): Automate complex, multi-step web research with OpenAI’s o3-deep-research model, now available in Azure AI Foundry Agent Service. GPT-image-1 model: Adds input fidelity controls and partial image streaming for advanced image editing and generation.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/whats-new-in-azure-ai-foundry-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new Dependabot NuGet updater: 65% faster with native .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you&#39;ve ever waited impatiently for Dependabot to update your .NET dependencies, or worse, watched it fail with cryptic errors, we have some great news. Over the past year, the Dependabot team has worked on a refactor of the NuGet updater, and the results are impressive. From hybrid to native The previous NuGet updater use
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/the-new-dependabot-nuget-updater 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I read more than 4GB of data from a file in a single call to &lt;code&gt;Read­File&lt;/code&gt;?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/04_08_2025/04_08_2025_12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The nNumber­Of­Bytes­To­Read parameter to Read­File is a 32-bit unsigned integer, which limits the number of bytes that could be read at once to 4GB. What if you need to read more than 4GB? The Read­File function cannot read more than 4GB of data at a time. At the time the function was or
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250804-00/?p=111432 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.9</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the release of TypeScript 5.9! If you&#39;re not familiar with TypeScript, it&#39;s a language that builds on JavaScript by adding syntax for types. With types, TypeScript makes it possible to check your code to avoid bugs ahead of time. The TypeScript type-checker does all this, and is also the foundation of grea
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-9 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two related questions about keeping track of PIDs of IPC clients</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/01_08_2025/01_08_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer was writing a program that was intended to run in the background and was looking for recommendations on how to store its PID so that other programs can find it and start communicating with the background process. Another customer was writing a provider program that will have multiple clients connect to it. They want the p
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250801-00/?p=111427 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us at Azure Dev Summit 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 18:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The success of AI-powered apps and agents hinges not only on cutting edge models and AI platforms, but on the developers who are chartered with designing innovative services that are secure, scalable, and grounded in the right knowledge. The inaugural Azure Dev Summit on October 13-16, 2025
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//join-us-at-azure-dev-summit-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated .NET and JDBC Drivers with Native Vector Data Support for High-Performance AI Workload</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’ve just released major updates to our data access libraries, bringing native support for vector data to both the .NET and JDBC ecosystems, unlocking significant performance gains for AI and machine learning workloads. Microsoft.Data.SqlClient 6.1.0 With the new SqlVector class, you can now handle vector data in bin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/updated-net-and-jdbc-drivers-with-native-vector-data-support-for-high-performance-ai-workload 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A consequence of the weird &lt;code&gt;wReserved&lt;/code&gt; value at the start of the &lt;code&gt;DECIMAL&lt;/code&gt; structure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_11/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Not too long ago, I explained why why there is a weird wReserved value at the start of the DECIMAL structure. Markus Grohs pointed out
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250731-00/?p=111423 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarter AI Edits in Visual Studio Copilot</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            When we first set out to get smarter AI edits in Visual Studio Copilot, we knew we were tackling a deeply complex problem. It wasn’t just about generating great suggestions—it was about figuring out how to seamlessly apply those suggestions to your code. While the idea seemed simple at first glance, the reality w
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/smarter-ai-edits-in-visual-studio-copilot 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building AI Agents with the A2A .NET SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Building AI Agents with the A2A .NET SDK The AI development landscape is rapidly evolving. Autonomous agents are becoming increasingly sophisticated, specialized, and capable of handling complex tasks across diverse domains. From customer service bots to data analysis agents, from content creation assistants to workflow orchestrators
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/foundry/building-ai-agents-a2a-dotnet-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Analytical Queries with Semantic Kernel and In-Memory SQL Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Semantic Kernel in-memory SQL processing for analytical queries In today&#39;s world, large language models (LLMs) like Azure OpenAI&#39;s GPT models have significantly changed how users interact with data-driven applications. While these models are excellent at understanding language, they can fall short on precise, structured computations.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/semantic-kernel-sql-processing 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot for Xcode: Introducing Copilot Vision, Custom Instructions, Locale-Aware Responses, and More</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 03:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/31_07_2025/31_07_2025_23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to introduce updates to GitHub Copilot for Xcode, bringing new ways to interact with AI and streamline your development workflow. With Copilot Vision, you can upload and chat with images—like screenshots and UI designs—directly in Xcode. We’ve also introduced global
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/xcode/github-copilot-for-xcode-introducing-copilot-vision-and-more 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (July 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Full-Stack App with React and Aspire: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we will build we will build a TODO app from start to finish using Aspire and React. We will do this using the CLI and C# Dev Kit. The todo items will be stored in a SQLite database. The React front-end will use a Web API to handle all the interactions with the data. I&#39;m going to be showing this with the dotnet CLI, Aspire CLI a
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of UNISTR function and ANSI SQL || Operator in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the General Availability (GA) of two long-standing capabilities that address critical needs for SQL developers and enterprise customers in Azure SQL Database and Azure SQL Managed Instance, configured with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-general-availability-of-unistr-function-and-ansi-sql-operator-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, how can I await multiple coroutines and capture the results?, part 0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while ago, I investigated ways of awaiting multiple C++/WinRT corotuines and capturing the results. I started with winrt::when_all(), but really I co
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250730-00/?p=111421 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Plan Validation in Copilot Studio Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wonder why your agent&#39;s answers can be right but for the wrong reasons? Let&#39;s dive into why that matters, with a brief foray into epistemology (bear with me!) Knowledge: More Than Just Right Answers Imagine asking someone the time, and they confidently reply, “2:30 PM.” They&#39;re correct—but what if their watch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/plan-validation-cat-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire 9.4 is here with a CLI and interactive dashboard features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we released .NET Aspire 9.4, our biggest release ever, bringing new integrations, interactive dashboard-based inputs, and a standalone, native AOT command line tool for creating and running Aspirified apps. We also published our first roadmap last week, which outl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-aspire-9-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft build of Go 1.25 crypto backend changes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting in Go 1.25, the Microsoft build of Go will default to using system-provided cryptography: OpenSSL on Linux and CNG on Windows. The systemcrypto GOEXPERIMENT will be enabled by default and picks the supported backend for the target platform.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/microsoft-go-defaults-to-system-crypto 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Live: Visual Studio Toolbox at VS LIVE! Redmond 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 15:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join Robert Green and Leslie Richardson for a full day of live sessions, demos, and interviews. Live from Microsoft HQ – Stream Tuesday’s Sessions with Visual Studio Toolbox! On Tuesday, August 5, join us for a special edition of Visual Studio Toolbox Live—broadcast f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/watch-live-visual-studio-toolbox-at-vs-live-redmond-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a window with no name blocking Windows shutdown?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you try to shut down Windows, and there&#39;s a program that is not allowing the shutdown to proceed, then the Blocked Shutdown Resolver (BSDR) shows a list of windows that includes the one that is processing the shutdown notification, as well as
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250729-00/?p=111417 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 20:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shares the details of the latest changes to the Azure Developer CLI (azd) in release 1.17.1 and 1.18.0. We invite you to join our July release discussion on GitHub with questions and comments. This month&#39;s release focuses on enhancing developer experien
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Learn MCP Series Recap: 8 Languages, 4 Code Bases, Full Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) has quickly established itself as the go-to standard for seamlessly connecting AI agents with a variety of external tools and services. In just a few months, it has become a prominent topic at developer events and forums, gaining adoption from companies of all sizes. To meet the rapid pace of advancements, we
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//lets-learn-mcp-series-recap-8-languages-4-code-bases-full-resources 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API design note: Don&#39;t make up multiple names for the same thing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recurring problem I encounter when reviewing API proposals is that teams tend not to be precise in their use of terminology. This casualness is inevitable when you work with a feature for a long time and develop notational shortcuts, but the people who are learning your API don&#39;t have the same level of familiarity that you do, and shiftin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250728-00/?p=111415 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling multi-tenant Go applications: Choosing the right database partitioning approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Multi-tenant applications face a fundamental challenge: how to efficiently store and query data for tenants of vastly different sizes? Consider the typical scenario where your platform serves both enterprise clients with hundreds of thousands of users, as well as small businesses with just a handful. With traditional database partitioning stra
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/scaling-multi-tenant-go-applications-choosing-the-right-database-partitioning-approach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
