<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 22:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure SDK Release (July 2025)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Thank you for your interest in the new Azure SDKs! We release new features, improvements, and bug fixes every month. Subscribe to our Azure SDK Blog RSS Feed to get notified when a new release is available. You can find links to packages, code, and docs on our
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-sdk-release-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Full-Stack App with React and Aspire: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In this post we will build we will build a TODO app from start to finish using Aspire and React. We will do this using the CLI and C# Dev Kit. The todo items will be stored in a SQLite database. The React front-end will use a Web API to handle all the interactions with the data. I&#39;m going to be showing this with the dotnet CLI, Aspire CLI a
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing General Availability of UNISTR function and ANSI SQL || Operator in Azure SQL</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce the General Availability (GA) of two long-standing capabilities that address critical needs for SQL developers and enterprise customers in Azure SQL Database and Azure SQL Managed Instance, configured with the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/announcing-general-availability-of-unistr-function-and-ansi-sql-operator-in-azure-sql 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In C&#43;&#43;/WinRT, how can I await multiple coroutines and capture the results?, part 0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A while ago, I investigated ways of awaiting multiple C++/WinRT corotuines and capturing the results. I started with winrt::when_all(), but really I co
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250730-00/?p=111421 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Plan Validation in Copilot Studio Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/30_07_2025/30_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Ever wonder why your agent&#39;s answers can be right but for the wrong reasons? Let&#39;s dive into why that matters, with a brief foray into epistemology (bear with me!) Knowledge: More Than Just Right Answers Imagine asking someone the time, and they confidently reply, “2:30 PM.” They&#39;re correct—but what if their watch
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powerplatform/plan-validation-cat-kit 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspire 9.4 is here with a CLI and interactive dashboard features</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today, we released .NET Aspire 9.4, our biggest release ever, bringing new integrations, interactive dashboard-based inputs, and a standalone, native AOT command line tool for creating and running Aspirified apps. We also published our first roadmap last week, which outl
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-aspire-9-4 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft build of Go 1.25 crypto backend changes</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Starting in Go 1.25, the Microsoft build of Go will default to using system-provided cryptography: OpenSSL on Linux and CNG on Windows. The systemcrypto GOEXPERIMENT will be enabled by default and picks the supported backend for the target platform.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/microsoft-go-defaults-to-system-crypto 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Live: Visual Studio Toolbox at VS LIVE! Redmond 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 15:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Join Robert Green and Leslie Richardson for a full day of live sessions, demos, and interviews. Live from Microsoft HQ – Stream Tuesday’s Sessions with Visual Studio Toolbox! On Tuesday, August 5, join us for a special edition of Visual Studio Toolbox Live—broadcast f
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/visualstudio/watch-live-visual-studio-toolbox-at-vs-live-redmond-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a window with no name blocking Windows shutdown?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/29_07_2025/29_07_2025_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you try to shut down Windows, and there&#39;s a program that is not allowing the shutdown to proceed, then the Blocked Shutdown Resolver (BSDR) shows a list of windows that includes the one that is processing the shutdown notification, as well as
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250729-00/?p=111417 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Developer CLI (azd) - July 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 20:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            This post shares the details of the latest changes to the Azure Developer CLI (azd) in release 1.17.1 and 1.18.0. We invite you to join our July release discussion on GitHub with questions and comments. This month&#39;s release focuses on enhancing developer experien
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sdk/azure-developer-cli-azd-july-2025 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Learn MCP Series Recap: 8 Languages, 4 Code Bases, Full Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Model Context Protocol (MCP) has quickly established itself as the go-to standard for seamlessly connecting AI agents with a variety of external tools and services. In just a few months, it has become a prominent topic at developer events and forums, gaining adoption from companies of all sizes. To meet the rapid pace of advancements, we
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//lets-learn-mcp-series-recap-8-languages-4-code-bases-full-resources 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API design note: Don&#39;t make up multiple names for the same thing</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A recurring problem I encounter when reviewing API proposals is that teams tend not to be precise in their use of terminology. This casualness is inevitable when you work with a feature for a long time and develop notational shortcuts, but the people who are learning your API don&#39;t have the same level of familiarity that you do, and shiftin
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250728-00/?p=111415 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling multi-tenant Go applications: Choosing the right database partitioning approach</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/28_07_2025/28_07_2025_9/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Multi-tenant applications face a fundamental challenge: how to efficiently store and query data for tenants of vastly different sizes? Consider the typical scenario where your platform serves both enterprise clients with hundreds of thousands of users, as well as small businesses with just a handful. With traditional database partitioning stra
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/scaling-multi-tenant-go-applications-choosing-the-right-database-partitioning-approach 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Container Options: Matching Services to Operational Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Customers are looking to modernize their application on cloud and ask us for guidance on which Azure container services to choose. Should you choose A or B container services or A+B container services? Some choose both (A + B) or use A or B appr
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/azure-container-options-matching-services-to-operational-responsibility 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Data Governance &amp; Compliance with UDM</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 20:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_1/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Why Data Governance Matters In today’s data-driven world, governance isn’t just a technical requirement—it’s foundational to successful business operations. Good governance ensures data is not only accurate and compliant but also discoverable and usable at scale. At the heart of this approach lies robust, high-quality meta
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/udm/scalable-data-governance-compliance-with-udm 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing TypeScript 5.9 RC</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 16:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we are excited to announce the Release Candidate (RC) of TypeScript 5.9! To get started using the Release Candidate, you can get it through npm with the following command: npm install -D typescript@rc Let&#39;s take a look at what&#39;s new
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/typescript/announcing-typescript-5-9-rc 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I confirm in the Windows debugger that I&#39;m looking at a COMDAT-folded function?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, we learned about identical COMDAT folding (and also
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250725-00/?p=111409 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Manual Testing to AI-Generated Automation: Our Azure DevOps MCP &#43; Playwright Success Story</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 06:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/25_07_2025/25_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            In today’s fast-paced software development cycles, manual testing often becomes a significant bottleneck. Our team was facing a growing backlog of test cases that required repetitive manual execution—running the entire test suite every sprint. This consumed valuable time that could be better spent on exploratory testing and higher-value
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/from-manual-testing-to-ai-generated-automation-our-azure-devops-mcp-playwright-success-story 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 21:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re pleased to announce the general availability (GA) release of Microsoft.PowerShell.PlatyPS v1.0.0. PlatyPS is the tool that Microsoft uses to create the PowerShell content you get from Get
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/powershell/announcing-platyps-100 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I wait until a named object (say a mutex) is created?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/24_07_2025/24_07_2025_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer used a named mutex as a way to detect that another instance of the program is already running. This is pretty standard. They also used the presence of the mutex to indicate that the program is ready to receive work requests: When the program creates the mutex, this prevents new instances from running, and it also announce
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250724-00/?p=111406 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSSQL Extension for VS Code: Agent Mode Updates, Colored Connections, and Schema Designer Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The MSSQL Extension for VS Code keeps getting better—bringing thoughtful updates that make SQL development more conversational, more visual, and more local. In version v1.34.0, we’ve focused this release on deepening
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/azure-sql/vscode-mssql-agent-mode-updates 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Build Agent2Agent Communication on MCP? Yes!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            MCP has evolved significantly beyond its original goal of &amp;quot;providing context to LLMs.&amp;quot; With recent enhancements including resumable streams, elicitation,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com//can-you-build-agent2agent-communication-on-mcp-yes 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring possible solutions to the inconsistency in how Windows searches case-insensitively for named resources</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_07_2025/23_07_2025_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I explained why Windows has trouble finding Win32 resources with accented characters. It boils down to an ambiguity in the Portable Executable sp
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20250723-00/?p=111403 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
