<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devblogs.microsoft.com on .NET Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>.NET Ramblings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dotnetramblings.com/tags/devblogs.microsoft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Local Development and Cloud Evaluation: Using Microsoft Devtunnels with Azure Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/23_01_2026/23_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction Picture this scenario: you&#39;ve implemented a critical fix in your AI service and want to validate it against your comprehensive evaluation dataset. However, the prospect of deploying to Azure for a quick test creates an unwelcome delay in your development cycle. This challenge is common among AI developers. When develo
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/bridging-local-development-cloud-evaluation-devtunnels-azure-ml 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit: Your AI Pair Programmer Just Got Smarter</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Azure Cosmos DB Agent Kit is an open-source collection of skills that teaches your AI coding assistant (GitHub Copilot, Claude Code, Gemini CLI) expert-level Azure Cosmos DB best practices. Install with one command, get production-ready g
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/azure-cosmos-db-agent-kit-ai-coding-assistants 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple helper function for attaching a progress handler to a Windows Runtime IAsync­Action­With­Progress or IAsync­Operation­With­Progress</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/22_01_2026/22_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            The Windows Runtime has interfaces IAsync­Action and IAsync­Operation which represent asynchronous activity: The function starts the work and returns immediately, and then it calls you back when the work completes. Most language projections allow you to treat these as coroutines, so you can await
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260122-00/?p=112005 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now in Public Preview: GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Last year, we launched our new GitHub Copilot build performance capabilities in Private Preview. With help from our fantastic C++ community, we gathered insights and addressed key feedback. We’re happy to share that GitHub Copilot build performance for Windows is now in Public Preview. Today, all C++ developers can try out the new capabiliti
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cppblog/now-in-public-preview-github-copilot-build-performance-for-windows 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the proper usage of a custom Win32 dialog class</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Some time ago, I discussed custom dialog classes. You can specify that a dialog template use your custom dialog class by putting the custom class&#39;s name in the CLASS statement of the dialog template. A c
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260121-00/?p=112002 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-Driven Development: Agent Skills for Microsoft Foundry and Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/21_01_2026/21_01_2026_8/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Code will be generated, not written. Working with 100+ companies, I have seen this firsthand: most enterprise workloads taking dependencies on AI SDKs are usually net-new microservices. Hardly anyone has Windows-scale codebases for their new AI features. This is modular, greenfield work. Perfect for coding agents. The catch? Out-of-the-box
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/all-things-azure/context-driven-development-agent-skills-for-microsoft-foundry-and-azure 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Azure Performance Diagnostics Tool for Java: Automated Java Performance Analysis in Kubernetes via Azure SRE Agent</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We&#39;re excited to announce that the Azure Performance Diagnostics Tool for Java is now available for preview as part of the Azure SRE Agent platform, bringing intelligent, automated Java performance diagnoses. Currently supporting Java workloads deployed to Azure Kubernetes S
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/java/introducing-azure-performance-diagnostics-tool-for-java-automated-java-performance-analysis-in-kubernetes-via-azure-sre-agent 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIX 2601.15 - new Intel plugin, many buffer viewer improvements, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_3/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Today we released PIX version 2601.15, which can be downloaded here. This release includes everything in the previous 2509.25 release, plus: A new Intel plugin with many new featu
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/pix/pix-2601-15 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go 1.25.6-1 and 1.24.12-1 Microsoft builds now available</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_4/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A new release of the Microsoft build of Go including security fixes is now available for download. For more information about this release and the changes included, see the table below: Microsoft Release Upstream Tag
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/go/go-1-25-6-1-and-1-24-12-1-microsoft-builds-now-available 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microspeak: On fire, putting out fires</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_6/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Remember, Microspeak is not necessarily jargon exclusive to Microsoft, but it&#39;s jargon that you need to know if you work at Microsoft. When something has gone horribly wrong and requires immediate attention, one way to describe it is to say that it is on fire. The obvious metaphor here is that the situation is so severe that
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260120-00/?p=111998 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerToys 0.97 is here: a big Command Palette update and a new mouse utility</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/20_01_2026/20_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
             Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/powertoys-0-97-is-here-a-big-command-palette-update-and-a-new-mouse-utility 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Boards additional field filters (private preview)</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We’re excited to announce a limited private preview that introduces the ability to add additional fields as filters on both the backlog and Kanban boards. This feature has been a long-standing request from the developer com
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/azure-boards-additional-field-filters-private-preview 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What was the secret sauce that allows for a faster restart of Windows 95 if you hold the shift key?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_2/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Commenter Otul Osan wondered what was happening when the user held the Shift key when restarting Windows. Windows displays the message &amp;quot;Windows is restarting&amp;quot; rather than doing a full cold restart of the system.
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260119-06/?p=111995 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🚀React Native Windows v0.81 is here!!</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/19_01_2026/19_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            App developers require performance, stability, and cross-platform consistency such as fast startups, smooth UI, and seamless code sharing across Windows, Android, and iOS as these factors directly impact user experience, development efficiency, and business outcomes. High performance and stability ensure apps run reliably and respond quickly,
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/react-native/%f0%9f%9a%80react-native-windows-v0-81-is-here 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new with Azure Repos?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_0/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            We thought it was a good time to check in and highlight some of the work happening in Azure Repos. In this post, we’ve covered several recent improvements, along with a preview of features that are coming soon. To stay up to date, be sure to visit the
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/whats-new-with-azure-repos 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I get the tab index number from a dialog box control?</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_5/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            A customer wanted to retrieve the TabIndex of a dialog box control. They were able to get its class name and
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20260116-00/?p=111991 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Building Your First Serverless HTTP API on Azure with Azure Functions &amp; FastAPI</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_7/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction This post is Part 1 of the series Serverless Application Development with Azure Functions and Az
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/cosmosdb/building-your-first-serverless-http-api-on-azure-with-azure-functions-fastapi 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Small Language Model Function Calling using the Azure AI Evaluation SDK</title>
      <link>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dotnetramblings.com/post/16_01_2026/16_01_2026_10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction In recent years, Small Language Models (SLMs) have become increasingly important. SLMs are language models with far fewer parameters and use significantly fewer resources than their Large Language Model (LLM) counterparts, while still achieving comparable performance in specific tasks. SLMs are ideal for environments wh
Link to article: https://devblogs.microsoft.com/ise/slm-function-calling-with-azure-ai-evaluation-sdk 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
